Hey Guys welcome to your first project in this project we're going to build a theme called Travel Ville
which is kind of like a travel agency type Web site landing page.
So basically it's all one page but we have a navigation where we're using the scroll spy component so
that if we click on something like surge it'll just kind of nicely scroll down to that area.
Same thing with popular places.
Gallery contact and all that so we can navigate that way.
We also have the slider using an image slider with some high quality images.
And each one each slide has the caption coming in from a different direction.
All right we also have this search destination's search box where we implemented the autocomplete component.
So for instance if I put an A in here you see we get a bunch of stuff that comes up if I started to
type like a Ruba then it narrows it down to Aruba.
Of course it's not going to do any searching or anything because this is just the front end UI.
OK then we have some boxes here are some icons.
These are material icons.
Down here we have some cards with some images for popular places.
I'm also using the material boxed component so that we can click on it and it will show a full size
image.
All right here we just have a follow section where we have some social media icons.
Now these are actually coming from Fonte awesome because the material icons library does not have social
media icons.
All right then we have a photo gallery again we're using material boxed here so we can see the full
thing and then we have our contact form with a couple of boxes for location and so on.
And then just a very simple footer with some flow text.
All right so that's what we'll be building.
Guys let's actually quickly take a look at the responsive version so if I were to make this smaller
and you'll see we have the side menu here that pops out.
And if I were to make this to wear it around here you'll see that it changes and everything is now stacked.
OK everything is in a single row and it looks good on smaller mobile devices.
Ok so so be building guys hopefully you enjoy this project.
And let's go ahead and get started.