All right guys so now that you saw what we'll be building let's go ahead and start now for the the project
files for this section or I'm sorry this lecture you should have a zip file called them theme's starter.
You need to do is download that and extract it.
OK and this is basically what we're going to be using for the next few themes that we build the next
few projects.
So I'm going to create a new new folder for our project and I'm going to call it travel ville.
And then what I'll do is open that up and let's bring everything over from the theme start folder OK
and then we'll go over all that stuff.
So it's copy it over.
Don't move it just copy it because we're going to be reusing these files.
OK and then I'm going to open up travel Velle in my text editor which I'm using VS code so I'm going
to it's going to say open with code.
All right.
Let me just bring that over and we'll go ahead and snap this to the side here.
OK.
And let's just take a look at these files real quick so we have an index each team which I'll go over
in a second.
We have a CSSA folder that has the main materialized CSSA File.
We're working with version zero point one hundred point two.
And as I mentioned before when there's an update I will be updating the course it might just take a
month or two after the update.
OK.
But I would definitely suggest using the version that's in the theme starter rather than the newer version
just in case there's any class changes or anything like that.
And you don't get messed up.
All right we also have a main CSSA file which is just a plain just an empty CSSA file for any custom
styles we have in the Fonts Folder we just have our rebottle fonts all come.
This all comes with materialize.
We have an images folder which is empty right now.
A javascript folder with the materialized mid-fi javascript file and then our index each Tamal which
is basically the if you go to get started on the materialized side.
It's basically that that mark up with a couple of things added.
So we have our material icons here so we can use those.
We have the may materialize CSSA file length.
We have our main dot CSSA file for custom styles.
We have a viewport for Responsive sites or responsiveness a title which will change through each theme
and then in the body we just have in each one.
And then the bottom we have our script tags which include J.
Queery the materialize mid-fi javascript and then just a custom script tag with anything that we want
to do in here such as initialized components or if we want to do some custom javascript or anything
like that.
Or custom Jay Querrey.
All right so that's what will be working with guys.
So what we're going to do now.
And before we start on the body is I just want to grab Fonte awesome real quick.
All right because we want to use foreign awesome for the social icons because they're not available
with material icons.
So I just want to make this bigger.
We're not going to do exact half and half because I want to have a lot of room here.
But let's go to Fonte awesome dot com and version 5 was just released the whole web site was redone.
Now we're using SVGA icons.
But if we go to get started and right here you see this script tag this is so we can use the SPG icons
with javascript so we're just going to paste that in the head right here.
And we should now be able to use those.
All right so we'll save that close up you.
We'll just open a new tab and close that.
And then what we're going to do is open this file.
Now you can just open the html file on your file system if you want but since I'm using a live server
I'm just going to right click and say open with a live server.
And again if you're using VS code and you want that just click on the extension icon and search for
it and install it.
OK and I'll just close the sidebar up here.
So this is what the theme starter looks like nothing pretty is just a basic boiler plate.
So first thing we're going to do is add our now bar.
So let's go over here and let's get rid of this H1 and I want this NOW bar to be fixed.
And if you remember from the sandbox chapter or lecture we have to wrap the Nav. in a div with the class
of nav bar dash fixed.
So we're going to do that and then we'll put our nav bar which I'm going to give a class of Teall because
I wanted to have a teal background color.
Okay we're also going to put a container so that everything is kind of moved to the metal.
And then we need our div with the class of Nav. wrapper and inside that will have our branding.
So it's going to be a link with the class of brand Dasch logo.
And for the treffen I'm just going to put hash home and then in here we'll just say travel vittle.
OK.
Underneath that we're going to want our collapse button for the South Side nav so it will be another
tag with the class of button dash collapse and for the Tref I will just put a hash.
But this is going to have a special attribute called Data activates.
OK and we're going to set this.
You can set this to anything you want.
I'm going to say mobile nav.
Just make sure that when you actually create the menu for the mobile now it has that same ID.
And then inside the tag here we're going to have an icon so all of our material icons need to have a
class of material icons and then whatever icon we want we put in the middle here and I'm going to use
the menu icon.
OK.
Now underneath this a tag we're going to put our regular menu link so it's going to be a UL.
I'm going to give it a class of rights that it floats everything to the right and then I want this to
be hidden on anything under a large screen so medium screens and down.
So there's actually a class we can use for that called Hide on Imedi and down like that.
All right.
And then we'll put some allies in here with some tags this is going to go to hash home and the text
will say home and then world do is just copy these down.
We're going to have five of these and this one here is going to be for the search.
It's going to go to hash search.
All right.
This one here is going to go to say popular places.
And it's going to go to hash popular.
All right this next one here is going to go to.
Let's see who's going to go to hash.
Gallery is going to be our little image gallery.
And then the last one is going to be for the contact so that will go to hash contact.
All right.
Now if I save that we're going to get our now.
Now for the side menu.
If I were to make this smaller those links should disappear once we hit medium.
This isn't going to work yet for two reasons one we didn't create the links yet.
And one we didn't initialize it in the javascript.
So what we're going to do is just copy this entire UL and in a lot of cases you'll see the sidebar UL
right under this ul.
But since we have a nav bar fixed div right here if we do that we're not going to be able to click on
any of the sidebar links it's going to be all greyed out.
So I don't think it says this in the documentation but what you want to do is put your sidebar.
Well under this div K which ends right here so we're going to go right here and paste this in and then
just change the class to side.
And we're going to add in the ID of mobile now.
And the only reason we're using mobile now is the idea is because that's what we put right here as the
data activates.
OK so it's going to activate the mobile nav and we're just going to keep the same links.
All right.
Now last thing we need to do is initialize it so down in the javascript here within the document ready
we're going to just say Gee query for the foughten collapse and we want to call Daut side now like that.
So make sure you save it and we'll go over and click and there we go.
So now we have our side now.
All right.
So I'm going to start the video here and then the next one we're going to move on to the slider the
big image slider with the captions.
So I will see you in the next video.