All right guys we're going to get started on the image slider here.
Now in order to do this obviously we need some images.
So what you can do is you can go into the project files and you can grab them from the EMG folder.
What are we're going to do is take them now and just put them in my IMJ folder.
And there's three images.
If we were to view these There's resort one resort two and resort three dot J Pegge those are the three
images.
And if you're wondering where I got these I got them from pestles dot com P E x e l s dot com which
is a fantastic site for very high quality free stock images so I think I searched for resorts just in
case you want to download them yourself or if you want to use different images.
That's a I think I use this that one maybe.
Not sure exactly which ones I use but if you want to use different images that's fine as well.
So pixels are a great resource.
So now that we have those images let's go back to our aged him now and do what we want to do here.
He just opened this room quick.
What we want to do here is create a section underneath our menu here.
So I'm going to put a comment here and I'm going to say section and this is the slider.
Now the way that we're going to weigh out everything in pretty much every project is in sections I like
to use the H Timo 5 section tag and break everything up give it its own class and also give it a.
Usually give it a class of section which is a materialized class that gives it some padding.
OK but we're not going to actually use it for the slider but we will use it in most cases so for now
we're going to say Section Daut slider which will give us a section with the class of slider and then
we're going to have a UL with the class of slides.
OK and then each slide will be wrapped in Ally tag and we'll have an image.
So we're going to say image and then it's going to be in the I Am G folder and we want the resort Daut
or resort one dot JPEG file.
OK.
So underneath that we're going to put our caption and we're going to use a center caption center line
caption So it's put a div with the class of caption.
It's also going to have a class of center or dash a line like that and then we'll put our H-2 in there
and we're going to say take your dream vacation and then and that we're going to have an H 5 and we're
going to give it a class of why is going to give it a class
of lights and let's say great text and then we want to do text.
Dash liten dash 3 which will make it very light.
And then remember I showed you on the responsive version I don't want the I don't want this to show
the H5 the small text.
So we're going to use the class hide on small only case that will hide it on small screens and then
for the text I'm going to put in Lorem and then let's use 15.
So warm 15.
Tab OK.
And we'll change that if we need more or less.
And then underneath that we'll have an eight tag with the class of beat and also the class of beat and
dash large.
And it's not going to go anywhere it doesn't matter.
And then for the text we're just going to say learn more.
All right so that's up first slides so now we're going to do is copy the entire ally and we're going
to put in two more.
So one two more and we're going to say we're going to change this to resort to and let's change the
slogan here to we'll say we work with all budgets and we want to align this differently we want to align
this one to the left
and that should be it.
And then down here will change just to resort three.
And then we want to align this one to the right sort of the right a line and we'll change the text here
too it's a group and individual getaways.
All right.
So let's go ahead and say that.
Now we're not seeing anything yet.
We actually have two lies this down in the javascript.
So let's go.
Let's see we're going to go down.
It's just common comment.
This will say that
side now of.
And then we'll go in net slider.
So we're going to use a little going to use a little bit of J.A.G. here and say dog slider.
We have that section with the class of slider and then we're going to call Daut slider.
And then we can pass in some options so I don't want the indicators to show the little dots when I say
indicators I'm going to set that to false.
And then we're going to set the height to 500.
OK.
We're going to set the transition to 500.
Half a second.
And then the interval which is how long the slide stays for.
We're going to say 6000 which is six seconds or six thousand milliseconds.
So let's save that.
And there we go.
So there's our first slide.
It should automatically change.
Gagin see that comes in from the left
and then that comes in from the right.
Actually though you know what the text is too dark.
So let's change let's see I said great tax and I spelt Litan wrong that's why I G H T and so let's change
that.
Sorry about that guys.
I hate when I make stupid spelling mistakes
OK.
There we go.
So now it's a lot lighter and we can see it better.
And it's important to choose images where your text is able to be shown that you notice the trees or
overhear.
So I had the text come in on this side and then this is a pretty dark image so it doesn't really matter
where it comes in here.
All right but now we have our Slider I think that looks pretty good.
So the next thing we're going to do is get into the icon boxes.
I'm sorry the search box and then the icon boxes underneath.
All right.
So I'll see you in the next video.