All right so we're going to start on the search area here.
But before we do that I just want to move the button down a little bit in the slider's So it's really
close to the attacks.
It's kind of bothering me a little.
So what I'm going to do is just open up our main CSSA and we're just simply going to say the class of
slider and then the class of button inside of that I'm just going to give a margin top 20 pixels and
that we'll just move it down a little bit.
OK not a big deal but something that I think looks a little better.
All right so now we're going to go underneath the slider section you shall have our section tag here.
It ends here so now we're going to go down on this line and this is where we're going to start our search
section.
So we're going to say section and search.
OK.
So section is going to have a class section which gives it some padding.
It's also going to have a custom class of Section Dasch search and let's make it.
But I also want to be a little darker so we're going to say dark and actuation of dots here.
So teal dark and one we're going to do and we want to make sure the text is white.
So we want white text and it's also center everything.
Christ that's our section now we're going to have a container inside here to contain everything into
the middle and then we're going to use the grid.
So we're going to put a row and then it's just going to be 112 call calling a grid so we can just to
call and we can do as well.
OK and this is the format we're going to use for most projects will have the section that container
to restrict it.
And then the row and then whatever however many columns we're using even if it's a full call on me when
it's a full width it's still good practice to have a 12 column div here.
All right.
So inside here will put in page three or we're going to say search
destinations.
Let's just save that.
So it should look like that so far.
And then under that we'll have the input field so we're going to have a div with the class of input
field and we'll have an input it'll be type text but I'm going to add some classes to this.
So one is going to be white I don't want it to have the standard materialized form field look where
it's just a single line.
I want it to have the you know the box the white box.
So that's why I'm giving it a class of white and then I'm going to give it gray text.
OK.
We're going to do the autocomplete too.
So we might as well add that as well so we'll say autocomplete for our class and let's give it a placeholder
as well.
So give people some hints like let's say a rube
cancn set.
OK.
Now when we're using autocomplete you want to use the ID of autocomplete Dasch input.
OK and we went over this in the sandbox as well.
And we're not going to do a label here the placeholder is fine.
We have the big H-3 so people will know what this is.
So let's go ahead and save.
All right.
Now there are some things that I want to change within our custom CSSA file I want to add some padding.
I want to change the font size things like that.
I want to make the with a little shorter.
So 90 percent.
And then just add a border.
So let's go to our main CSSA and let's say dog section dash search and then we want the input that's
inside that section.
OK and we're going to add a padding of five pixels.
Now a lot of these re to override materialize so we're going to need to put the important flag which
will obviously give it you know you know make it important and it will override the initial style.
So font size I'm going to set to 18 pixels and we'll also say important and give it a width of 90 percent
and then we're going to say border and we'll do a light gray let's do three pixels solid and important.
All right save.
And there we go.
You can see it changed up a little bit.
I think it looks a little better.
All right.
Now let's see for the auto complete.
Obviously nothing.
Nothing's going to happen yet because we need to initialize it.
We need to actually let it know what's going to be included in the autocomplete.
OK so we're going to do that in the javascript's So let's go down here we'll go under the slider and
we'll say auto complete and we're just going to use g Kurri and we're going to say the class of autocomplete
And then what we want to do is do a Daut auto complete and then we want to pass in an object and then
pass in a data object.
OK and this is what what where we put the auto complete words.
So what I'm going to do is just paste these in real quick.
So we're going to use like a rube cancn Mexico Hawaii just some popular vacation places and we'll go
ahead and save that and then let's go over here and just put it in a.
And you see we get our auto complete.
Now one thing that I don't want is this whole area this green area to extend with the auto complete.
I wanted to go outside of it and I want it to stay the same height.
So we actually have to add a little bit of custom CSSA for that.
So it's put in a class of auto complete Desch content which is a class it's automatically included with
it.
And we're just going to set the position to absolute so that it basically doesn't it's not going to
affect things around it.
OK.
And we're going to set the width to 100 percent and then just the line everything to the center.
OK so now if we save when we do it again.
Now you see that it actually goes outside of this section instead of extending the green part which
is what we want.
All right so that is the search area.
So now it's to the icon boxes which is a pretty easy pretty easy area of the template so what's go right
under this section and say Section icon boxes and you see how neat this is to have just each section
like this.
This is how I prefer to do all of my web sites and you guys like this.
I think it makes things very easy very scalable if I wanted to move the search down.
I could just take this and move it down.
I do this with bootstrap with I would just stand just regular each time I'll CSSA any kind of framework.
I like to just break things up into sections.
All right.
So go ahead and say section on section because we want to give it that that materialized section class
which gives it the padding and then we also want to give it our own class which we'll call section icons.
OK.
And then we're also going to give a class of gray and let's do a class of light in the dash for I want
to make it gray but really like gray.
And then we also want to center it and then in here will do our container will do our row and let's
do our columns.
Now these are that we're going to have three different boxes.
So we want to do call as 12.
So it's stacked so it's responsive and it's just one caught one you know one box across one it's on
a mobile device.
But we want to do em for medium sized screens and bigger.
We wanted to go across four columns.
We want three four column divs.
OK.
And then here what we'll do is use a card panel.
So class card panel and then inside here will put an icon.
So we want our material it's material icons and we're going to use an icon called Room which actually
gives us like a Google Maps marker or placeholder thing.
So if I leave it as is it's going to be really small so I'm going to actually add in here I'm going
to have large to make it bigger and I want it to be teal.
So I'm going to say teal dash text whenever you want to color an icon you want to make sure you use
the text not just the color.
So teal text and then we'll put an H for and this is going to say pick where.
OK.
And then for our paragraph here we're going to say Lorem 10 tabs to give us 10 words.
And then what I'll do is copy the column.
So from here to here and we want to more of these.
And then the second one here we're going to change the icon to store and then I'm going to change the
H 4 to travel shop.
OK this last one here we're going to change the icon to airplane underscore active and they have some
weird names for icons.
And then for this we're going to just do.
We're going to say fly cheap.
OK.
So let's save that suit.
It looks like let's see a spill airplane wrong.
Or is it not.
Oh it's airplane mode active.
That's even weirder.
OK.
So there's our icons.
Good.
And they should be responsive so when we get down to here you see that everything stacks.
All right.
And notice that though the smaller text and the slider also disappears.
So everything everything looks pretty good so far.
So in the next video we're going to start on the popular places where which are cards with images.
We're actually going to use the same images that are used in the slider's you know enough to worry about
downloading new images.
All right so let's go ahead and do that next.