All right and last video we went over the search destination's area and the icon boxes.
Now we're going to work on the popular areas of the popular locations which are basically just cards
with images and they also use the material boxed component which is just a very simple white box.
So let's go under the icon boxes section and I'll put a comment there will say section and this is going
to be the popular section and I'll say Section DONZE section and then the custom class will give it
is section Dasch popular.
All right.
So let's do that.
And by the way we're going to get to the navigation after this.
The scrolls by so we can click on the navigation links and it'll go down to that particular area.
We'll do that after.
So let's do container let's do row and we're going to do.
We're going to do a full just a full call them here.
But before we do that I'm just going to put an H for and this H for let's actually give it a class
of center because I want it to be center and then we're going to say popular places.
But what I want to do is I want the word popular to be to have a teal color and then the places will
just have the regular black or gray text whatever it is so let's wrap this in a span so we'll save span
class equals let's do Teale dash text.
OK.
And then we'll wrap just the word popular.
And give it a nice little effect.
All right.
So popular places.
And then underneath that is where we're going to put our column or I should say our columns we're going
to have three four column divs just like we did with the icon boxes so call s 12.
So they're stacked.
And then let's do medium four.
All right.
And then each one of these will have a card class and inside here we'll have a card image class and
inside the card image we're going to have the actual image tag.
And I'm going to use the resort one J bag and then right under that still in the card image class we're
going to have the title which will be in the spans so it'll be a span with the class of card title like
that.
And we're going to say cancn
Mexico.
That way the title is actually inside of the image.
And then we're going to go under the card image div.
And this is where we're going to put our card content class.
OK and then in here I'm going to put a paragraph.
And let's just do Warum 10 like that.
Actually it's two Lorem 15.
OK.
And then what we'll do is copy the whole column here which ends right here.
So grab all these pasted in two more times and the second one we're going to change to resort to dot
J-P egg and we're going to say the Bahamas for the location or the title.
And then this third one here we're going to change to resort three and we're going to change the title
to Nova Scotia
and then that should be it.
So let's save that suit it looks like it's here.
Images put sport.
That's why they're not showing up.
And save.
And there we go.
So popular places now I also want to have just a button underneath that says contact for booking.
So that's going to actually go under the ROE.
So we have our roll which ends right here and then we're just going to put a new row.
And it's just going to have a 12 column div.
So it's to class call as 12.
And let's also Center.
OK.
And then in here we'll put in a tag and let's give this a class of beat and let's do beat and dash large
Let's do grey and let's do Darkon dash 3 so it's almost black.
It's very dark and the trap will just go to hash contact.
And then for the text inside the tag here we're actually going to put an icon.
So material icons.
And let's also do left so there's a line to the left and the icon itself is going to be the center icon.
All right.
And then we'll just say contact for booking
and save and then we go.
Is pretty good.
So now we're going to do the follow section so we're going to go under this say Section follow
and give it a class of Section follow.
And let's as far as the colors goes to teal and let's do Darkon to in let's do white text and let Senator.
OK so those are the classes we want and then we'll have our container roll and let's do just one single
column.
Or should say a 12 column div So as 12.
And then we'll have an H for in here and we're going to say follow
travel ville and we'll put a paragraph in we'll just say follow us on social media for special offers.
OK and then we're going to do our fun awesome icons because remember the material icons they don't have
the Facebook and Twitter icons and all that.
We're also going to wrap them in lynx.
So we're going to put in a tag here with the class of white text
and then I'm just going to have it go to h t t p s Facebook dot com and will put a target of underscore
blank.
That way it doesn't take us off the page of this open a new tab and then inside the tag is we will put
the icon.
So it's going to be an eye tag with the class of FHB and also a class of f a dash Facebook and then
we want to make these bigger so we're going to do F.A. dash for X. So that will make it four times the
regular size.
All right.
And then what we'll do is just copy the tag with the icon in the middle and we're going to do two three
four five of them.
The second one is going to be Twitter dot com and will change the icon to Twitter.
All right.
This one is going to be linked in.
Change the icon.
And then this one here is going to be Google Plus
and the icon is going to be F.A. dash Google dash KLOS.
And then this last one is going to be Pinterest
and the icon itself is F.A. dash Pinterest.
All right.
So let's save that.
Take a look.
All right.
Now one thing I want to do is spread these apart a little bit.
So let's go to our main Dotsie SS and let's a section follow and then I'm going to target the f a dash
for X class which they all have.
And we're just going to set a margin of five pixels top and bottom 10 pixels left and right save and
now it spreads them out a little bit.
All right so expertly good.
So now we're going to do is the gallery so let's go under this section and let's say Section gallery.
OK so Will do.
And each time a whole section tag.
And we're going to put a custom class section gallery and then that should be it for now.
So inside here let's put our container that I put a container for C for follow I did yeah.
OK I just wanted to make sure all these sections should have containers and then I'm going to do an
H for here that will be centered.
And we're just going to say photo gallery but I want to do a span with the class of teal dash text and
put the word photo my phone photo and then over here will say gallery right that way it gives it that
green text for the first word.
Whoops.
I need to do that.
So under the photo gallery each for we're going to put in a row and we're going to have a bunch of images.
So we're going to have four three column divs.
OK so it's say.
Call as 12.
And then let's do em three OK and then in each one of these will have an image and then we're going
to get this from on Splash dot com so c h t t p s source.
Dos Sunsplash dot com.
And then I'm going to just put a size to say 16 hundred times 900 and then we can actually put keywords
so I'm going to say questionmark beach like that.
All right.
We're also going to give all these images a class
of material material boxed
That way they can open up in a white box so let's just try that one image make sure that shows up.
All right.
Now you can see it's giant and we don't want that.
So what I'm going to do is go into my CSSA here.
Actually what we should be able to do is just add a class of responsive I am Gigue.
There we go.
So that will actually contain it to its parent.
All right.
See what else.
All right so I'm going to copy this dev.
Let's put three more.
So that's two three four all together.
And then I mean if I kept it like this it's going to be all the same image.
I don't want that.
So what I'm going to do is just change up the key word a little bit.
Second one here I'm going to call travel and this one here will do nature and this one here will do.
Beach and travel you can actually put more than one and then they should all be different.
All right.
Now I want to have two more rows of these guys so I'm going to grab this whole div right here this whole
row.
Class of row and paste it in again and then one more time.
And then let's just change some of this stuff up.
So for this one we'll say beaches.
This one will say traveling.
This one will do bridge.
And this one will do both just basically anything that's outside.
OK we'll go out here and we'll do a water
to building
trees
and for this one will do.
Cruz looks
all right let's save and now we should have three rows of images and if we make this small they should
all stack.
Ok snag and see they're all stacked.
Good.
That's our photo gallery.
So we're almost there in the next video we're going to start in the contact area and then we also want
to implement scroll spy so that we can actually navigate to different areas.
Nice and smooth.
All right so I'll see you in the next video.