All right so we're almost done with our project.
We have most of the sections here and now we want to work on the contact area so we're going to go here
and I'm going to put a comment that says section contact.
OK so section Daut section and we'll call this section contact.
And then within here will put our container.
We'll put our row.
And what we're going to have is two six column divs on medium screens.
So we want call dog s 12 and then 6.
OK so we're going to want two of these.
So go ahead and put two of those and now on this side we're going to have two card panels one is going
to just have some text one is going to have the location with a collection item or a collection list.
So for this let's do a card panel.
So say car dash panel class and then I'm also going to make it Teall.
Let's give it white text and let's also make it Center and then within here I want to have an e-mail
icon sort of B and I tag with the class of material dash icons.
I'm also going to give it a medium class and then the actual icon will be called e-mail and then under
that will put in H form will say contact us for booking and then I'm just going to put a paragraph with
let's do Lorem 20 20.
All right so if we save that it should look like that when make this a little wider.
OK.
So she looks like that
you know what let's make that in each Five see if that looks any better.
Yeah I think that's better.
And then under that.
So still within this this column here don't go outside of it you just want to go under the card panel
which is here.
So right here I'm going to put a UL with the class of collection and we're going to have this is actually
going to be a collection with a header so we also want the class with header and then the first lie
is going to have a class of collection
dash header like that.
And we'll put an H for in here and we'll say location OK under that then we'll have our list items with
collection item and we'll say travel.
Travel will agency
travel agency
with two of those so this one will just say 5 5 5 Beach Road and will say sweet 33.
And then in this collection item we're going to say Miami Florida.
I don't know the zip code I'm just going to put all fives.
All right so see what that looks like.
All right.
So now on this side of this column we want to put the contact form.
So now we're going to go into this six column div on medium screens and up and we're going to put a
card panel in it's going to be gray.
So we're going to say Gray but let's lighten it let's say lightning dash 3.
OK and then and here we're going to put in age five and we'll say please fill out this form.
OK let's put a class of input field.
And this is going to be the name input so do inputs.
Type text.
Let's give it a placeholder.
Name what's given in the idea of named
and that should be it.
So underneath that will do a label for a name.
Let's save it.
OK.
That's what it looks like.
Now we're going to add the other fields I'm going to copy this input field and we're going to do two
three and four.
OK so the second one here is going to be the email going to change that is going to change the ID to
email and change that type to email and then the four attribute and then this one here is going to be
the phone number.
So it's changed the placeholder to phone ID to phone for a phone.
And then this last one is actually going to be a message but it's going to be a textarea.
So we're going to get rid of the input type and we're going to use textarea now with materialize when
you use a text area you need to use a class called materialize text area to make it look right.
And then for the I.D. we'll call it message placeholder we'll just say Enter message
and text areas need to have closing tags so let's do that.
And then for the label will say message we didn't even put any text in these labels.
Let's do that.
So this will be phone
email and name.
All right.
So the last thing we need another form is a submit button so let's go under this input field right here.
Say input we're going to give it a type of submit value will be submit and we'll give it a class of
DTN OK which is Teall by default.
So let's save that.
And let's take a look and there's our form.
So that looks pretty good.
All right.
Now the last thing I want is for her and that's very very simple
so we're just going to do Forder.
We're going to give it a class of sections so it gets that padding we're going to make it Teale we're
going to darken it by two and we're going to make sure the text is white and we're going to center it.
OK and then inside here we're going to do a paragraph I'm going to give it a class flow text to make
it bigger and responsive and we'll save travel ville and let's do a copyright symbol and then 2018 and
that's it save.
And then we go and I spelt that wrong.
All right that looks pretty good.
Now one thing this text right here please fill out the form it's a little close to the label right here.
So I'm just going to add a simple style and say Section contact.
I believe it's an h 5.
And we're just going to give it a margin bottom of 30 pixels and that'll just push it down a little
bit.
All right.
So now we want to do is implement this scroll spy.
OK if I click search it should scroll down to search.
Now start off by giving the IDs to the content areas so the body is actually going to be for the home
the home link right here.
So I'm going to I'm going to give that an I.D. of home and then I'm going to go down to the search section
which is right here and we're going to give this an I.D. of search.
OK.
And then we want to go to our skip the icon boxes go to popular give that an I.D. of popular.
We also have QAnd whereas our gallery give that an I.D.
and then contact
right now I'll save this.
And when we created our now wavelengths we have them go to hash home half search hash search and it
will work.
You'll see that I'll go to search gallery or somewhat but it's not a smooth scroll It's just like one
it's just it just goes there.
What we want to do is implement scrolls by OK which will make it much smoother.
Now to do this all of the things that we added an ID to we also need to add a scroll spy class too.
So for the body let's say class scrolls by and then I'm just going to actually the rest of them have
classes so just copy the words scrolls spy and let's go to the search and just add that onto the class
at the end.
We'll go to the popular ad that will go to the gallery at it and then on the Contact
skirl spy.
OK.
And then the last thing we want to do is just initialize it so we'll go down to our javascript here.
And we just need to take that class of scrolls by and call Daut scrolls by access should be an upper
case s and let's save let's try it out so search.
There we go and you can see it actually goes and shows the top of that.
Why is it doing there.
Oh sorry.
I'm not sure why did that gallery contact.
And if we go back to home it goes all the way back up.
All right.
So that is our project guys hopefully you enjoyed the first one.
I think this is a pretty good looking site.
I mean if it were a real travel agency I wouldn't think twice I wouldn't say it's a crappy site I think
it looks pretty good.
Obviously if it were a production you might want to do some more stuff to it then obviously you'd have
more functionality like you'd really be able to search the destinations.
But it's a really good start on learning this framework and how to create some some good looking stuff.
All right so that's it guys I will see you in the next project.