IT guys in this video we're going to take a look at a parallax example and Aperol XS is a cool effect
a scrolling effect with images where you can actually scroll and see different parts of the image.
It's just it's a really nice effect and we may use this in a project but this is going to be it's actually
pretty simple to implement what we're going to do is take this top div here and see if we have this
div it ends here and then we have another div that goes around all the content.
And then again another div around the image.
OK so we're going to have two images with some content in the middle.
So this div here we're going to give a class of parallax container
so that materialize knows this is going to be a parallax effect and we'll give this div a class of just
power locks and then we'll have an image that we want to use.
I'm going to use image one J bag and this right here is going to be it's going to have a class of section
that's what we want to put around our content.
And then I'm also going to give it a class of white.
Make sure the backgrounds white and then let's give this a class of row and container.
Which the container I don't think we really need because we actually have this inside a container already
but that's fine.
And then the H-2 is going to have a class of Hetter.
OK we don't need anything on the on the content on the paragraph but down here we want another parallax
container.
So on this div
and you can have as many of these as you want.
And then the image will be image to dot JPK.
So let's save that.
Now we're not going to see anything yet because again this has to be initialized so we're going to go
down here into the javascript and we're going to say the class of parallax.
And we're going to call thought parallax and save.
And there we go now.
Notice that when I scroll you can see different parts of the image.
So for instance this part of the code in this image if I scroll up it hides it OK so it gives you a
really nice effect and you can create some really cool projects using this effect and it's very easy
to implement.
OK so short video but I wanted to just dedicate a video to this this particular component so in the
next one we're going to take a look at the side nav.