All right.
So we're going to take a look at the side now of component.
Now we saw a little bit of this in the nav bar section.
In fact if I go back to nav bar and the response of one we did here if I clicked that we get a side
now of that that pops out and that's what we're going to do.
But we're going to add more to it we're going to have like an image up here with an avatar and in some
other stuffs some icons and just make it look really nice so let's go back to side now.
And this is five underscore to side.
Now I've aged him now and notice they have a well here and they have an ally that wraps around a div
that has another nested did with an image and then we have a link that surrounds an image we have span
with a name span with an email.
So we're going to make this here look pretty nice and be part of the side navigation.
All right so first thing you want to do is take this UL and give it an ID of slide dash out.
Now this idea this can be anything you want.
This is just what we're going to call when we have our trigger to actually make the side of pop out.
So this can be anything.
All right but you do want to have a class of side dash now.
All right.
And then this div right here I'm going to give a class of user view which allows us to have a pretty
cool UI with an image in the background and you'll see once it's once it's added.
We also need a class here of background.
OK.
And then for the image we're going to use Let's use image for jpeg.
And then for the tag here I'm just going to have it go nowhere so just hash.
Exclamation.
And then for this image here I'm going to give a class of circle member we can do our circle images
and I'll give it a source of image five
and then for this link here again it's not going to actually go anywhere.
Normally it would go to like a profile but I'm not going to have it go anywhere.
And then for this span I'm going to give this a class of white text because this will actually be over
the image and then I'm also going to give it a class of name.
OK.
And then here on this email I'm also going to give that a class of white text and I'm going to give
it a class of e-mail.
All right.
So this is like this is very typical of some kind of link to a dashboard or something like that or actually
we have the dashboard link down here but to see your user information once you're logged in.
So for the dashboard again this will just go nowhere.
These links aren't going to actually work.
And then for the icon we'll add our material icons class and let's make this there's actually an icon
called dashboard.
We'll use that
and then let's see posts
and we can also have dividers just lines that kind of divide sections.
So this div I'm going to give a class of divider
and this account info.
I want this to be like a subhead so I'm going to give that a class of sub header and then we have a
logo button.
So I'm going to give that a class of let's do Wavves effect and it's not actually going to go anywhere.
Same thing with this here all right and then down here this ATAC this is going to be our activator.
So the Tref is going to go anywhere but we're going to have a data activates attribute and we're going
to set that to remember we have the idea of slide out.
This is where we're going to call it.
All right.
This also has to have a class of foughten collapse
OK just like it did in the nav bar and then we'll have it wrapped around an icon.
So we'll say material dash icons and we'll give this the icon of the menu.
And let's save it.
So it's not going to work yet because we actually have to initialize it so we go down here and let's
say putten collapse because that's a class on the trigger and we need to call side now.
OK.
So let's save that and let's try it.
And there we go.
And you can see this looks really nice.
We have our old dashboard link with the avatar and the name and email account info log out.
So it's a pretty nice effect.
Pretty nice look.
And we have some options that we can add for this as well.
We wanted to change the width.
We could do menu with if we wanted to change it to let's say 400 pixels.
Actually we just do 400.
And now if I click it you'll see that it's much thicker.
I think the default is 300.
And then if we can also change where it is so if we say edge to edge right and now it comes out from
the right and to put it back to left though we can also do close on click which is true by default.
Let's just try it.
So if I click on i guess.
Let's see.
Let's do a close on click.
True.
OK.
So if I click outside it closes but if I put this to false it still does
not exactly sure what close on click does but I know it is an option see that it might have to do with
touch screens.
Actually one thing that does have to do with touch screens is draggle.
So that's true.
Now this will allow you to choose if you want to be able to drag to open it on touchscreens or not.
I think the default is true.
So that's what I'm going to keep it as we can also do callbacks for when it's open and close.
So for instance let's put a comma here and let's say on the open let's say function
and we'll say alert or actually it's to a console log.
And we'll say when you open and then we can also do
on close
say console dot log
in New Clothes.
All right.
So now what I'll do is open up our console at 12 and let's open it up and we get menu open.
Close it we get menu close if you want something to happen in javascript when you open and close the
side.
Now you can do that easily.
All right guys so that's going to be it.
So in next video we're going to take a look at pushpin which is kind of unique it's kind of a way to
lay out your page.
We're going to have to we're not going to be able to use our normal layout because it's going to take
up the entire page so we can have our menu items but you'll see.
We'll take a look at that next.