All right guys so this is going to be the pushpin component which is kind of strange but I think it's
pretty cool.
Basically we have a couple of different navs here we have three different now as in by default and materialized
just by having the nav tag here gives you this pinkish background with the padding and all that.
OK so what we want to do is for the div that's wrapping around all of these actually it's wrapping around
each Nav. each has a div.
We're going to give this an ID.
So this is going to have an idea of value.
And then it's going to go in and give it a class of block.
OK when we use push Pimm you want to use block and then I'm also going to make the the I'm going to
make it blue.
All right.
So for the nav tag here we actually want to give this a class of pushpin dash Jammo Desch now.
OK and we're going to give it a data target
of blue.
So this data target should actually match the ID.
Now inside here this div we want to give this a class of NAV wrapper just like any other nav bar.
And we're also going to do.
I'm going to give it a color of light blue and then I'm going to put a container inside the nav bar
you don't have to.
But I like to just so things aren't pushed up against the side.
And then this is going to be the logo so we want to give this a class of brand dash logo.
And then we don't actually have to do anything for the links.
Let's go ahead and save that.
OK.
So we're actually going to have to add a little bit of custom see SS in order for this to work.
And this is even in the documentation.
So I have some style tags here we're going to go inside here and we're going to say for the H T now
the body and the block class we want to set the height height to 100 percent.
OK.
So you can see it gives it a height of 100 percent and then it's
you know let's yell it's let's move on to the other ones.
Now instead of let's see actually one thing that I forgot.
Here is the UL.
The UL should actually have an ID of NAV dash mobile and then a class
let's do class rights.
OK so that leaves it to the right and let's hide it on medium screens and end down so we'll say hide
Dasch on MGD and down.
OK.
So that way if if the screen is too small they're not going to show if we make this bigger they should
the link should show all right.
So now what I want to do is just copy this whole div right here and then replace this div like that
and then we're going to change a couple of things we're going to change the ID to read.
We're going to change this to read.
I'm also going to do a Leitung Dash 1 and then we want to change the actual color of the Nav..
Or I'm sorry not the color but the data target to read which should match that ID.
We're going to change this div right here with the Nav. wrapper will change that class to read in.
Let's just change these right here.
So I'll say red for those.
And then what we'll do is for the green again we'll just replace this whole div rate here and we'll
change the ID to Green we'll change this to green the data target
in this
plough to change all these two green
and let's save.
So now if I scroll down you'll see that these are all different colors.
Now they still say blue though it's change.
All right at least the middle one does that should be red.
OK so we're going to go ahead and just
say we're going to add a little bit of Javascript to give it the effect that we want.
The pushpin effect.
So I think we have a class called Target but it's not it's not a class that we actually added.
You know.
Let's take a look.
The element
it can make this smaller.
All right so we have devised the idea of Wu
teener
right.
You going to do is take a look at the documentation
and go to javascript and pushpin
so that the effect we're trying to get is this.
OK.
So I'm scrolling my mouse wheel down and it's moving each one up.
So that's the effect we're trying to get.
So if we look at the code here it actually doesn't give us which is really weird it doesn't give us
the markup that we just put in.
It just kind of gives us the CSSA the J.A.G. plug in initially on the shelf zation So let's grab this
here.
Actually not the document ready we already have that let's grab this right here.
This target dot pushpin.
And then we're going to put this in our javascript's
OK.
And then we're going to take this right here and we're also going to put that in
and then let's see.
OK so that works.
Good.
Now there's also some C Ss
So let's grab this right here.
So class for one element is above threshold.
We're just going to throw this in the style
so pace that in.
These are not CSSA common formatted so we're going to get rid of these.
So it should look like that would save.
And there you go.
No that's not right.
That's CSSA messed up.
Let's actually get rid of that
yes.
And now the green replaces the red red replaces the blue.
Good.
And we're using the colors just to show you the difference and just to show you a clear separation of
these things I guess pages we would call them.
I have never actually used the pushpin in a real project.
This is really the only thing I've ever done with it.
So I apologize that I don't have a better example for you or a better explanation but this is available
if you want to check it out and work with it.
All right so that's going to be it in the next video we're going to look at the scrolls spy component.