All right in this video we're going to look at scroll spy which is pretty neat it's basically we we
have different sections of content.
In this case we have who are we what do we do where are we.
So this would be like an About page or something like that and we want to make it so that these links
over here will be able to click and that will take us.
They'll scroll up to that part of the text.
Not only that but as we scroll will see a little marker that will be at whatever point we're at.
OK.
So we're going to go over here and this should be a pretty quick video because there's not too much
to do but basically we have a role.
We're using the grid.
We have a nine column since we're on a medium screen we have the nine column and three column.
OK.
So this div here which wraps around the age four in the paragraph this first one we're going to give
this an ID and we could call this anything I'm going to call it who.
And then we also want to give it a class of section and scrolls by.
OK so every section should have a specific ID and should have these two classes.
So this next one here I'm going to give an idea of what and then I'm going to give a class of section
and scrolls spy.
OK this one here same thing will give an ID of who are not who where and will give a class section and
scrolls.
All right so we have our IDs and classes for each section.
Now we're going to go down to this area.
Here we have the UL case.
This is basically just a UL with some allies and some aid tags.
What we're going to do is on the UL we want to give this a class of pinned now pinned is not specific
to scrolls by basically it just makes it a fit it makes it fix so that even if we scroll down this will
stay in place.
OK so you want to make sure you have that or else you're just going to scroll up and you won't be able
to see this.
So we're going to do pen.
We're also going to give it a class of section and then Table of Contents.
OK so this is
this is specific to scrolls by we want the Table of Contents.
All right.
And then for the lengths we want these to go to wherever ID that we have above.
So we want this to go to who we want this one to go to what.
And we want this one
to go to where.
Right and that should do it and I just put a margin.
Seven hundred pixels at the bottom just so we can keep scrolling.
So I'm going to save that and you see that automatically it looks different.
And if I hover over this we have this little red border on the side and let's see if I click on what
we do it'll scroll to that part.
I go to what who we are or where we are rather goes to that part.
I click on who we are it goes to the top and then as I scroll Actually it should it should show the
border as a scroll.
Not sure why it's not doing that.
Think I might mess something up here.
See
I know I didn't initialize it.
I need to go down to the Javascript.
So we're going to go down here and let's say scroll spy net.
So the class
of scrolls spy we need to just call Daut scrolls by like that and say There we go.
So now the border shows and as a scroll it's going to show us where we are.
And again we can still click and it'll take us to that area.
Before I was just doing the standard ID the standard HMO ID but now it's an act actually initialized.
All right so it's pretty nice for like an About page or something like that.
So in the next video we're going to take a look at tab's.