Guys in this video we're going to take a look at tab's.
So again if you've had experience with bootstrap and some other frameworks tabs are very popular.
You basically have a line of tabs you click on and it shows the content from that one click another
one shows the content.
So this is the basic markup here we're using the grid so we have a row.
We have a 12 column row.
And that's where we're putting the UL.
And then underneath that we have another 12 column I should say 12 column div for each tab.
OK.
And then what we want to do is add to the to the right here.
A class of tabs OK to let it know that it is in fact tabs and you'll see as soon as I save it lines
them up horizontally and then for this first line we have we're going to set this to a class of tab.
OK Cingular We're also going to do call S-3 because we want it to basically be we want three or I'm
sorry for three column tabs.
OK.
And then for the tag that's around this text right here we're going to have this go to hash Tab 1 K
and you can call that whatever you want.
And then for the second ally same thing we'll do tab call S3 and then for the Tref and we'll do hash
tag 2.
We wanted to call three
in each draft.
This one will be hash Tab 3 and then that's fine on
the hash tag for.
All right.
Now if I say that you see that it changes it it looks pretty nice and we can click on these different
tabs.
Kind of has a little slider animation.
Obviously this stuff isn't working because we haven't done anything to the content part.
So what we need to do is figure out what we want for Tab 1 which is obviously this area here.
So we're going to add an ID right here for Tab 1.
OK.
And then we're going to go to the next div add an ID tab to this one will have an ID of Tab 3.
And of course this one will have an ID of tab 4 and we'll save that.
And now if I click tab two you see we can see the content from tab to Tab 3 and so on.
I don't know why I have this outside of the paragraph and we just yeah this.
I'll fix this one on you guys but this shouldn't be.
There should be no text outside of the paragraph.
All right.
Here we go.
So that's that's a simple tab.
Now we also have what are called Sweetapple tabs.
So for this we're going to add to this.
Well we're going to add an ID of tab's dash Swype dash demo.
And we're going to also give this a class of tab's and K and then each ally will have a class same thing
tab call S-3.
So basically the same thing as we did above the Tref.
So the Tref is going to go to let's say Id tab swipe one
Sury a Tref or B tab swipe to one more will do tab.
Call.
Three
and you know it's at the A-Trak
tab dash.
Why dash 3.
All right.
Now we want to do is for these divs here we want to match the IDs to these eight graphs So the first
one will be tab's swipe one so will say ID equals pace.
Then Id calls this one will be two and then this one
will be three Ok I am also going to give these kids a class I'm going to give this a class of call has
12 blue.
I want these to be different colors so I'm going to copy that class and I'll say blue this one will
be red and this one will be green.
All right so let's see what that looks like.
So basically each content area is going to have a different background color.
Now this looks weird with no padding or anything.
So what we want to do is we want to go down to our javascript's and we're going to say
tabs actually let me see both of these have a class of tabs.
Correct.
Yes.
They both have a class of tabs.
So two
tabs.
Actually we can use the ID we use tabs swipe demo.
So instead of doing this we're going to do Id tabs swipe demo and let's say Dot tabs and then and here
I'm going to pass in an object and we're going to say survivable.
The swayable I'm going to set that to true and save and now you see that it fills out the content space.
OK so now we can do that.
I mean these don't have to be different colored backgrounds but I want you to clearly see that they
have different color backgrounds are different different content areas.
OK.
And of course arts tabs appear still work.
So that's it.
Those are tabs and that's it for the sandbox.
OK if we look in our files here we've done all the way from 2 1 to 5 5.
So what we're going to do now is we're going to jump in and we're going to start to create some projects
going on the stuff that we've learned so far.
OK so I realized that the sandbox isn't the funnest thing in the world to do but it is necessary to
learn the different class names and also just what's available with the framework.
All right so let's go and get started with some projects.