All right guys in this video we're going to start to talk about typography and alignment things like
that things to do with text.
So in the material I sandbox I'm going to open up to underscore one to biography and we're going to
go to the top here.
Now like I said we're going to start where it's a start here in most cases.
But just for this one file I want to take a look at the container because everything in the sandbox
files is wrapped inside of a container class.
OK.
Now if you've ever worked with bootstrap or most other frameworks there's a container class which gives
your content that is within it.
It gives it a with usually a flexible with.
And it gives it margin auto and pushes basically pushes it into the middle and add spacing.
So let's open up this file I'm going to use open.
I'm going to use live server.
So when I say open with a live server but of course you can just open it on your file system or you
can use another server or however you want to open it just get it open.
All right.
Now as you can see there's spacing on the sides here.
Even if I were to make this bigger you'll see up to a certain point then it just stays at that with.
And I think the max with this 12 80.
So let's actually take a look.
If we open up our chrome tools here and we go to the container and we look over here you see that we
have a media query for the men with 993 pixels.
And at this stage at this screen size the width of the container is 70 percent.
If I were to make this smaller let's put it back to where we had it.
And look at the container.
Now it's 85 percent OK so that with is going to change based on these media queries.
And if we look down here the max with is 12 80 pixels so no matter how big your browser is that's the
max with It'll be ok it also has that margin.
Auto.
So that's the container.
And let's go down here now where it says Start here and we're going to start to look at some headings
and paragraphs and stuff like that so I'm going to put in an H1 here.
Actually I'm going to put in the heading of each size just so we can see what they look like.
So that will be heading to an amusing Amet here.
Each drive will be heading five and age 6 having sex or let's save that and see what we got.
So these are what the headings look like.
Now there's really no special classes in the materialized framework for headings for instance bootstrap
4 has the display one display two headings.
There's none of that materialized you just basically have ones one version of a heading and you can
add color classes but we'll get into that in the next video.
So let's take a look at the CSSA Ford H-1.
So if I just go ahead and inspect the each one you'll see you have a font sizes of four point two RAM.
Now a RAM unit if you don't know is a relative measurement in CSSA.
Basically one RAM is equal to the amount of pixels of the root h t m l element.
So if we go ahead and look at that and see what that is we'll go to the h l element and you see as a
font size of 14 pixels so in materialize if we use the unit 1 REM then we're using 14 pixels.
Now where the heading is four point two RAM.
It's going to be 4.2 times 14 pixels and that will be the amount of pixels so we can actually see that
under computed in the chrome tools if I were to go down here and you see that the actual size in pixels
is fifty eight point eight pixels.
Ok heading to is forty nine point eighty four pixels which is if we go back to Styles three point five
six ram OK and then every heading has a line height of 110 percent and it has these margins which are
also in RAM units.
OK one of the feedbacks that I got on my bootstrap course where we did the same thing we set up a sandbox
is some people said that I was just adding classes and not really talking about what they did.
So in this course I'm going to look more into the CSSA and actually see what it's doing OK but I don't
want to do that too too much because I think it will just take up a ton of time if we see every single
style for every single element in class.
But I will be doing it more often than I did in the bootstrap corps.
All right so now for a paragraph we're going to go ahead and just add a simple paragraph.
If we're using it you can just do Lorem you could do the word larm and then a number.
So let's say 20 and then tab and that will give me 20 words of sample text.
So if I save that you can see that this is the paragraph I just added and that's just what the standard
paragraph looks like and materialize.
And if we look at the see SS Basically it's just displayed as a block.
Not too much not too much style on a paragraph.
Nothing really special.
Now for a block quote Let's go ahead and add that.
So I'll go down here and we'll put in a block quote.
Whoops.
You know what caps will do.
Warm 10 tablets would give us 10 words and save.
And then this is what a block quote looks like.
So it basically gives you this red line.
This border on the left and it gives you some padding between attacks.
OK.
Looks like the text size is the same as a paragraph.
So that's a block quote.
Now in addition to just the standard paragraph we have a flow text paragraph so we can use this with
the class of flow dash text and save and you can see it does a couple of things one it makes the text
bigger.
So if we were to look at the font size you'll see it as a font size of 1.3 9 to ram.
Now that said this screen size flow text makes it so that this is completely responsive this text if
I make this bigger you'll see that text actually gets bigger.
So now if we look it is one way to change 1.6 a ram.
Yeah.
Now if we go down here it's 1.4 that it's 1.3.
So it changes based on the screen size or the device size which is really cool.
All right so that's what flow text does.
So now what I want to do is look at alignment.
We have these three H fives here I want to align them so we're going to add the first one we'll have
a class of line dash left and if I save there's going to be no difference because it's already aligned
to the left.
This one here lets out a class of a line right and save and that did nothing.
Let's see.
That's because it's supposed to be left align and right line not aligned left and right left.
Right so the write right align and save and you can see now that's lined to the right and for this 8:5
here let's do class and let's do center line and save and now that's aligned to the center.
Now vertical alignment.
What I'm going to do is this div that wraps to each five.
I'm just going to give an inline style and I'm going to give it a height of let's say 400 pixels and
then just a light gray background.
OK.
And then if I save that is see that it gives it the 400 pixels.
And what I want to do is I want this text to be in the middle vertically.
So what we would do is we would add a class not to the H5 but to the wrapper.
OK so there's actually a class called V a line dash wrapper.
And if I save that it'll move it down it'll center it vertically OK which can be helpful.
We also have quick floats.
So if we would just want to align to the right or left or real quick we can say class equals two left.
And then for this paragraph will do.
Class equals right.
Now if I say that it's going to look weird because what's happening is we're not clearing our floats.
So to do that we need to put a div here which I have and we're going to add a class of clear fix a just
like bootstrap if you're familiar with bootstrap and I'll be making references to bootstrap because
I'm sure a lot of you already know that framework just because it's so big and popular so it's save.
And now you can see that the floats are being cleared.
All right so I think that's going to do it for alignment and typography and stuff like that.
Notice that I can scroll down more that's because with some of these pages I just put this margin top
five hundred pixels.
That way you know you guys don't have to look at the bottom of the screen because that's what was happening.
So I decided to put that there so that I could put stuff in the middle even if it's at the bottom.
All right.
So the next video we're going to get started on text background colors.
OK.
Or I should say text colors and background colors.