All right in this video we're going to take a look at collar's So that's one thing that materializes
is really good with colors are so many to choose from.
There's different shades of colors we can use and this is for text as well as background colors for
just about any element.
All right so what I have is just a bunch of paragraphs they all they all the same dummy text inside
of them and we're going to look at some of the color classes.
Now first thing we'll look at is text colors.
OK so for text colors we're going to give these classes of a color name so let's say red and then dash
text.
So if I go ahead and save that you'll see that that is now read text.
All right.
So let's add some other colors here so I'll say class equals and let's do blue dash text.
All right so for this one let's say we'll do orange dash.
TEXT
And it's two green text
yellow.
So these are kind of the standard colors are the just the more common colors.
There's some other ones as well that aren't so common that I'll show you in a minute.
So we have purple
and many frameworks just have like four or five colors there's just a ton with materialize so we have
pink
and we have gray.
And for this one here it's two brown text and we also have white text.
All right.
So let's go ahead and save that and you can see all these different colors.
We have the white text you can't see because it's on a white background.
But if you have a dark background color you're going to want to use white text.
Ok so we also have some less common colors.
So one of these
is Deep Purple.
So if we say deep Dasch purple Dasch text and say You see it's kind of a different purple than this
one here.
And we also have indigo so I'll say Indigo Dasch text and save and that gives us kind of a different
color purple or Indigo of cyan.
So science texts we have teal
Teall text
we have lime
we have Amber dash texts and we can do like green
if we got the class there.
And then for this paragraph here let's do deep orange
and then for this final one we're going to do a blue gray.
So blue the gray dash text.
So save that and I can see we have a whole nother group of less common colors I call them.
OK so if you want to look more into the different colors if you go to the materialize documentation
let's see it's click on this and go to I think it's CSSA color.
And you see all the different color palette.
So we have red paint.
So these are just basically all the colors reviews purple deep purple blue.
I'm pretty sure I used all of them cyan of light blue and then use that
green we use that lime so all the different color palettes and we're going to get into the different
shades as well but white and red.
Now what I want to do is look at background colors.
So what I'll do is copy all the standard colored paragraphs and I'm going to go down here and I'm just
going to replace this here.
All these paragraphs and then just remove the word text
OK and what that does is it makes the background that color not the text.
If you want the text color then you need to include just dash text.
If not it'll do the background so let's go back and save and I can see we have our background colors.
All right.
Now there is some padding to these paragraphs because for this file I just added a style of five pixel
padding.
If we didn't have this then we wouldn't have as much space around the graph.
But I figured that adding that may makes it look a little better and you can see the color a little
better.
All right so that's how we can add the background colors.
Now if you have for instance let's say this purple background you probably are probably going to want
white text on that.
So we could go ahead and also add the class of white dash text and save and now we have white text.
All right.
And you can do any color text save for this yellow.
We wanted to do green tax which will look really ugly but we can do it.
OK.
And then we also have our less common colors backgrounds so what I'll do is copy those and we'll just
replace these standard paragraphs and just remove the word text from all of these so I'll go ahead and
use some vias code magic I can do I can do control D-NV s code it'll just select all of those and I'll
just delete them.
All right so I'll save that.
And now we have our background colors with these less calming colors.
All right so now let's take a look at Darkon and Litan.
So let's take this first paragraph and let's add a class of red and save.
All right so it gives us a red background.
Now we have different levels of Darkon enlightened so I'm going to go ahead and say Darkon actually
I'll leave this one at red so we can see the difference.
But then this next one here I'm going to add a class of red again and then dark and Dash 1.
All right so if I save that you'll see that it's slightly darker than the regular red.
And then for this one will again say red and will say dark and Dash 2 for this one let's say red whoops
we need a class.
So will save red and dark and dash 3.
And it goes up to four.
So this one will be red and dark and dash four and save.
And I can see it just gets darker as it goes up as the number goes up.
And at the same time we have lightening noon so I'm going to just copy all of these and go ahead and
paste these here and I'm just going to change the dark and so again I'll do control d to select all
these darkens and change them to lighten and save and I can see that they get progressively lighter
as the number goes up.
OK so that's it for colors.
Guys we have a lot of options so you can add colors to buttons to divs paragraphs anything at all.
All right so I will see you in the next video.