All right in this video we're going to take a look at Buttons.
OK so we have quite a bit of options when it comes to buttons right here.
I'll go to.
We're it's a start here.
It's a standard button in the two three buttons icons each time I'll file.
And see I have it loaded here under this menu item.
And what I'm going to do is add to this button tag a class of just between.
OK so let's save that.
Now this is what basically a standard materialise button looks like and we can add this to a button
as well as a link tags so we can see a class Button here as well.
And it'll basically look the same.
OK.
Now we also have a cool waves effect with materialize so for you are to give this a class can't I.
So a class of BGN.
And then we can do waves dash effect.
And we're going to see waves dash light and let's save that.
And now if I go to a regular button and I click look you'll see that nothing really happens if I click
the waves you can see the little effect that it gives us.
OK and we can do this on a button or a link.
So if I just grab this class and put it on this link you'll see it does the same thing.
All right.
Now we also can add different colors to these waves so what we're going to do is I'm going to add a
class of white K for that for this button here for all of these buttons.
We also need to be T.N. class which gives it all its padding and stuff.
And then let's make the text I will say read Desch text.
Ok so this is all stuff that we've already learned all the color stuff.
And then I'm also going to say waves dash effect and then lets say waves dash red.
OK so now if I go to this button and click you'll see that we get the red wave.
All right.
Now just to make this a little shorter.
Let's go ahead and just paste this in.
What is it for so.
One two three four and we'll just change up the colors so we'll say let's do T.L. and then we'll change
the waves to waves dash T.L. and your text doesn't have to match the color.
But I think it looks nice when it does.
Let's do green and we'll say green text and then for this one let's do you know let's do grey text but
we'll do a yellow wave
and then for this last one wants to purple.
So will say purple Tex and let's say waves dash purple and we'll save and now each one that I click
you can see that it has a different color wave effects.
That's pretty cool.
Now we can also have icons very do this material icons library.
You do have to include it.
You can see appear in the head.
I'm including it.
What I've also done in this file is include the font.
Awesome CDN which is another icon library because I want to show you that you can use those as well
if you prefer font.
Austin does have a lot more choices than the material icons.
All right.
So let's go right here and let's see.
To add an icon we're going to use an eye tag and we're going to give it a class of material dash icons.
So this is how it works.
Every icon gets a class of material icons and then the specific icon you want.
You put that in here the identifier so let's say I want a shopping cart icon and I'll say shopping underscore
cart and save and it gives me that icon.
And if you want to check all of these though I forget the exact you R-AL but will see him with Tiriel
icons.
And yeah it's material Daut IO slash icons.
And down here you'll see all of the different things that you can add so it's look for shopping cart
Let's see where is it's big area here.
So if I click shopping cart an icon for Aunt right here shows us how to use it.
I class material icons and then shopping under score card so you can check this site if you want to
check out the different icons that are available.
Now what I'll do is let's let's copy a couple of these down so we'll do one two three more and to do
that I'm just doing shift alter shift option and down.
OK so let's let's do settings and let's do a search on
and stars icon.
OK.
So if we save that we get a bunch of different icons and if we want to change the color that's simple
we just add text colors so red dash text.
Technically these are fonts.
So we want to add you want to use the text colors will say blue dash text and save.
And I can see that those two icons have different colors.
We can also change the sizes.
So what I'll do is let's say I class material icons just using Emett here and then let's just take the
done icon which is basically a checkmark can see right here and I'm going to just copy this down four
times and this one here I'm also going to give a class of large and for this one I'll give a class of
medium.
This one will be small and this one will be tiny.
OK so let's save that and you can see we can have different sizes of icons using these different classes.
Now what if we want to have a button with icons so for that we go down here to button with material
icon and let's add inside the tag.
And this could be just as well a button but we're using an Atallah here.
Let's give it a beat and.
And we'll even give it a waves effect and say Wavves dash light.
And inside here next to the by now text we're going to put in I tag give it a class of material dash.
And inside here let's use the shopping cart icon
I will just put a little space here and let's save and I can see we have a button with an icon now to
make this a little more aligned to what we can do is we can add in the class with material icons left
and save.
And now you see it's aligned nicely and we can do the same thing with a right aligned icon.
So if I were to copy this I will just replace this one and we'll go ahead and just change it to right
right here and save.
Now the icon is on the right.
And then just to show you we can use font awesome icons.
I'll copy this a tag and instead of doing it like this we'll use the font awesome method which doesn't
have anything inside the eye element we just need to add a special class of F.A. for font.
Awesome.
And then whatever icon we want which we want.
F.A. dash shopping dash cart.
And then we'll put it on the left and we'll save.
And there we go you can see it looks slightly different because this is a fine awesome icon.
All right.
And you can go to I think it's fine.
Awesome dog.
I know.
And you can see all the different icons they have.
All right so we can have different colored buttons so if we just go ahead and add a class of BGN and
we could add for instance red and save we get a red button.
We could do better then let's do purple.
You're not limited to any colors you can use any of the colors that are available
so if we wanted to do like Tio do that
if we wanted to do black
or eyelets to Amber and save and we get all these nice looking colored buttons.
Okay and last two things I want to show you are large Broughton's and disabled buttons.
So our class of DTN And actually we don't even need the just the beat and we can just do between large
and save and we get a large button.
Now for some frameworks like bootstrap you'd have to do both the beat and.
And then I think it's between algae or something like that.
But it materialized we just need the one BT and large.
Now for a button to be disabled well just give it a BGN in class will make this one large as well should
be in the class.
So just to be Teahen large.
And then we'll add a class of disabled and save.
And now that button is disabled so I can't click on it or anything.
All right so that's going to be guys in the next video we're still going to look at Buttons what we're
going to look at the floating buttons which are one of the coolest elements in materialise.