All right.
So in the last video we looked at just standard buttons.
Now we're going to look at floating buttons and fixed action buttons.
And if you've ever seen anything with materialize you've probably seen these before the circular buttons.
We can even have them fixed to the bottom here or wherever and we can have it make it so that we click
and then some other buttons open and it looks really cool it's just a really cool looking UI.
So let's start with a simple floating button so I'm in my two four floating dot age team I'll file I
have it open in my browser and we just basically have a button here with an I tag OK no classes or anything
yet.
We're going to add that now.
So for the button we're going to add a class of between dash floating and if we save that it's going
to just be a saw basically a circle and then we want to add let's make it a large button so add beats
and dash large.
So that makes it bigger.
Let's also give it the waves of fact.
So we'll see waves effect.
And we also do waves dash lights and then let's also change the color to red.
So save Now these buttons normally have icons inside of them or else it's just a circle.
So what we'll do is give this the standard class of material dash icons and then the icon I want is
a plus sign which is the ad icon so let's save that and there we go.
So there we have a floating button and you can see it has that Wavves effect.
So what I'll do is copy this and let's create another one.
So just paste that here actually will make this one a link so I'll just make this in a tag instead of
a button.
Go and put a tag there as well.
Let's change the icon to it.
And let's also change the color to blue and save.
And there we go.
Now we can also add a pulse effect and this isn't just for floating buttons.
This is an effect you can put on.
Pretty pretty sure you can put it on anything but it looks really good on button.
So what I'm going to do is just grab this whole a tag the folding button here actually will grab this
standard button tag and paste that in and I'm going to change the icon to publish just to make it a
little different.
And then I'm also going to change the color to green and then I'm simply going to add the class of pulse.
OK and we'll save that.
And now you can see that it just has a constant pulse effect which looks pretty cool.
So these are standard floating buttons.
Now I'm going to comment out everything we just did in vs code you can just do contard you can highlight
it and you can do control and then forward slash and I will comment everything out.
See why is this I guess since we have a comment here we have to do it separately so we'll comment the
stuff and then we'll comment.
So OK so now let's down to the simple fixed action button.
And basically what this does is it'll give us the folding button.
But it will be down here and it will be in place we won't be able to move it no matter how big you resize
the browser or make it smaller.
It should stay in that place.
All right so let's go ahead and just add to this div here a class of fixed will see fixed dash action
dash button and then we're going to go into the button the actual button and say between dash.
Floating.
Let's also do BT and dash large and let's make it red and then I'm also going to give this an add icon
and we'll save let's see what am I missing here I forgot the class.
So should the class equals and save should be material icons.
So we have the button now it's not fixed.
That's because it shouldn't be button the word it should be between so fixed action between then and
now you can see that it's in place down here.
And even if I were to make this smaller it's just going to stay there it's absolute basically OK.
So now what I want to do is make it so that we can have a button here and if we click it will have a
bunch of other buttons kind of just pop up right here which looks really nice.
So I'm going to comment this so that we just did and go down here and we're going to add in a bunch
of stuff here.
So we're going to put in this div a class of fixed dash action dash B.T. and not button.
I want to do BT and then this tag will do Class B and ash floating and we'll make it large and red and
then for the icon
the icon let's do mode dash at it.
So this would be like something you'd have on on a blog added page something like that a post and a
page.
And then in the UL This is where the pop up buttons are going to go.
So we actually want to go into the ally and into the tag and we're going to add a class of again between
Dasch floating and we'll make this read.
And for the icon to insert char OK and of course we need the class
material icons.
All right so will do that's when you will go to the next one here.
Let's actually just copy this.
Ally and then we'll just pasted in what's this one two three more times
you know change this one to say blue will change the icon
will change just to its two format quote
and then this one will be yellow and will change that icon to publish.
And then this final one here say green and we'll change that to attach file attach underscore file.
All right so if I go down here and now you see when I hover over it it gives us these other floating
buttons which looks really nice.
Now there's a couple options that we can add to this you'll see in the comment.
I have horizontal and click to toggle those are two actions or two classes that we can add to change
the effect so you see how it comes from the top end goes up.
We can make this go this way horizontal by going ahead and adding in a horizontal class like that.
So if we save and I go on I hover.
Now it goes the other way.
Now if you want to make it so that you have to actually click it click it for this effect then you can
do that as well by adding in click dash to dash toggle.
So now if I go down I hover it doesn't do anything.
If I click it that it does I can just toggle that effect.
All right.
Now one other thing I'm going to show you is the fixed action button toolbar which is another really
cool effect but after a comment this stuff out or else we'll have some some compatibility issues and
we're going to go ahead and add on to this div..
We're going to give it a class of fixed action button and then also we're going to give you a class
of toolbar.
OK.
Now for this inside the div this link here is a tag we're going to give this a class of beat dash floating.
And then let's make it large and let's make it red and then for the icon
we're going to do the mode and it
OK and then the well doesn't need anything else.
However we're going to give a class of waves waves effect and waves dash light.
OK and the ATAC does not have a class on it or anything like that.
But let's put our icons so this will be insert charts
all right.
And what I'll do is just grab this ally here with the class and just pass that on to these beginning
allies and then let's also copy the icon just to make this shorter.
And we'll change these icons so this one will be format quote
and let's do publish
and let's to attach file.
OK so let's save.
And now if I go down and they click on this button there economy it turns into a toolbar which is pretty
cool.
And if I click off of the toolbar it goes back to the button.
So this is the kind of stuff that I think separates materialize from Bootstrap bootstrap does not have
stuff like this.
OK.
Interactive UI elements like this.
I'm not saying one is better than the other.
Bootstrap is much more used so it is very beneficial to learn bootstrap.
But as far as design elements go I'm a fan of materialize.
Now we can open and close this stuff through javascript as well so if I were to go down here and let's
use a little bit of jay query and we'll say fixed action dash between and let's call open toolbar
OK so we're grabbing the fixed action button which is this and we're calling a function called Open
toolbar and that's going to run when the page loads so it's save.
And you'll see that it just automatically goes to a toolbar and at the same time we have a closed toolbar.
So if we say close to our IT basically just opens and closes when the when we enter the page.
OK so you can you can manipulate it from the javascript and you can do the same thing with the standard
floating action buttons by doing instead of open toolbar.
You could do open fab like that and you can do close fab.
OK.
So that would be for the floating button that we have commented out or I'm sorry the fixed action button
the fab.
So you can open and close out from javascript as well but I'm just going to comment this stuff out.
I just wanted in there so you guys know that that's possible.
All right.
So that's it.
That's it for floating buttons.
We will get back into these later on.
But in the next video we're going to start to look at nav bars navigation in material eyes.