All right guys so now we're going to get into the nav bar of.
Now one thing you may notice that's different about this file is where it says start here it's actually
under the container and the reason I did that is because most nav bars are going to go all the way across
the page you're not going to be restricted inside of the container.
So that's what I wanted to do so I put every all the bars underneath the containers so they go all the
way across.
So first we're going to look at just the standard navigation menu so just having the nav tag gives us
all of this so it gives us this pinkish background and padding and all that.
In fact if we look at the see SS by hover over the nav and we go down you see and automatically has
a height of 64 pixels that has this background color here with 100 percent color of white.
So just the nav tag has quite a bit of style with materialize.
Now to turn it into an actual nav bar what we'll do is go to this first div right here and we're going
to add a class of NAV dash wrapper.
All right.
And then we're going to go to the next div and what I like to do is put a container class inside of
the Nav wrapper and you don't have to do this.
But if you don't your nav bar is going to it's going to be stuck up against the side like this how this
logo is and it's going to stretch no matter how far you go.
So I like to put a container within it.
So if I save that now you can see that that's pushed in.
All right.
So it's the for the logo the tag that has the logo in it we're going to give that a class and that's
going to be brand brand dash logo.
OK so once they do that notice that you can see our links.
OK now these will change based on
while actually that's actually I guess it's not going to change based on the screen size just yet.
But what we can do is we can add to our UL which is going to have an ID of NAV dash mobile and then
we can add a class here and we're going to say.
Right.
And that will move all of our links to the right.
And then let's do hide on small and down.
Now what this means is that these links are going to be hidden.
If the size of the browser of the device is on the small size or lower.
So if I go ahead and save this it's not quite on small yet but if I make the smaller use you'll notice
that they disappear OK and that so it doesn't run into the logo.
By default the logo is going to be centered when it's on a smaller screen.
When I go back up you'll see that it gets it's now on the left.
OK.
So when I get around tablet size or maybe a little bigger I maybe like laptop size the logo automatically
goes to the middle and then we get really small the menu items disappear OK.
So our solution to this for mobile devices would be to add a button that we could click that would open
up a side menu with the links.
OK so that's what we're going to do next we're going to go down to our responsive side menu or a response
I should say responsive nav bar with side menu.
So let's go ahead and add I'm actually going to change the color as well.
You can change the color of absolutely anything.
So the nav bar will say we want it to be blue and let's add Darkon dash 4.
OK and that gives us a blue nav bar also going to give it a container
and let's add to this div right here we want.
Now rapper
and for the logo let's add class brand dash logo.
OK so that moves it to the middle.
And you see this a tag here is going to is basically going to be like our hamburger menu it's going
to be the icon we click that opens up the sidebar.
So we need to add a couple of things to this one as a class.
So we're going to say class equals and we're going to set this to the button dash collapse class.
Now in addition to a class we need an attribute called Data dash activates.
OK because we're activating the mobile menu.
So I'm going to call this mobile dash now and you can call this whatever you want you just have to make
sure that your UL that you put down here has that ID.
All right but before we get to that let's first add the icon we want.
So this will be class material icons.
Ok it's always material icons no matter what the icon you want goes in here which in this case will
be menu.
All right so that looks a little weird.
We have the the icon but all of the drop all of the links are showing.
So to fix that we want to go to this well here and we want to add our class.
First we want to say right and then we want to say hide on.
And this time I'm going to do medium screens on medium screens and down and save and now that right
menu is hidden.
OK.
Now this.
See we're going to ignore the dropdown right now.
That's actually part of the well that's hidden what you're seeing here the home about them contact is
this.
Well now this is what's going to open on the sidebar when we click this button.
OK.
But we don't want it to show here.
So what we do is add a class of side dash nav and then we want to give it an I.D. that matches whatever.
This is the data activates in this case it's mobile nav.
So we want to go down here and we want to make sure that that ID is mobile nav.
Now if I save you'll see it disappears.
OK which is what we want.
Now if I click on the button here nothing happens.
That's because in order to use the side NAV you need to actually initialize it in Jey query in javascript
so we're going to go way down to the bottom and we're going to initialize this sidebar by using Jay
queery and sing dot button collapse.
OK button collapse is the class of this button right here and then we're going to just say Daut side
now.
OK we're going to call that function.
And now if I save and I go in I click.
There we go it opens up a sidebar with whatever is in this UL right here.
OK.
So you could have a different set of links here.
Ignore this thing.
Ignore this stuff for now.
But you can have a different set of links here in fact we do.
Then your sidebar or you could have them the exact same so it just works like a responsive menu.
OK hopefully that makes sense.
So now what I'm going to do is just make sure that this all these links are showing.
And we're going to now work on it say will do.
Let's do the dropdown.
OK so we have a list item here under the home about contact.
Then we have this list item and I want this to be a dropdown.
And what we need to do is let's say we need to added Id or ID we just need to actually you seek at a
class
in the class of dropdown button.
Dash button.
All right.
And then let's just put in.
I'm sorry.
This should be on the tag not the ally.
All right.
So draw down button.
And then it's going to also have a data activates
and we want to set this to.
We could set this to anything I'm going to set it to my dash dropped down
and let's see we're going to have an icon in here.
So this icon is going to be like in a down arrow that you would have next door dropped down so it's
going to be erro dash drop dash down.
So we'll save that
and see.
That's weird.
Oh you know we need to put a right class with the material icons.
There we go.
So now we have the arrow there.
Now it's not going to work what it's doing is it's looking for an idea of my dropdown and it's looking
for a UL with that I.D. Now that you well we can put anywhere we can put it here or we could just go
outside of the nav bar itself and put it down which I actually have it right here.
So I'm just going to give this an idea now of my dash dropdown cage match whatever that data activates
was and then it also has a class of dropdown dash content.
OK and that's it.
Let's save and let's go over here and now when I hover over it.
There we go.
You can see this UL is showing.
So this you can be completely separate from the nav bar we can put this at the bottom of the file it
doesn't matter as long as this ID my dropdown matches whatever we put in the data activates.
OK so just a couple of other things I want to mention a button link.
So this log in let's say we want that to be a button.
All we would have to do is go and add to our tag here.
Class equals BTA and we could give it a wave's effect say Wavves dash lights and save.
And there we go.
Now we have a button in our NAV are OK we can also have an icon link.
This P actually wasn't supposed to be here.
That's right.
It's just part of.
Person which is the icon I want to use say class material icons and save.
And there we go.
Now we have a little icon inside the nav bar.
So couple other things if we wanted to make a link active.
I'm just going to make this a little smaller.
Let's say we want this about linked to be active.
I'm going to go up to the top menu here and just add onto the ally tag the class of active and save.
And I can see that's active.
Now when we make this bigger the logo automatically goes to the left.
But if we wanted that to stay in the center we could also add to the brand logo class a center class
and save.
And now you see it will stay in the center no matter what.
So just a couple extra things that you can do with your nav bars.
So what about the fixed nav bar meaning that if we scroll down we want it to basically just stay in
place.
So what I'm going to do is take the standard menu that we have and we'll just grab that whole thing
and go down to where it says fixed nav bar and just replace these two.
Actually I'm going to put it inside the device sorry.
And all we have to do to make it fixed is take this device wrap it around the nav bar and give it a
class of nav bar dash fixed and save will actually make this a different color.
We'll make this one black and save and it's fixed so you can see I can scroll actually to make this
a little more understandable.
Let's make this margin top 1000.
And now if I scroll you'll see it's just going to stay in place and usually you'd have this at the top
so it would stay right at the top.
All right so the last thing I want to show you is a search bar which is kind of like just a nav bar
search box kind of thing.
So I'm just going to type this out quickly will have a nav with the class of let's make it green and
let's put in a class of Nav. wrapper and then we'll put in a form.
We don't need an action.
It's not going to actually do anything it's just a form.
We're going to have a class of input field and we're going to get into this later on when we get to
forms and we'll have an input.
We'll give an idea of search and let's give it a type of search and we'll just say it's required
acquired and then we're going to put in a label and I'm going to give this a class of labeled dash icon
and we'll say for search and let's see inside the label.
I'm actually going to put in I tag put our material icons class and let's make this a search icon and
then I also want a close icon after the labels will say material icons and clothes.
All right.
Let's save that now a little search icon if I click it and it becomes a search box if I could close
it goes back.
So pretty cool.
All right so that's going to be it for now.
Barrs guys in the next video we're going to start to look at collections which are kind of like fancy
lists groups or fancy list items.