All right in this video we're going to take a look at collections which are a big part of materialize
a lot of times you're going to have lists of data especially if you're building like an application
that fetches from an API you might want to display that data that comes back inside of a collection.
So we have some markup here it just looks horrible by default without any of the classes or anything.
So we're going to work on this we're going to start with the just standard collection.
OK we're in the 2 6 collections age Tim I'll file and to create a collection.
All we have to do is add a class of collection.
And these are similar to lists groups in Bootstrap where you'd have a class of lists group and then
you'd have a class of lists group item well in materialise we just want a class of collection item.
OK so pretty much the same kind of thing.
A collection item.
All right.
And let's save that.
And there we go so that looks a lot better than it did before.
And that's just a basic collection item.
Now you may want to have a collection item as a link.
So kind of like a menu maybe a side menu.
In this case we'd have a div and we'd give it a class of collection and then for each tag here we'd
have a class of collection item.
OK so basically the same classes just different elements.
And I'll just copy this make this a little quicker.
OK.
And let's see the badges.
I'm just going get rid of that for now.
We'll do that after.
So let's save.
And now you can see we have kind of like a side menu we have a collection links.
All right.
Now badges are just like little if you want a little box with maybe these are our categories of blog
posts and you might want to have the number of posts in each category.
That's where a badge comes in handy so we'd have a span and then we would do class equals badge and
actually you know class equals badge.
And then let's save that see what that looks like.
Second 44
Oh we get to give this class of collection item.
OK.
So it's just basically just putting a number over here.
Now we want to make it look a little bit fancier.
What we could do.
We need our classic election for this a tag.
And then in this span let's do class badge and also do new and save.
And what that does is it basically gives it a background here.
And it also puts in new and it's helpful because you wouldn't have to put in the word new programmatically
you could just have just the number and then materialized takes care of putting in the word new.
All right so let's take a look at a whole collection with a header.
So what we would do is have a UL and give it a class of collection just like above.
But we would also have a class of with Dasch not with w i th with header.
OK.
And then for this first ally it would have a class of collection dash Hetter.
All right.
In the rest of these will have classes of collection item just like any other collection.
All right so let's go ahead and save that.
And now if we look down here we have this header that says items and then we have all the items underneath.
OK so we also have something called secondary content
and looks like I have an extra or I forgot my angle bracket right here.
OK.
For secondary content the UL.
We're going to do again collection and then with Hetter need a class though.
And then this list item will have a class of collection header and say items and then each of these
allies will have a collection item class.
And now under the first item here or under whatever text is here we have an eight tag and we're going
to give this a tag class of secondary content.
OK.
And then the secondary content is going to be an icon.
I'm going to make it a close eye on making an X so let's say it was something you could delete
it all right.
So if I save that now you see we have a collection item with an X over here and just to shorten this
up let's take this ally and let's see we have three more so we'll go one two three and I'll just change
this to second third.
And fourth they're all going to have the same X icons so that's fine.
All right so now we just have a collection with some delete icons over here.
Now we can also do Avatar content or Avatar collections where we can have like either an icon on the
side or an out an image we could form an image we're just going to use icons.
We're going to pretend this is like an address book type thing.
So we'll go ahead and give this you all a class of collection and this ally will be abse
class collection and or a collection item.
And then also avatar.
All right and I'm just going to copy that.
OK and then the icon underneath.
Let's make this a Contax icon.
And we're going to give this a couple classes in addition to material icons because I want it to be
blue.
And I also wanted to be a circle k so we can give this a circle class and then we're going to leave.
Actually the span we're going to give it a class of title which I think just makes it a little bigger
or a little more prominent and then that stuff will stay.
No need for for any classes on that.
That's a tag this will be the secondary content
that should be secondary Dasch content and let's make this a great icon.
Or if I save that.
There we go so that looks pretty good.
You know what I'm going to do instead of having to type all that out let's just copy the whole ally
and we'll just replace these three other guys so I'll paste that in.
That's one two three and then we'll just change the names.
So say Steve Smith.
Hey Karen
and I will say Mary Williams and Mary and we'll just leave the same phone number.
Not a big deal just want to show you how it's formatted so that looks pretty good.
All right.
So one other thing I wanted to show you that isn't really relevant to collection's is having a badge
inside of a dropdown OK because we also mentioned badges and this in this lecture.
So we're just going to have basically a button that has a drop down and we can put a badge inside of
it so let's do a tag with the class of B.T. And and we're also going to give it a class of dropdown
dash button.
OK.
And then we're going to give it a data activates
because the sidebar
So our data activates I'm going to set this to drop down one and inside here let's just say drop down
and let's put an icon.
I'm going to go on the next line.
And this will be an arrow underscore this drop underscored down so if I saved that.
Now we have this drop down in let's see for the HGF I'm just going to do a hash in a exclamation so
it doesn't go anywhere.
Now underneath that let's create our UL with the ID of draw down 1 K because that's what we use for
the data activates.
So inside here.
And this actually also has to have a class of dropdown content.
OK.
So I will put in an ally.
And inside the ally will have an eight tag and let's say this is item 1.
Shall just go ahead and make a couple of these
proofs.
Sorry about that
all right so the Subi for three and two for save that.
Now we have our drop down now if we wanted to put a badge in one of these we could go inside the tag
and we could say spanne class badge and I'll say 44.
All right we could also do a new badge
so we could say spand class badge and new.
And we'll say three.
All right so let's save and there we go.
So if you had like a directory site or something like that you add new new items or new posts you could
use these badges.
All right so that's going to be IT guys that is collections and badges in the next video we're going
to.
We're going to work on a really important part of materialized or any framework and that is the grid
system.