All right so now we're going to take a look at one of the most important parts of any framework and
that's the grid system.
So the materialized grid is pretty easy to use.
One thing I want to do before we get started is go into the head you see the style tags.
We're just going to add the style for a collage class of box because I want to make the grid I want
you to be able to see the columns better.
So we're going to have a class box with a background of light gray which is F for three times and then
we're going to have just some padding.
So we'll say 10 pixels padding and then we're going to just text a line to the center.
OK so save that and we'll go down to where it says Start here and we're going to first look at non-responsive
grids meaning that whatever columns we put it's going to be the same for all screen sizes.
OK.
Now all grids should be wrapped in the class of row just like bootstrap if you're familiar with bootstrap.
And then what I want is 12 one column divs So we're going to have the class of call.
We're also going to have the class of S1.
OK.
Now as for small we basically have four sizes we have small we have medium large and extra large.
Now if we just too small it basically propagates up.
So any.
If we say small one it's also going to be medium one large one extra large one it's going to be just
a non-responsive grade it's going to always be the same.
So in here I'm going to put our box class in I'm just going to put the number one Actually I'll leave
that blank and then I'm just going to copy this down.
So let's do 12 of these so two three four five six seven eight nine 10 11 12 and save and you can see
that we have 12 columns I'm just going to put numbers in here so 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 and 10 11 and 12.
All right.
So there our 12 column div and no matter what screen size I have it on it's always going to be 12 columns.
OK so let's do one example for let's say three four column divs.
So we'd have our row and then we would do call and we'd say ask for a member of this 12 all together.
So four times three is 12.
So if we want three of them three full columns and we want it to be an ask for an inside here we'll
do dot box and we'll say 1 and then what I'll do is just grab this and let's make two more of these
and we'll just change this to three and we'll change this to two and save.
And then we go Oh so now we have three four column divs.
So let's say we want to do two six column divs if you guys want to pause it and try and come back.
You can do that but it's really easy.
We're just going to do call and let's do x 6.
Ok so I have 2 6 column divs let's say box and one will do the same thing here so call six.
And inside here will two box and two.
And there we go.
Now we have two six column dips.
OK and if we wanted to do an 8 and 4 so like a side bar in the main area that's really easy we'll just
do a row and then we'll do a class of call and lets 2 8 8 be call
and we'll do what we call it.
Box
is called dots and this one will be s for
and then we go.
So now we have eight and four.
All right.
So as I said these these will stay the same no matter what the screen size.
Now if you wanted to make a responsive grade have inhabit different for multiple sizes for instance
let's take it
let's take our first example which is 12 one column does so I'll just grab that actually know what I'll
do.
Let's let's grab all of these so we'll grab the 12 one columns the three four columns and the two six
columns and we'll grab all of them and paste them in here.
But I'm going to get rid of these and the rid of the comments because they're going to change based
on size screen size.
So for this usually what we would do is we keep the or we change this to one if we wanted a 12 column.
So it's a medium size screens and up will be it'll be a 12 column row so no change at all to M1.
But if we get to small screens obviously I mean that's just it's too squished in there so let's change
it to x 12 where the column takes up the entire thing.
OK so it will be stacked so we'll just go ahead and add in as 12 like that.
I don't think I've ever even used a 12 column div but just to show you can know if I go when I make
this smaller.
When we get to small screens eight stacks.
OK so it makes it responsive if I get to here.
Now it's back to 12.
All right so let's go ahead and do this one here and we'll say instead of S-4 will say M four for a
medium and then we'll say x 12 which will make it stack because the small screens will take up all 12.
All right so if I go ahead and make the smaller.
Now I can see that this is now stacking on small screens.
OK so that makes that responsive.
Let's see four Actually we don't need to do this one is pretty much the same thing but for this one
here I'm going to add a bunch of different sizes.
So we'll have s 12 if it's a small screen.
Now if it's a medium screen let's do six and six.
So I've 2 six column divs.
If it's a large screen then let's do let's save the large screen we'll do nine
yeah we'll do.
Actually no it's 2 8 and 4.
OK.
And then if it's an extra large so say extra large and we'll do nine and we'll do three.
OK so this is a very responsive grid so let's save We'll start at the small screen.
So we're looking at the bottom one here you can see it stacked on small screens.
We get to see the medium screen and now it's six and six.
OK so it's two six columns.
If we get two large screens which is still not there right here now it's nine and 3.
And then if we get to extra large which is what make it really big now it's 8 and 4.
OK.
I'm sorry it's the opposite.
It was 8 and 4 with large and it's 9 and 3 with extra large OK.
So this is a very that's a very responsive grid row.
So another thing we can do is we can use push and poll to kind of switch the positions of the columns.
So we give you an example I'll put in a row and I'm going to put a class of call let's do s will say
s 7 which will just be 7 for all all sizes.
And then actually we'll just do that for now and then we'll say Daut box and 1 and then for this one
we'll do call S-5 and we'll save box 2 and save.
So we're looking at this bottom one here.
Now if I wanted to just switch these but not change the markup around what I could do is just add a
class of push and then say I want S-5 on this one.
And then this will save push and we'll do seven and save.
I'm sorry.
Paul has seven.
So he should have Push and Pull.
And now they're reversed.
So now to actually has is on this side and the one is on this side.
So this one gets pushed into the S-5 this one gets pushed into the seven all I should say pulled into
the seven.
OK another thing that will we'll deal with is offsets.
So if you don't want to take up all 12 like let's say you only want a six column div but you want to
move it into the middle and this is used often for like log and page.
So what we would do is create a row and we would create our column and let's say six.
And then what we'll do is we'll say offset and let's say offset 3.
OK.
And here we'll just put our box and we'll just we'll say log in and save and then we go.
So what happens is we have a six column div.
But we pushed it over or we offset it by three columns.
All right.
If I offset it by four then it's going to get pushed over a little more.
OK if I offset it by six it's going to go all the way to the other side.
OK.
But a lot of times if you're doing a log and you'll do like you'll make it right in the middle.
All right.
So I think that's going to be the guys we're going to be using the grid system a lot not just in the
projects but even in later sandbox lectures.
So this is something that we're going to kind of drill into your head as we go through the course.
All right thanks for watching and I will see.