It it's going on guys welcome to YOUR NEXT PROJECT.
This project called Chua's zoo.
I'm not really sure where I got that name.
I think it was from some kind of fake word generator but basically this is going to be like a cloud
a welcome page or a welcome sight for a cloud hosting platform.
And I got the idea for this from Heroku I even got the color scheme the purplish color scheme idea from
them.
So we basically just have a nav bar and noticed that it's transparent.
It's actually part of the Showcase area here or the hero whatever you want to call this.
So even now we have a couple of links.
It's going to be a multi-page site.
We have three pages and then we have this logon button which if I click it opens up a modal that has
an email address and a password input with a couple of buttons.
OK we are going to be using font awesome in this project as well because we have some social icons up
here.
OK we have this area with some icon boxes the About Us area with a circular image.
We have these two these two areas which have an overlay so it's basically an image with a purple overlay
which will do through some custom CSSA.
We have some icons for different programming languages.
We're using a slider for the carousel here for testimonials.
So I have a couple of different testimonials.
And then just a simple footer with some links and the about us.
So that's that page then we have our solutions page where we just have a shorter version of the Showcase
area.
We have some tabs here for different services and then we have a bunch of different features here with
icons.
I'm pretty sure these are material icons.
I could be wrong though they could be font.
Awesome.
And then we have a button and text and then the footer and then for the sign up page we just have 2
6 column divs one has some headings and text and then on this side we have a form with the name and
email password.
And then we have a select list where we can select a roll and then just assign a button.
All right so that's what rebuilding guys I think it looks pretty nice pretty clean.
Hopefully you enjoy it.
Let's actually take a real quick look at the responsive version so you can see everything is stacked
on we have this little podcast.
It's an area as well but that looks good.
And if we look at the solutions page and everything looks good and if we look at sign up that looks
good as well.
All right so let's go ahead and get started building the core zoo theme in material Lysias as.