All right let's get started on the KwaZulu theme so we're going to create a new folder for our project
and create it on my desktop and I'm going to call it KwaZulu and same thing we did with the travel Velle
we're going to grab from the theme starter.
So going to open that up and I'm just going to grab everything in there and just copy it and then just
bring it over to our folder here.
OK.
And then we're going to open this folder with vs code OK so I'm not going to go through the files because
we already did that in the last project.
Just very simple stuff.
Let's open up the index each team now and we are going to need font Awesome again because we're using
social icons and material icons does not provide those at least yet.
So it's open up our browser.
And let's go to fun.
Awesome.
And we'll go to get started.
And we just want to grab our script tag right here for our SVGA icons and I'll go ahead and put those
right under the materialize icons.
OK.
Now we're going to go down and go into the body here.
Get rid of our each one.
And this is going to be the header and it's going to include the nav bar.
So let's create Let's use a header tag and we use the class of main header.
OK because you may have multiple headers in on a Web site you may have an article header and use this
tag so it's a good idea to give it a special class or ID.
OK now inside here we're going to have our Nav. and we're going to give it a class of transparent which
does just that makes it transparent.
Inside here it's give are now a container.
Let's do our NAV wrapper so you'll see some repetitiveness here but I really don't want to do copying
and pasting.
I think it's better to kind of repeat yourself and drill it into your brain so that when you do have
to create a nav bar you don't have to keep going back to either the sandbox or the documentation.
You can just go ahead and create it.
All right so now we need our brand logo.
So in here we'll give it the name which is KwaZulu And now we want our mobile now button or link.
So it's going to be in a tag with the class of button Dasch collapse.
And remember it has to have a special attribute of data activates.
And we're going to call it mobile now.
Just like we did in the last project and for the icon here I'm actually going to use a font.
Awesome icons so I'm going to say I dot FAA and then also a class of FAA dash bars which is the same
basically the same icon as the menu in the materialize icons.
OK under the tag here we are going to put our menu.
Are you well which is going to have a class of rights.
And we're also going to do hide on medium and down and we'll try our links.
So see this one is going to be our home link.
So it's two and a tag and it's going to go to indexed all aged him now.
We're actually doing separate pages here.
We're not doing like a single landing page with hash tags.
So that will go to index each tomorrow.
And then what I'll do is copy this down two more times.
So this one will be the solutions and it's actually going to go to a page called solutions Daut each
DML.
And then this one is going to be the sign up that will go to sign up each team that all
and then I'm going to put another ally on me just save and format.
So it's put another ally.
And inside here I'll put another a tag but this is going to have it's going to be a button so I'm going
to give a class of between and also a class of purple
K and then this is going to be our log button which will open a motel but we're not going to do that
just yet we close up.
OK so now what we want to do is we want our social media link.
So again we're going to put some more list items here so this will go to we'll just have a go to Facebook
and then inside the ATAC.
We want the icon for Facebook which is FHB and then F.A. dash Facebook.
OK so we'll do the same thing for let's do Twitter and Instagram.
So I'm just going to copy these down to more so this will be Twitter
and then this one
will be Instagram.
All right.
And let's save that.
Let's take a look.
So I'm going to just open with live server.
All right now it's transparent so we can't see anything because we don't have our background image.
So you can get the image from the project files.
What I'm going to do is just open my folder up so it's the desk top KwaZulu images and I'm going to
bring the image over.
Give me a second here.
All right.
So this is actually going to be quite a few images.
What I would suggest is grabbing them all from the project files now and getting it over with.
So that's what I'm going to do.
I'm going to paste them all in.
And if we take a look.
So this is the main background right here for the showcase but then we have all the programming language
logos the about Logo.
These two which are for the overlays.
So you want all these images.
All right now it's still not going to show because we didn't add any CSSA to show the image in the background.
So let's let's go ahead and finish our now Wajir first and then we'll do that.
All right so that these are the main links.
Now under this well we want to have the UL for our side nav.
So let's go ahead and do that.
We'll say well class of side nav.
And we need to give this an ID which should match the data activates which we gave mobile nav and I'm
also going to put an H for in here with.
So should have put a class in I'm going to do purple text and I'm going to do text Darkon for.
OK.
And let's also Center it and then it's just going to have the template name or the the website name
which is KwaZulu like that.
All right.
And then under that I'm going to put in ally which is going to have a divider which is just kind of
like a line across so it's going to be a div with the class of divider like that.
All right.
And then we'll go ahead and put in our main links which are these three Salone to copy home solutions
and sign up and put those right under the divider.
Except they're going to use icons here as well so inside the tag here I'll put an eye tag with the class
of F.A. and the class of F.A. dash home UPS dash home that in let's see let's change the color let's
say gray text and let's say text Darkon for the icon.
And then I'm going to copy that I tag put it in here hand in here and we're going to change the solutions
icon to F.A. dash KOG and then the last one will be F.A. dash users
OK.
Then we're going to have another divider.
So why would the classic divider.
And then finally we're going to have a logon button here as well so it will be inside of an ally and
a tag with the classes and also the class of purple.
And we're going to say log in
all right let's save that and now it will do is go.
Let's see.
Let's go to our main CSSA file so that we can get that background image showing.
So remember our header has a class of main Hetter
and we're going to give that background you are l of I m g.
Actually it's good to be dot dot slash.
I m g because we need to go outside of the CSSA folder and then it's going to be what did I call that
actually.
Background So background dog J pack.
OK.
Now the hetter I'm going to set.
Let's actually set some other background properties so background size I want the image to cover and
then for the position background position I want it to be centered.
OK.
And then we're going to give this some men height
we're going to do a min height of 600 pixels for the header and let's make sure that the color is white
and save.
And there we go.
So looks pretty good.
So we might as well do the content within the header.
So where we want to go is right under the Nav. but still within the header.
And actually we'll say showcase here and we're going to do a class of showcase and let's also do a class
of container because we want to we want to contain everything with inside and we'll do a row.
It's going to be a full 12 column row so we'll just call as 12
actually know what.
On medium screens I want it to be 10.
I don't want it to reach all the way across.
So we're going to do m 10 but we will also want to offset it by one because we want it to be in the
middle.
So we'll say offset dash and 1.
OK.
And then we just want to center everything and then inside here we'll put in h 5 and we'll say welcome
to cause do.
And then we're going to have an H one and we're going to say build for the future and then just a paragraph
of dummy text so do.
Let's see will do Warum 15.
OK and then we're going to have a couple line breaks.
Those couple line breaks and then let's do a couple lengths formatted as buttons.
So this is going to have a class of between DTN large.
We're also going to do white and let's do purple text.
OK.
And then this is going to go to the solutions dot h team l page and the text for this is just going
to say learn more.
All right now we're going to do is copy this link.
We're going to have another one next to it which is going to go to the sign up page.
So sign up each team now.
And we're going to change the color to purple and change the text to white.
So white text and we'll change the actual text to sign up.
All right so let's save that case.
That looks pretty good.
Let's see I want to move it down let's go to our main CSSA file and let's say main header and we want
to attach the showcase.
And we want to add a padding talk of 110 pixels and save and that'll move it down.
All right and I think I think that should do it.
One other thing I want to do is have an active link.
The active class isn't going to show all of the transparent nav bar.
So what we'll do is any link that's active.
So this index right here I'm going to give this a class of active dash
link like that.
And then we're going to style it ourselves so we'll go back and let's say Daut active link and I'm just
going to give it a color of that like pinkish purple ish color so it's going to be a hex value of d
8 for 7 for 1.
And we're also going to make the font weight.
Bold
and save.
And now you see that the home has that pinkish purplish color.
All right so I think that's a pretty good start.
And the next video we're going to continue on with the icon boxes and then we'll go from there.