All right.
So the last video we created our transparent nav bar and the background here in the header.
The are the header with the background image.
Now we're going to go underneath the header and we're going to put in our icon boxes so let's say Section
icon boxes and we're going to do a section with the class of section and then a custom class of Section
icons.
So this should look pretty familiar.
We see a lot of Web sites with this with the three of four icon boxes because it looks really nice and
clean.
And it also allows you to specify features or whatever you want to convey to the viewer.
So let's do a row.
And we're going to have three four call them medium Rose arke or columns I should say or does so say
call s 12 and then medium 4.
And we also want to center actually we'll do the center up above.
I will put the center here like that.
All right.
And inside here let's do a card panel
and I'm going to put an icon.
So when you find awesome I'm going to do I diet F.A..
So class of F.A. and then a class of F.A. dash user and then we're going to do three times we want to
make this beggar so F.A. dash 3 X will make it bigger.
We're also going to give them a color of deep Dasch purple and then I'm sorry Deep Purple Tex.
Since it's an icon.
And then let's also do text Darkon dash to a very specific color.
OK so that's our icon and if I save it you'll see it here.
So underneath that icon I'm going to put an age 5 and I'm going to give it a class of grey text and
I'm going to do a text Darkon let's do Tex Darkon for and let's say free account.
OK.
Sorry.
Five.
And then our paragraph will just be ten dummy text words.
So if I save that it should look like that.
OK so now what we'll do is copy the column which is this right here this div.
So we want to grab that and we're just going to bring that down two more times.
And the second one here we're going to change the icon see the icon from the user to the database and
then the h 5 We're going to say no and skewl databases.
And then this last one here we're going to change the icon to F.A. dash bolt and we're going to change
the h 5 to fast connections.
OK so save that and there we go.
So pretty easy.
Now underneath that we're going to have our boat section.
So let's go and put a comment here you don't have to do all the comments but I figure that it helps
out people.
So you know exactly what goes where.
So let's say S.S.
and then we'll do us.
Class of S. about.
All right.
I also want to add a class of great to give it a great background.
And then let's do Leitung dash for OK.
So that way it's a different color than the white here.
So it doesn't look like one big section you can actually tell the difference.
All right.
Let's do a container.
And inside the container will put a row and then we're going to have basically two six call them divs
on medium screens and up so call as 12 and 6 on this side.
We're going to have basically some text.
So I'm going to have an H three.
We're going to say about us but for the of the word about I'm actually going to make it purple's so
I'm going to put a span with the class of let's do deep dash purple dash text and we'll do text Darkon
dash 1.
All right so that span and then that ending span needs to go on the other side of the bow like that.
So about us.
And then underneath that will put a paragraph with the class of flow text and let's do Warum 20.
So have 20 words.
And then we get another call them after this one.
So this column right here ends at this div..
So we want to go underneath and do another column as 12 and 6 and then our image will go here so it
will be an image and it's going to be in our image folder.
And it's called takk.
Jay peg and then I also want to add a class of circle and also responsive dash I am Jizo so it stays
in its container so let's save that and take a look.
And there we go there are about S..
So next we're going to do the four developers by developers section and it will have a background image
with a purple overlay.
All right.
So let's do section
developers and we'll say Section Daut section actually you know what I don't want to add.
Oh wait.
Never mind.
Forget I said that we're going to do section Dasch developers.
That's our custom class and I wanted to have Whyte's text.
Ok so in here we're going to actually do our overlay so we're going to have a class called primary dash
overlay and if he took my bootstrap course with five projects you might see some similarities with that
stuff.
We did the same kind of overlays.
We wanted to do the overlay we want to do text white or actually no we don't need to do that
but you know let's align it to the middle vertically so we can use a class called V a line dash wrapper.
All right.
And then here we'll put our container in the container we'll put our row in the row we'll put our column.
So call as 12.
And also let's actually let's just leave as 12 and then do Center.
OK because it's going to go all the way across no matter what the screen size.
And then it's simply going to be an H-3 that says for developers
by developers I don't really know what that means but it sounds cool.
So it's save.
And if we look it's just all white right now we need to add our overlay in our background image so we're
going to do that within the sea.
SS Let's first do the image so we want section developers and we're going to position this relative
because the overlay is going to be positioned absolute and absolute positioned element needs to be inside
a relative element.
Okay.
And then what's the background to you are l want to go dot dot slash into the images folder and then
we want the the image called Code dot J Pag.
All right.
We're also going to add the background size which will be cover and then we're going to add the background
position.
Which will be center.
And let's also do a border top came just do a dark gray border talk of solid and five pixels just to
kind of separate it and then let's also do a border bottom so I'm just going to copy that down and change
that to border bottom and then the last thing I want to do is just add a minimum height of 180 pixels.
All right so that's our developers.
Let's save that.
And now you can see we have the text over the image but you can't really see the tax because the image
is so prominent.
So that's why the overlay comes in.
So now we're going to do is the primary overlay and I'm going to put that up at the top because it's
kind of a general class we're going to use in other places.
So they overlay.
All right.
And then for this we're going to add a background now when you want to have a background color with
an opacity meaning having it be transparent.
You want to use our G.P.A..
So red green blue Alpha which is an opacity level basically.
So we're going to say 112 by 81 by 176.
That's the color.
And then for the opacity I'm going to do 0.7 by default.
Ok then we want to do a position absolute
and then we want to say start at the top 0 and the left 0.
OK so basically start in the corner and then we're going to give it a width of 100 percent so it covers
the entire thing at least widthwise and then do the same height y.
So 100 percent as well.
And then we want overflow.
Hidden because we don't want any scroll bars or anything showing up.
So save that and now you can see we have a an overlay purple overlay.
So the last thing I want to do in this video is the languages area where we have all the different logos
so let's add that
so we'll call this section languages and or let us use language.
And then let's give it a gray background but let's light it so we'll do lighting for.
OK and then we'll do a container.
This should be a pretty easy one.
We'll do a row.
And let's see we're going to do an H for here and we'll say work
with will say work with and then we'll do a stand with the class of deep purple Dasch text.
Let's also text Darkon one and then and here we'll say any language.
OK so work with any language
let's also Center
and then we'll go under that age for let's put a couple line breaks and then we're going to put a row.
And basically we want to call them rose.
OK.
So sue because we're going to have six icons.
So it's a 12 column Gred So we want to each for the 6.
So Klatt Div. of call as 2.
And then let's put an image in here.
This first one will be python so will do image slash Python dash logo dot PNB.
OK.
We also want to give these classes of responsive Dasch I m g.
And then what I'll do is copy that column.
That's one two three four five six and then we'll just go in and change this one to Ruby.
We'll change this one to PH P then we'll do node
one C Sharp C dash sharp and then Java.
Let's save it and take a look and then we go work with any language and we shouldn't have to edit anything
in the CSSA for that part.
So that looks good.
All right so in the next video we're going to move on to the other overlay section the podcast section
and then we'll do the carousel slider and hopefully we can finish up the home page in the next video.