All right guys so hopefully we can finish up the home page and this.
In this video here so the last thing we did was this part here this work with any language and we have
all the little icons for the languages so we're going to go under that section and we're going to create
our podcast section.
So let's do a section tagging.
Do you guys know the deal so we'll give it a custom class section podcast.
OK let's also give it white text.
So the reason that I'm not giving it a purple background through materializes because that's going to
come from our overlay.
OK just like we did up here we want to create an overlay so we can actually copy what we'll do is just
copy everything here inside the developers section and paste that in because we do want the overlay
in the wrapper.
We want that container.
We want a row.
Except we're not going to do one one full round we're going to do an eight column on medium screens
and in a four column on medium screen.
So let's do right here am eight and let's get rid of the center so we get em a.
And then we'll go under here and we'll do call as 12 am for right.
On this in the 8 side we're going to have an H for.
And we'll change this to listen to
the cause zoo podcast and then we'll put a paragraph underneath that and we'll say every
Thursday at let's say 5:00 p.m. Eastern Time.
All right.
And then in this side on this side the four call them we're just going to have a link formatted as a
button so we'll do between.
And we also want it to be purple and we're going to want it to be large so beat and dash like I can't
type.
And that's just going to go nowhere.
And then inside the tag we're going to have an icon font.
Awesome So it's going to be FAA.
And then also a dash is actually in an icon called podcasts.
We're going to use that and then we're just going to say listen.
And that should do it.
So let's save Take a look.
OK now actually one second here.
So we have some CSSA to add.
First let's go to our means.
SS In C I feel like I'm missing something here.
So section podcast.
We have our primary overlay
we have our row we have our medium a medium for columns
the overlay is way up here.
Oh you know why because our section podcast isn't position relative.
So what's happening is the overlay is looking at the whatever the parent relative element is which is
basically the the the root element.
So it's up here.
So all we have to do is go in here and say Section
podcast you know we want to set me in that position to relatives and save.
And now that's down here why this is so small.
All we get to put the image and stuff.
Never mind.
Got a little confused for a second there so let's do our background because we did it the other way
around before.
Background is going to be you are all it's going to be in the image folder and it's going to be called
it's circuit.
So circuit J peg.
And then let's do a background size of cover in a background position center
and let's do border talk.
I'll just copy this we're going to do the same thing we did here
then under that we'll do a minimum height of 180.
All right let's save that.
And there we go.
But you know I don't want this.
This is too light.
I think this is good.
The overlay for this image because it's a darker image but this is too light.
So what we'll do is we'll just say S. pod cast and then we'll take the primary overlay that's in that.
And let's set it to background
R-Ga. and we want the same color we want the one 12.
What is it 81.
176 what we're going to change the alpha value to zero point nine and save and that makes it darker.
Let's see what else we want to do here.
Let's not change the minimum height because they look a little too big.
Yeah there we go.
Maybe even 160.
Yeah that's good.
And then let's check the responsiveness.
OK so looks like we have an issue here.
All right.
So we're going to change the men high on small screens for both the podcast and the developers section.
So let's go down here and do a media query
so we're going to say Max with five hundred pixels is five hundred pixels that should be at media.
And then we'll take the section developers and section podcast and we'll set the men right to say 240
pixels and save.
And there we go.
I think that looks pretty good.
Yeah that looks good.
You know what I want to move that button down a little though.
See this button right here.
So we could do to see if we could do section hard cast pod cast
S. pod cast whips and then we want to just add
a.
And let's do a margin top 30 pixels.
OK so now that pushes that down.
Good.
I think that's fine.
I mean if you want in the media where you can take the margin off if you don't want that space there.
But I think that's fine.
All right so now we're going to move on to the testimonial and the testimonials actually a carrousel.
This section
testimony you know
you know let's do Dougray and let's do Leitung dash 4.
All right so in here we'll have our container or have our row we'll have a call at 12:00 and then we
want our Carrousel.
So a class of carrousel We're also going to do carrousel slider number there were two types of carrousel
one was like kind of like the I guess the apple type where it has you can see all the images and it
kind of you can kind of scroll through them or the slider which shows like one image at a time or it
doesn't have to be an image but any content area.
So we want contents carousel slide or we also want to center everything.
All right.
And then in here we want our carrousel items.
So this will be carrousel dash item in
div carrousel item and then we want to give this in a trough which is going to give an ATF of hash one
exclamation.
And inside here we'll put in each two we're going to say testimonial
testimony or one.
Let's give it a paragraph with flow text and then let's do we'll put some quotes in then we'll do
Florham 30 tap like that
OK.
And let's see underneath the paragraph let's put in some emphasis tags and we'll say John Doe from
Microsystems and then underneath actually you know what this AM.
This emphasis I want this in the paragraph.
So great here and then outside of the paragraph we're going to put a class of carrousel dash fixed item
center.
And then I'm also going to hide on small and down.
So hide on
small and down K because it looks weird on small screen.
This is just going to be the button or the link so it'll be a link formatted as a button and we'll make
it gray and we'll just say read more.
All right.
So there's our carrousel item.
Now what I'll do is copy that carrousel item div.
So I'll take that and we'll do two more.
OK the second one here.
Let's change this to two and let's change this to testimonial to we'll change the name to say Mike Smith
from.
I don't know.
Edge ink.
And then the last one here will change this to three and we'll change it to testimonial 3 and then let's
change the person here to Karen
Williams from let's say teks soft.
OK so let's let's save that.
Now it's not going to show up just yet because we need to initialize it.
So we're going to go down to the bottom here and let's go ahead
and let's say keras.
It also had a class of carrousel dash slider.
And we just want to call DOT carrousel but we want to pass in an option of full width and set that to
true.
So it goes across the whole thing.
Let's also initialize our sidebar while we're here we didn't do that.
So we want our button collapse
wups button collapse side now.
Sorry.
And there's our testimonial and we can scroll through them now.
Cool.
And let's test out the side now.
Awesome.
So these are links with the icons in the log and that looks pretty good.
Now all we have to do after the testimonial is the Forder But we also have to do the log in modal.
I want them when I cooked this log in but I want to motile to open.
So I think that I'm going to save that for the next video we'll throw the footer in and then we'll go
ahead and we'll do that motile.