All right guys so we're going to get to the flooder and the log in motile But there's one couple of
things they want to do first with this testimonial one.
The name should be on its own paragraph should be on its own line.
So where I have the emphasis right here we want to wrap this in a paragraph
Okay so we just want to go through that for each of these.
So also be paragraph
and this one as well.
OK so that's on a separate line.
And then I also want to make the font bigger so I'm going to go to my CSSA and I'm going to say carrousel
dash item
paragraph and let's say font size
20 pick 20 pixels important and save.
And there we go.
So that looks better.
All right so now for the faulter
I'm actually using the same footer that is in the documentation so we could also use the sandbox if
we wanted to.
But just to be real quick let's go to footer and I want the same set basically the same thing here just
different colors so I'm going to copy this whole thing and paste it in and then we're going to change
up a couple things so the for the actual for tagging going to deep deep purple as the color.
And then we'll say liten Dash 1 and then this part down here where it says photocopy right.
We're going to use Deep Purple and we're going to use dark and Dash 1.
OK.
And then we'll change this h five to about us and I don't really want to use this tax.
I'm just going to put in my own sample tax.
We'll do larm 20 maybe a couple us and then for the links let's make these into actual length so do
home.
So so go to index dot each team.
This one will be for solutions
and then this one will be for sign up
and then we don't need this last one OK and then down here we'll say
KwaZulu
copyrights.
Copy
2018.
And then instead of more links we'll say Terms and Conditions and save it take a look at it and here's
our footer.
All right so that's done now we're going to do the log in motile.
So for a link to be a log in moto there's two things we need to do to it.
So let's go to that part right there which is this one we need to add a special class called motile
trigger.
OK.
And then we also need to have an age BRAF which we do but we need to change that value to go to the
idea of the modal which will be loggin dash mode.
OK so now we can go in we can create that.
So let's go down to the bottom I like to put any modals we have at the very bottom.
So let's say log modal
so this is going to be a div with the ID of log and.
And the class of modal and then inside here we will have the modal content
class will have an H for say a count log in paragraph log in to access your count dashboard and then
will have a simple form.
We don't need an action in this form we're going to have an input field and we're going to have an inputs.
It's going to have any type of e-mail.
And let's give it an idea of email and then we'll have a label for e-mail.
OK and then I'm just going to just copy that.
Copy that down and then this is going to be the password.
So type will be password ID.
OK.
And then we want a modal Fortner which is going to go under this div..
OK this is the modal content div we're going to go under that Indu modal dash for her.
And in here we'll have an eight tag and let's give this a class of modal dash action.
Also motile dash close so that when we click it it actually closes and let's do DTN and let's do gour
and then further text.
This is going to say reset password.
It's not actually going to do anything we're just putting that in we're actually going to put an icon
in here as well.
So right next to the text puts to dot FAA DOT FAA dash sync.
So put that icon there and then what I'll do is copy this a tag you're going to have another one except
this one is going to be purple
and this one is going to say log in and it's going to have an icon of a lock.
So it's going to be F.A. dash lock.
So it's safe.
Let's try it out log in.
It's not working because we need to initialize it so we need to use Jey query and just for the modal
class we need to call Daut modal.
OK and this should actually be in quotes and save.
And now click.
And there we go.
Can't log in.
So it's actually going to do anything but it has we have the UI.
So our home page is now complete in the next video we're going to start on the solutions page.