All right.
So we finish up the home page now we're going to do the solutions page which is going to be pretty easy.
We are going to use this showcase like we did here but it's going to be kind of cut in half.
It's not going to go down as far and I'll show you how we do that.
So let's copy every single thing on the index page so we're just going to do a select all and then copy
everything.
And then we're going to just create a new file called solutions start each team and then we're going
to paste everything in that file and then we're going to go through and just take some stuff out.
One thing I forgot to do is change the title.
So even on the index page I'm going to go on I'm going to change this to let's say cause you
say cloud hosting and we'll do the same thing here.
OK.
So
what I'm going to do is for the header I'm going to change the class from main header to main header.
Enter because it's going to have some different styling.
Well as far as the rest goes the navigation that's all going to stay the same the side nav that's going
to stay the same.
And then for the showcase that's actually going to be much simpler.
We're going to get rid of the two buttons here are the two links the line breaks.
We're going to get rid of the paragraph all we're going to need is the h 5 and the h one.
So we'll leave.
Welcome to cause Xu and then this will just be the page name so we'll say cloud solutions.
Okay.
And then we can get rid of basically everything as far as the sections the boxes the developers the
language the podcast The testimonial everything up until the Forder we want the water.
So I'll save that and then let's go up here and click on solutions and it's going to look like this.
So let's go to our CSX and let's do the main Hetter inner which will be very similar so I'm just going
to copy this.
We'll go right here and paste it in and change it to main header it's main header.
In her case same background image everything is the same just the minimum height is going to be three
fifty.
So let's try that.
OK.
So it's good to showcase.
I'm going to copy this line right here.
And then we're going to say main Hetter in our showcase instead of 100 pixels padding we want 50 pixels.
So pushes it down like that.
OK so we basically have like a page title in the header so now we want to do our solutions about S..
So let's go to solutions HDMI and go under the header.
So B.S. now I'm calling this Dasch solutions slash about because we already have a section about on
the home page and I don't want to mix class names up or have double class names so we have a container
and we're going to do a row.
Right now this row is going to have two columns to call as 12 and then I'm going to do an EM 5.
OK so in here we're going to put in H2 and we're going to say what we do.
And then under that will put a paragraph in I'm going to do Laura I'm 30 K 30 text and then under this
column we'll have another.
And this one's going to be s 12 and it's going to be 6.
Now you may notice that we have 5 here and then am 6 while I'm doing this because I want this one to
be pushed over a little bit.
So we're going to add an offset.
So offset dash and one like that.
OK.
And then and here we're actually going to have our tabs.
You have a little tab services thing.
So if we go to our documentation and go to javascript tabs or you can go to the sandbox that we created
and just grab this
and paste that in what we'll do here.
Is let's change let's see instead of test 1 let's do cloud hosting.
And we'll change this to tab 1.
I don't like Test 1
I don't want this active either.
So this one will be tab two.
And then this text here will be cloud storage.
This one I don't want disabled.
It's going to be Tab 3.
And then for the text we're going to say cloud database and then we don't need a fourth one.
All right.
And then down here we'll get rid of the fourth one and we'll change these ideas up so this will be tab
one tab to tab three
and we're going to put some more content in here so let's let's put in age five.
And this is going to be cloud hosting.
Paragraphing will do Lorem 20.
All right.
And then this one here.
Let's do an H5 and let's say cloud storage
paragraph and again Lorem 30 and then this one.
Sure you guys know we're going to do cloud database paragraph form 30.
All right so if we save that.
Let's go to our solutions then.
So looks like that's getting truncated.
And you know what is happening is that we have threes but we only have three three of these so these
should actually be asked for.
Because remember there were four of them we got rid of one.
So we want this because four times three is 12.
So let's save that.
And there we go.
All right now I want to change the color of these tabs.
That took me a while to figure out.
But there's actually some CSSA we can override to do that.
So we want to use to dot tabs and we want to do Daut
indicator and then we're going to change the background color which seems a little weird but that's
what we need to do to a hex value of 6 a 1 b 9.
Which is a purple color and we want to put important and save.
OK.
So that change the actual underline here so we can change the text inside here if we go to the tab right
here.
ATAC great here we're going to have a class of purple dasht text.
All right so changing the text isn't isn't hard but it took me a while to figure out how to do the underline.
So save that and now we have all purple text.
All right.
So next we're going to do the features.
So we're going to go under everything under this section here and we're going to say section features
so section features let's make it work give it a gray background and lighten it a little bit.
So like three
to our container.
Let's do some text.
We're going to do an H for.
It's going to be purple
text and letters to text dark in Dash 1 and center wups should read dot center and then we're going
to say powerful and innovative.
OK then under that I'm going to put an H 6 with the class of grey dash text.
And let's do text Darkon too.
And let's also line into the center and then I'm going to do Lorem 10 for that.
OK.
And then underneath the age 6 I'm just going to put a couple line breaks
just to move things down.
And then we're going to have a couple of different rows so let's save that.
OK so looks good.
Now we're going to a couple rows of icons.
This is going to be icons with text.
So let's do row.
We can actually label these Let's do row 1.
So it's going to be c call as 12.
And then medium sized screens will be for column devs and then will have an H 5 and in that age 5 We're
going to have an icon.
So it's true I dot FAA DOT FAA dash user and next to that I can say unlimited users.
OK.
So that's our age 5.
Now under the age five you're going to have a paragraph I forget exactly how long I did try 20.
I think that should do it.
So if we see what that looks like.
Good.
So now we want since this is a four column div on medium screens and up we want three of these in each
row so I'm going to copy the column div.
So this right here two more times in this row.
OK.
The second one we're going to say scaleable data and we're going to use the FAA database icon here.
All right this last one here is going to be F.A. dash sharp dash line.
And then for the text for the text we're going to do data analytics save that.
Good.
Now what I'll do is copy the entire row.
So right from this comment actually this div ends where right here.
So we'll go ahead and copy all that
paste in there.
So this is going to be road to now and then Road to.
This is going to be good hub F.A. get hub and the feature is going to be a good hub integration.
And then underneath that we're going to do an FAA plus icon and we're going to say add ons
and then this one this icon here is going to be an FAA HDD hard drive and it's going to this is going
to be smart.
Storage
OK.
Actually do we only do two.
Yeah that's that's good.
We don't have three rows.
All right so let's see under that
see that row ends here and in
we're going to go right here and we're going to put a div with the class of center.
And I just want to put a link here to the Sign-Up page this is going to have a class of beat and and
then Beati and dash large to make it bigger.
And we're going to make it gray and it's going to go to sign up daughter aged him now and then for the
text for the link.
We're going to just say sign up for free.
OK let's see what that looks like.
Good.
And then we're just going to put a little bit of text under it.
So under the age tag let's do a couple of line breaks and then we're going to put an h 5.
And in this age five will do a span with the class of deep purple text and let's do text Litan Dash
1 case that to lighten it up a bit and we'll just say have a question and then we'll go outside of the
span and we'll say contact our sales team and then under the H5 we'll put a paragraph with the sales
team a email address so will say sales will say sales at KwaZulu theme dog test which obviously isn't
a real email address so it's save it.
And there we go.
All right so that is our solutions page.
We have a little tab thing here.
Services all the features sign up which doesn't exist yet but that's it.
All right so in the next video we're going we're going to work on the sign up page.