Hey Guys welcome to your last project in this project we're going to build a graphic design portfolio.
It's a pretty simple site but we're going to do something different.
We're going to be using SAS.
OK if we go to the materialize get started right here.
You'll see that we have the regular source which we've been using.
And we also have the SAS files or SPSS files that we can use and we can actually change up different
variables like let's say the standard.
I don't know that the card shadow or something like that.
You can you can manipulate that and change it to your liking.
So I want to show you how to implement SAS and also how to create some variables where we can change
like the background color and stuff really easily.
All right.
Now we'll also be using scroll fire to have a fade in effect on scroll.
So notice that we see one project here if I scroll down a little.
Another one will appear.
Keep scrolling.
Another one will appear so a lot of people asked me how to get that effect and they don't realize that
it's built in with materialize with scroll fire.
All right.
Now for each project we have a card we have some star ratings and we have the little button here and
this will actually open a motel with that image inside.
OK with some text and the title and the star rating.
And we have different pages this is abstract.
We also have logos which is basically the same thing it's just different images.
And then we have gaming which again is the same thing different images.
And we have our Sidebar over here and if we were to make this smaller.
What I did is I hid the text on a very small mobile size screens.
See the text there disappears and we just see the image and we can open up the motile and that looks
good.
OK so everything looks pretty nice.
It's very simple.
But again I wanted to do something different and use SAS.
So in the next video what we'll do is get everything set up we're going to talk a little bit more about
SAS and we're going to install a program called Koala because we need our SAS to get compiled down to
regular CSSA.
And that's what we're going to use so we want to install that and get that set up.
All right so I'll see you in the next video.