All right guys who are going to go ahead and get set up here.
But before we do I just wanted to talk a little bit about sace.
We're not going to this isn't a SAS course.
I just want to show you how to use it with materialized and all we're really going to be using is variables
in maybe a little bit investing a mix in we're going to create a mix in which is like a function but
you know if we want to create a variable we can use a money sign and then just name the variable and
we can set it to like a color or a font style anything in CSX.
And then we can simply use it wherever we want.
OK so any selector and a style we can use the variable and we can nest styles so you can see where they're
putting a UL and ally and and a tag within the nav tag.
So only these only the UL ally and tags that are inside a nav tag will be affected by these styles.
OK we can use Parshall's which are just separate C-s as CSSA files we can import them.
We can use mix ins which are like functions they can take in parameters and so on we can extend styles
or extend classes.
So it's really it's really cool.
We also have operators so we can have like dynamic functionality we can do conditionals things like
that but I'm not going to get too far into it.
I just want to show you how to get it set up and use it in a project now in order to use SAS the browser
doesn't actually read SAS or SPSS files it has to be compiled to CSSA to regular CSSA.
And we're going to use a program called Koala for that which is a GUI program it's a graphical program.
A lot of times you'll see people use command line programs from NPM and stuff but I don't want to get
into that I don't want to get too deep into it into the command line or I shouldn't say too deep I don't
want to get into it at all in this course because I'll tell you in my bootstrap course we used NPM we
used Gaulke to compile SAS and a kind of Olvir took the course all of the Q&amp;A questions if you go into
that course it's all about NPM and gulp and not bootstrap.
So I chose a different route with this course and chose not to do any of that because it just it just
distracted everybody from actual bootstrap.
All right.
So we're going to use a simple GUI program.
So let's go ahead and download this and install it.
So it's going it's going to download and basically all we do is at our project we can click the plus
sign at the project and we choose where we want to output our regular CSSA we choose this SPSS file
which is our SAS file and then where we want to output the standard VSS.
OK we also want to go to materialize and download the source for the SAS package.
So we're going to grab that as well while that's downloading.
Let's open up the koala's set up and depending on what's operating as operating system you're on it
may be a little different.
On Windows we're just going to go through this real quick.
Just click next.
I already had it installed so it's telling me I already have the folder but I'll just click yes and
install.
OK so it actually is already installed but that's fine I'll just go through it again.
All right.
So that's all finished.
Now we can go ahead and start it up.
Keep that shack thing click Finish
and it's going to start up our program so we don't have any projects yet.
I'm just going to leave this open for now.
So now what we'll do is create a new folder for our project and we're going to call this Gallup here
and what we'll do is take from the theme starter.
Initially I was going to do with a theme starter for the SAS but I'll just show you how to implement
it with this theme starter.
So we're going to copy our files over
and let's open up Gallup here with this code right now.
What I'm going to do is create to open up our folder here.
We're going to create a new folder called SPSS.
OK this is where all of our SAS is going to go.
Now the SAS is those are the files that we edit if you want to change anything in your CSSA you edit
your SAS files and then the compiler will then compile it and put it into the CSSA folder as a regular
CSSA file.
Ok so in the SPSS folder we're going to create a new file called Main dot SPSS just like that.
And then we're also going to open up the materialize zip file that we just downloaded.
So it's close.
And what we want to do is go into the SAS folder and we want to take these and put them into our SPSS
folders so open up Cal appear here and go into SPSS and let's bring these to this folder and this file
over we'll look at those in a second.
And then that's really all we need.
We already have the fonts folder for the J.S. we don't need that we already have the J us so we have
that.
Now let's open up vs code again or go back to vs code and you'll see we have materialized on SPSS.
Now basically what this is is just a meeting place for all of the SPSS components.
Each aspect of materialized has its own SPSS file.
For instance the carousel has its own SPSS file with all the SAS and you can see it's using nesting
and all that stuff.
Badges and buttons and you can see there's there's variables and hair and all that stuff.
Now normally you don't want to change any of this what you what you can change or what you should change
is the the underscore variables file.
And this is where like the primary color is the primary color light primary color dark secondary color
you can change these values here and then we have things like the button height if you wanted to make
your standard button height bigger or smaller you could do that.
This is all button stuff this is all card stuff the carousel height default is 400 but you could change
that here.
You could change a lot of stuff from here.
So it's really to customize your materialize installation.
All right but we're not and we're not going to do too much here.
We're going to change up the colors a little bit and maybe a couple of other things.
All right.
Now what I want to do is now go to Kohala which is buried here and we're going to add a project and
we basically want to just choose our SAS folders so it's going to be in my desktop in the Gallup folder
and then I want to choose the SPSS folder and we're going to open that up.
So automatically it finds our SPSS files we have the main file and then materialize.
So what I am going to do here is right click and I'm going to say set output path for main dot SPSS
and I'm going to I'm going to set it to the CSSA folder to main Dotsie SS and save OK even though it
already exists.
I'm going to say yes.
And now that's going to compile to that file.
This one here that materialize.
I'm going to do the same thing I'm going to set the output path to the CSSA folder.
And set it to the materialized man Ghodsee SS and save that.
All right.
Now if I go back into the folder structure here if we go back into SPSS you'll see that it already compiled
to CSX before I did anything into the SPSS.
OK so we don't want the CSSA files in here we want them to go in here to these.
So what we can do is delete the main dot C Ss and also the sort.
This the source maps were not really going to get into that.
Any ways we can disable those too.
But we only want our SPSS files in here so let's delete that as well.
Let's delete this source wrap.
So we should only have these two SAS files and components.
All right and if we go to Kohala and we can actually uncheck source wrap for both of these.
OK and see how it's set to auto compile that means when we save anything in SAS it'll auto compile to
the CSSA files.
All right.
So let's go ahead and click compile
it auto compile anyways.
But now if I look in materialize men CSSA this all came from the materialized SAS file.
All right.
And this is the file we want to include in our index each team now which we already are anyways so we
don't have to change that.
We don't want to change any of this because we're using the same CSSA files.
It's just being compiled from our SAS.
All right.
So hopefully this isn't too confusing the set up once we get set up then it's basically just like every
other project except we can use variables and stuff.
OK.
So let's open this with our live server.
And I just want to try something here so if we go into our main SPSS file let's set a variable we'll
say let's say primary and we'll set that to read and then I just want to say body will say background.
This is just a test we'll say background and then we'll set it to the variable of primary and let's
save that
and that should actually get compiled automatically let's look at the main dot CSSA file.
Ok so it didn't and I think that's because I closed caller Yeah it's no longer open
qualis should be running in order for it to auto compile so just say resave this.
There we go.
OK so koala went ahead and compiled it.
Now if I look in my main DOS CSSA file it's just background read because a CSSA file can't have a variable
inside of it.
So now that's our workflow we work in the SAS files but it gets compiled to the CSX.
All right.
I'm just going to get rid of this and save and then that background will go away.
OK so now we're going to work just like we have been except we're going to use these SPSS files instead
of the CSX.
So in the next video we'll go ahead and we'll get started building our project in creating our markup.