All right guys.
Now we're going to create the gallery section or the gallery images.
So what we'll do is go under the header in the index page and let's say Section main and we'll say Section
class section and then we also give it section Dasch making.
All right so basically in here we're going to have a container and then we're going to have three rows.
So this is going to be row 1.
So let's say class row.
I'm also going to give it a class of row Dash 1 and then we're going to have to call them let's say
6.
So medium 6 in let's say hide on small dash only and the reason I'm putting this is because I don't
want this text to show on small screens.
So this is going to have a class of I Am G content OK it's going to be the content for the image which
will have the H-3 and I'm just using fake words here like Dila gourd for the for the name of the project
or whatever it is and then let's do Warum 20 and then we want to go let's see under this column that
we just created and we want to do another column 6.
And then this will be a card.
So say does class card it's going to have a card image class.
Inside here we'll have our actual image which is going to be in our I am g folder in the gallery folder
and it's going to be abstract.
One dot J Pag.
All right.
Let's see.
And then underneath the image will have a span.
And this is going to have a class of card title and will say Dila Goerge and then under that will have
an eight tag and this is going to be a floating button so we're going to do BT and dash floating.
Let's also do
Half-Way dash FHB which is going to allow it to basically be like in the middle of the image and the
content of the card.
So Half-Way fab will also do a wave's effect
and will do waves dash light.
Let's do red will make it a red button.
And it's also going to be a motile trigger.
So I'm just going to put that class for now as well.
So quite a few classes.
And then inside here we want an icon.
Whoops.
This is actually going to go to abstract one which will be a modal and inside the tag we're going to
have an icon
which will be the Add button.
The ADD icon.
All right.
And then underneath the card image which ends right here we're going to have the card contents
in the card content is going to have the star ratings.
OK so it's going to be the star icon so we're going to put a paragraph and then just have a bunch of
icons.
So not class Tiriel icons and is going to be a star and we're going to just copy this down.
We're going to do five of them.
So let's save that.
And it should look like that.
Now for the body text.
What I'm going to do is create what's called a mixin or actually you know we're going to use a function
a SAS function.
And I wanted to look at the background color and see how dark it is.
If it's dark enough then I want it to have white text if it's light then I wanted to have dark text.
So the way that we can do this is a go up here and it's a text color function.
And to make create a function we can say at function I'm going to call it set text color ok it's going
to take an
see it's going to take in a color
so we put a parameter and then we can do an if statement by saying at if
and we can use a method called lightness.
We're going to say if whiteness of the color that's passed in is greater than 50 then we want to return
the color black
OK else.
So I want to say at als that we want to return the color white OK.
Now we can go into our body and we can say we want the color to be set text color and then what you
pass in the background whatever is being used as the background color which in this case is the primary
color variable.
All right so if I save that now the text is white because this is dark enough to have white text the
whiteness is is it's less than 50.
If I were to go into my variables and change the the background color to white it's just too white and
save
I guess white isn't a valid option.
Now is not a color for Litan.
All right so let's do.
All right so it's two Teale but let's do Litan
Leitung four which would be really like.
And now you can see the text is dark.
OK so it's going to look at that background color and the text color will change depending on that which
I think is really powerful because then you can change the background color without having to worry
about the next color.
So let's put that back to dark and to save.
And now the text goes back to white.
All right.
Now let's add some more SS Actually before we do that let's add the rest of the content here.
So we're going to copy let's see for the second row let's just copy this whole row which ends here.
Abse
So grab all that
and this is going to be row to
change the class to row to and fro row to where it's going to be reversed.
I want to have the image and stuff on this side and the text on this side.
So I'm going to grab everything that's in this column
X yowled will do is take this div this column right here cut it and move it below.
This one
them will change the image too abstract too.
And we're going to change the name to
Al RSA.
And if you're wondering where I get these names there was a there's an online fake word generator which
I used I'm going to change this abstract to and see what else.
Right here.
Want to change this to Allergist's as well.
So let's save that.
And there we go.
All right.
And don't worry about it we can't see the stars.
Don't worry about that yet.
We'll fix that.
And now the last one is going to have the same format as the first row.
So again let's copy the first row which ends here.
See here.
Copy that will go below the second row and paste that in and change this to row 3.
Change this to three.
And as far as the title it's going to be record.
Abstract 3.
This will be abstract 3 and will change the title here and save.
All right.
There we go.
So now we're going to go to the C Ss and let's add a class for our out of style for image content.
And I'm actually going to display Flack's here.
We say display flex and flex direction will be call them.
So it's going to go vertical.
And then we'll justify to the center
and we'll set the height to 300 pixels.
OK so that's just what it did is it move the text down into the middle here.
All right.
Now the card content which is this.
I want that to have a color of the primary color.
So we're going to use that variable
so save and now the stars are green.
All right so in the next video will do is implement the Modals we want to click on these buttons and
have a mode open for each one.
We'll also add the footer.
All right so I'll see in the next lecture.