All right guys.
Now we're going to add the for real quick I'm going to grab this format from materialize.
SS If we go to components her rather than typing it out I'm going to grab this and we'll go and paste
that in.
Let's see we'll put it right under the section.
All right.
Now if I saved that and we take a look.
It has basically no color to it.
What I'm going to do is go to the main door SPSS and let's add for the page for her.
Let's set the background color to the secondary color.
Remember we made it a dark gray.
So I'll say secondary color and then the photo copyright which we can nest in here because we're using
SAS so we can say for Dash copyright.
We're going to set that background
to the secondary color white which is the variable that we created
OK we created it in the materialize variable's file.
So let's save that and there we go.
So there's our footer.
You can see the colors have changed.
I'm just going to change.
SEE.
Let's go to our index.
Let's change these links.
So this will be abstract
and what was the other ones logos.
And gaming.
And we'll get rid of this last one here.
OK.
And then instead of for our content we'll just say about me all right and we'll change that copyright
tax will say 2018
and gallop here.
And we'll just leave that that's fine.
All right so there's a fourth.
Now it's let's do the Modals.
OK so first let's initialize our modals down here.
Let's put a comment here and see a net side now and then we'll say net motile and we do that by taking
class modal and calling Daut moto.
So if we look at the first one the first row here the first whatever gallery image
and we look at the link it goes to abstract 1.
It also has a modal trigger class so that's all set.
Now we just need to create the Modals So we're going to go down to the bottom right below the water
and let's say modal one
and we're going to give this an ID of abstract 1 in the class of modal
OK and then we'll do our modal content
inside here let's put in age for the title which is Dila Gore and then our image with the class of responsive
Dasch I am g.
And this is going to be the image slash gallery slash abstract one.
Jay peg and then under that we're going to put some text and when I say warm 20 tab OK and then under
this div we're going to have our motile for
which is going to have our star rating so I'm going to copy this paragraph with all the stars and we'll
put that right here.
OK so let's copy that and then if we click on this it opens the motile Now notice that the text is white
we can't see it.
So I'm I'm just going to give the motiveless static color so let's go it's say class motile and will
say color 3:33 and you guys can experiment if you want if you want to create a variable for it whatever
you want to do is fine.
There we go.
So that's our moto.
Now let's do the other two.
So they're going to be formatted the same way they're just going to have different content so I'll copy
that.
So this will be modal too.
It will be abstract to will change the image will change the title to al-Ras
and let's see I think we can do half stars as well.
Let me check something here.
Yeah Star half so I font is Star underscore half.
So let's actually make it a little more realistic and we'll take the second one and let's do star underscore
half right here.
Okay.
And then we'll go down to the motile so modal to do star half save that and then we go and see it as
a half star.
Open up the.
Good now do is copy
motile one and we'll do the third one.
Abstract three abstract three and let's see if we want to change the title to reconned.
So now these two should work so that one and that one good.
So now we're going to do as the scroll fire which is actually pretty easy to do.
What we'll do is go down to the javascript and say scroll fire.
So we need to create our options which is going to be an array of objects with a selector.
Now remember we have selectors we have Row 1 2 and 3 so we want to select row 1 and then the offset
is going to be 50 K 50 from the top and then that takes a callback.
I mean just make this wider
it's so offset 50 callback function
and this takes an element and then we just want to fade it in so we can say materialize Daut fade an
image and we can pass in here like that.
All right.
So the first one is is basically always going to be displayed because it's at the top.
But the other two we don't want displayed unless we're at a certain point.
OK.
Which I believe we want this one at 300 offset and this one at 400 I think that's what I had working
so we'll copy this piece of copy that and put a comma here.
Paste that in and we'll say row two.
We'll have an offset of 300.
That's when we want it to fade in.
And then the next one row three will have an offset of 400 OK.
And then we want to go under the options array Whoops.
And we want to call materialize dots scroll fire and pass in our options.
So let's save that.
All right so let's see.
They do appear even the first one is going to fade in but the second one.
What am I missing here.
Did I not change the row
see row 3 row to
oh you know what the reason for that is because we actually need to set the opacity to zero to begin
with.
So in our main CSSA SPSS we're going to say row 1 row 2 and
row 3 are going to set the opacity to zero to begin with because we're feeding them in.
So let's save and then reload.
OK.
So we're already at offset 50 right.
Which is the first one are already at this.
So it fades in.
Now the other two the opacity is set to zero.
But when we hit 300 RHO to should then fade in K when we hit 400 row 3 should fade and good.
So that that's working out good.
Awesome.
So that's all set.
And let's check out the responsiveness.
Make sure that looks good and that still should work even if it's responsive.
So even if you are on a mobile device that would work.
All right so we're getting there the last thing we really need to do is just the other two pages which
are pretty much identical just different content.
All right so that's what we'll do in the next video.