All right guys so we're pretty much there now we just want to add the other pages so I'm going to create
in the route here to new pages one is Logos daughter aged himself and then one is not a folder we want
to file one is going to be gaming aged him now and then I'm going to copy everything from the index
file to logo's except we're going to change some of the content.
We're also going to take the class active off of abstract and put it onto the logos ally and then down
here let's change up this stuff so see.
So the first one the name is going to be Strozzi is
and will leave that text the the image is going to be in the gallery and it's going to be logo one will
change the title again.
Strozzi strides these are now and let's change this to star half
and then the second one is going to be the logo to
and the name is going to be Unix.
It will keep.
I will change the name here as well to Unix.
And then the third one
is going to be hosting
changed the image to logo 3.
Change that to hosting and that should be good.
Now we're going to go down to the Modals and let me see did I change the IDs.
Let's see.
No we didn't.
So idea should be logo 3.
Not the idea but the graph.
This one should be logo too.
And this one should be logo one
and then we'll change up our modals So this will be logo one changed the image.
I know it's tedious but we want it to make sense.
I think that as a star half.
So this one here will be logo's to
you next.
I think that had five stars.
And then this one will be logo three
all right.
So let's save that see if we can go to logo's and other javascript and d.j queries all the same.
So we're still getting the scroll of fire and it's click on them all.
Oh good.
We scroll down we get the next one we get the hosting.
Good.
So now we just need the gaming.
So I'm going to copy everything here and go to gaming h Tim Allen paces then go to the top.
Let's change the active class.
We'll take it off of logos and put it on to gaming and then we're going to change the rows.
So for names we have Clauss costs you know some weird names here Clauss CEO.
We're going to change
the image to gaming one
the HGF here this will be gaming on
this on we'll be
gaming to and for the name.
We have voice Flyn
to change the name care as well.
That I change both names here.
No I didn't.
This one should be Colacello.
All right so road to this will be good gaming too.
OK.
The third one here is rendang for the name
change the image in the trough
right.
So now we'll go down to the Modals and change the ID to gaming one
change the image and search the title
gaming to title title was one voice when
came into to that.
Good.
Oh we're going to change this
game in three and then the title for this was run Dan
and we should be good.
So let's go to gaming.
There we go.
Odal works skirl fireworks
awesome so that's it guys.
We are done.
Now if you were to say deploy this to a web host or something some kind of server you would not need
to deploy the SPSS.
This is strictly for your development all the SAS.
This is all getting compiled to these two CSSA files.
This is all you need so you can leave this behind.
This is just for your own on your own development machine.
Ok just to let you know that the browser does not.
It does it doesn't recognize SAS files.
There's no point in uploading those.
OK so just leave those out.
So we've reached the end of the course.
I really hope you guys enjoyed it if you went through the whole thing and built all five projects.
Congratulations.
I know it's a lot of work it's a lot of typing and hopefully you can take the skills that you've learned
and you can create your own projects and you can get clients and create user interfaces and Web sites
that they're happy with and you can use this in your career and better yourself as a developer.
But I want to sincerely thank you for purchasing the course and sticking through it and that's it.
Thanks guys.
Hopefully I will see you in the next one.