Hey Guys welcome to your next project.
So this is going to be a full screen landing page called biz land and we're going to go through and
Josh I'm going to show you some of the features that we have here.
So if I reload the page you'll see that this text will fade in.
That's because we're using the scroll fire component.
We're also using scroll fire for the nav bar you'll see it's transparent and if I scroll down when we
hit a certain point it turns to solid That way we can't just see through it and you can read the text
clearly.
OK and it's going to stay solid until you actually come back to the site at the top.
OK we're also using an overlay for the image.
So it's kind of a bluish grayish purple ish overlay.
We have scroll spy enabled so that when we click a link it takes us down to that area and just to go
over the areas real quick we have these colored boxes here with some icons.
We have the boat area with an image and a card with some extra shadow and inside the card we have a
collection.
OK and then right here we have just some testimonials and some cards that we have our contact form with
a Google map behind it.
So we're going to implement Google Maps and then we just have a very simple Forder.
OK.
We also have this icon here just to notify the user that they can scroll down and if they click it it'll
take them down to the contact area.
OK let's go ahead and resize this and take a look at their responsiveness.
So if we go down to here you see we have a sidebar with the branding at the top and these boxes now
turn to two six column divs and everything looks pretty good.
If we go smaller to smartphone size you'll see that the image actually moves up.
I didn't want to take the whole the whole area on very small screens.
I didn't think it looked right.
So that's that.
And then we just have everything that's stacked OK and it looks pretty good.
So that's what we'll be building guys hopefully you enjoy it.
And let's get started.