All right so we're going to get started on this project so we're going to do what we did in the rest
of the projects and create a new folder called biz land.
And I just want to bring everything from the theme starter over to our new folder
Okay.
And then let's put this up here and I'll go ahead and openness with the code.
Of course you can use whatever you like.
And then the index age.
Tim I'm going to open with life server
right.
So now we just have our theme starter Let's pull this down a little bit
OK.
And now what we'll do is let's change the title here to biz land
theme and what we're going to do in this video is the whole land the whole image the showcase or head
or whatever you want to call it with the nav bar.
So let's get rid of this H-1 here.
Get rid of this too.
And inside the body let's put a header and let's give it a class of main header.
Now we want an overlay over the image so I'm going to put a div here with the class of primary dash
overlay.
That's just what I like to call my my overlays and then if we had another one with another color we'd
call it secondary overlay.
Now the nav bar is going to be fixed and remember if we want a fixed nav bar that is going to kind of
scroll down with us.
It needs to be wrapped in a div with the class of nav bar fixed and then inside here we put our NAV.
OK and this is going to have a class of transparent because I don't want it to have any background.
So it's put a container in our nav bar and then we'll put our class of Nav. wrapper.
You guys should start to remember these classes you know because we're using them in just about every
project and then we want our branding So it's going to be in a tag with brand logo.
We'll have a go to home.
And then let's just put in here for the text we'll just say biz land and then we want our button collapse
so it'll be in a tag with the class of button Dasch collapse.
And it's also going to have another attribute of data Dasch activates and we'll call this mobile dash
now.
OK and then inside here we want an icon with the class of material dash icons and we want the menu icon.
So if I save that we're just going to get a transparent nav bar so far.
All right.
Now underneath the button collapse we're going to put the the UL which will have a class of right because
we want all the links to float to the right and it's also going to have a class of hide on MGD and down
we want it to hide on medium size screens and less.
OK in here we'll have an ally.
Let's put our links here so this will actually know Class C it's going to go to hash home.
And then what I'm going to do is copy this ally.
So we want let's see let's do two three four and five of these.
So this one will be about
the Swan will be testimonials
and let's see this one here will be contact
and then this last one is actually going to be a bottom.
So it's not going to go anywhere.
It's just for show it's the download button so it'll have a class of the T.N..
And let's give it a class of blue and it'll say download.
All right.
So save that now for the side.
Now remember if it's a fixed nav bar the UL for the side now has to go under this div or it's not going
to work.
We won't be able to click on it so this div ends right here so we're going go right under it and let's
say side now those.
So that will be a UL with the class side nav and also an ID of mobile now because that's what we used
above.
And then and here what I want to do is put in H for the class of blue dash gray.
And let's also do Darkon dash 3 and let's center.
And that's just going to say biz land.
And then under that we'll have our links which are going to be the son going to copy all of these except
for the download button and put those inside here under the age 4.
They actually want to put a divider between the two.
So right here let's put in Ally and then an A with the tag of a class of divider.
It doesn't actually need a try.
Now in order for the sidebar to work we have to initialize it.
So let's go down here and let's say class foughten collapse and we want to call dark side now like that.
You know we'll say a knit side now of right.
So now we're going to do is work on the main image the background of all of this.
So you can go into your project files and you can get the images.
So I'm going to open up my land folder go to I am g and I'm going to paste in the two images that are
included.
So pay in and just to take a look.
So we have the showcase j peg and then we have the people j peg those are the two images for this project.
And then what we'll do is go to our main CSSA and we're going to add the CSSA for the header to have
the the image background and all that as well as the primary overlay.
So let's do the main header first.
So it's going to have a background which is going to be a u r l.
We're going to go outside of the CSSA folder into the image folder and then we want showcase dot chave
peg and then under that we're going to do a background size and set that to cover.
Let's do a background position and let's get that to center we want to center the image and we want
to do the height.
Now for the high we're going to use the H or viewport heights.
And what you can do is you can think of the height as 100 different slices.
OK.
And we can say how many of those slices we want.
Now those slices aren't going to change no matter how much how big or small the browser is it'll always
take up that amount.
So this is how we can do a full screen landing page and have it always be full screen no matter the
size.
So I want to say one hundred VH.
All right.
I'm going to set a minimum height of 600 pixels.
I don't want it to be able to go under 600 pixels.
And then we'll set the text to white and let's say at the position to relative because we're going to
have the overlay inside of it which is going to be absolute and anything absolute has to be inside of
a relative position element elements so will save and you can see it takes up the whole screen.
Now if I did like 50 VH It would take up 50 of the 100 slices.
So VHS is very very powerful.
We also have VW which is viewport with.
You can do the same thing going horizontal.
So now the image is too prominent.
We want to kind of dark it down a little bit with the primary overlay.
So it's sad that I'm actually going to put that up above.
All right.
So primary overlay will do the background and it has to be R-GA because we want it to be able to be
see through.
So the color will be the R.G. will be 63 red 57 green 77 blue.
And then for the Alpha for the opacity you will do 0.7.
OK we want to position it absolute
and then inside here inside we want it from the top zero position and the left zero position.
And we want it to spread across 100 percent and then also height should be 100 percent.
We wanted to take up the whole thing.
The overlay should just do just that it should overlay the image so width and height should be 100 percent
and we'll set the overflow to hidden because we don't want any scroll bars or anything like that so
let's save.
And then we go now we have our overlay.
OK so let's add the content the showcase content.
So we're going to go see it's going to go under the UL right here still within this Div. say showcase.
So all of a classic showcase.
Let's also give it a container and inside here we'll have a row.
It's going to be a full column grid's So we're going to do call as 12.
And let's also do a custom class of main text and then in here will have an H 5 and it's going to say
you found the can then H-1 and it's going to say right place to start.
Just some corny marketing text they came up with so we have a paragraph with flow text to make it bigger
and make it responsive and then it's going to say to take your business
to the next level with our services.
I can't spell and type services that have taken the companies
to the Fortune 500.
Probably misspelled something but that's mine doesn't matter.
So let's put a line break underneath and then we're going to have a button to learn more buttons so
it's going to be in a tag that's formatted as a button.
So be it.
And let's also do between large Let's make it white and let's make it have black text.
All right and then it's going to go to hash about and the text will just say learn more.
All right.
In addition to that button we want to have that icon as well.
That little icon to notify the user that they can scroll down.
That's going to be wrapped in a link with the class of white text and it's going to go to the contact
if they click it.
OK so now inside the tag what's put in Icon Tiriel icons.
We also want it to be medium sized.
And then the icon itself is going to be an arrow.
It's going to be erro underscore draw down underscore circle.
All right.
I'm also going to give this icon a special class of scroll
dash icon because I need to grab on to it within the CSSA to position it.
OK.
So let's save and there we go.
Now we need to fix this up a little within the CSX.
So I want this all to be pushed down so let's grab the showcase.
So main Hetter showcase and we're going to add a padding top of 110 pixels so that'll push it down.
And then let's see we want to add the positioning for the scroll icon icon.
It's going to be positioned absolute.
Remember the header is already positioned relative.
So that's what we're using as a parent.
We want to say from the bottom it should be 5 percent up and then from the left it should be 47 percent
over.
And let's set the opacity so that we can see through it a little bit.
So we'll set that to zero point five and save in there we go.
All right.
So I think that that's good for now.
So I will see you in the next lecture.