All right guys so in the last video we created the full screen Hetter here.
Now what I want to do is before we move onto the boxes down here I want to implement the scroll fire
to kind of feed in this text when we enter and also make the nav bar solid when we scroll which we're
actually not really going to be able to test yet because there's no we have no scrolling.
Well I guess you could put a margin top or something.
But let's let's let's go down to and then each team will go down to the javascript area and let's see
we'll go right here and we'll say scroll fire.
So a scroll fire we need a variable.
Let's create our options which is going to be an array.
So first of all do the fade in of the text member I gave the text the class of main text.
So this is going to take a selector and it's going to be the class of main hash text and we're going
to set the offset to zero.
And let's say for a callback we'll have a function
that will take in the element
like that and then all we have to do is say materialize
materialized and then we're going to use fade in image and then pass in our money sign parentheses and
then the element.
OK now the offset just means that we want we don't want to scroll for it to fade and we just wanted
to fade in right away.
So then after the options array here we want to say materialize Daut scroll fire
and we want to pass in those options.
So let's save that and there we go.
So now when we reload it fades it
now for the nav bar.
All we have to do is add in another objects to these options and we can actually just copy this and
paste that in.
So now we're going to say selector and it's going to be the now bar fixed class.
So now our fix is in the offset.
I'm going to say fifteen hundred.
OK so when we get to that position this is that's when this will run and what we want to do is we can
get rid of this.
We actually don't even need to pass in this element here.
We're going to take the Nav. using Jay queery.
We're going to take the now and we're going to remove the class of transparent
OK not only do we want to do that but we want to add a class.
I guess we could just chain it on like this.
So I say add class of blue gray and also Darkon dash 3 or whatever color you want it to be.
So if we save that we're not going to see any difference yet because it has to hit this point before
this actually takes effect.
But what I could do to test it out is go to the each team now and go right here and let's just put a
div and we'll put a style
and let's say height equals
weight angle to do height.
He calls
say 700 when a scene equals C Ss.
OK so save that.
And then
seven hundred pixels.
OK so now if I scroll down
and work
it's to sixteen hundred
that's not working either.
So Nav.
remove class add class.
Know let's see if this is actually firing off.
I'm going to say materialize Daut toast.
Let's try that.
So a reload.
Scroll down.
All right.
So we're getting the toast.
It's just this isn't working.
I haven't used J-curve in quite a while so maybe we can't do that.
Let's try that.
Get rid of that toast.
That didn't work either.
What did I do wrong.
Oh I don't have coats in here.
Quotes.
There we go.
All right so that's working good.
So I'm going to just get rid of that this Stiv right here.
That was just for testing.
All right.
So we know that those two features are now working.
So let's create the boxes.
Now we're going to go under the header and we'll say Section boxes.
So it's going to be a section.
I will give it a class of Section dash boxes.
Notice I'm not giving it a regular section class because I don't want any padding I wanted I wanted
to be basically full with I wanted to take up everything.
I do want to add a class of center though.
What's
right.
And then inside here let's put a row.
OK we're going to use a grid we're going to say call let's do call x 12.
And then on medium screens it'll be six.
And on large screens it will be three.
And let's make this one blue with white text and we're going to give it a class of box as well.
And inside here we're going to have an icon.
So it's saying material dash icons are going to be medium sized And this or this one's going to be show
under score card.
OK.
And then age four we're going to say grow your business.
And then a paragraph and let's do Lorem 15
actually would sue Lorem Tony
hers.
So if I copy the column that's right here let's put in for three more so we have one two three four.
And then we're just going to change some stuff up.
So the second one I want to be purple something to change the color.
We're going to change the icon to people and then we'll change the heading to professional advisors.
And let's see this one here.
I'm going to change the color to teal so I'll say teal will change the icon to varified underscore user.
And then the H for is going to say six here your company.
All right.
And then finally the last one no change from blue to Amber.
Let's also do dark and for all make it darker and then the icon will be a count underscore balance and
then the H four is going to say
multiply your income so let's save that.
And that's what it looks like.
Let's see.
Why is that.
Icon not showing our show chart not card.
OK.
So there we go.
Now what I'm going to do is go to we're going to go to CSSA because I don't I want to add a bunch of
padding here so in the CSX let's add a class of box let's say padding 40 pixels on the top and bottom
10 pixels on the left and right and I'm going to add an important flag so that we make sure that that
gets overwritten and then the H for in the box.
I just want to add padding bottom of 30 pixels so save that and take a look and that looks pretty good.
And if we resize this when we get here we get them side by side and then here we get them stacked.
All right now let's work on the media query because somehow when this is very small like that I don't
want this to take up this whole area that's just too much.
So let's create a media query.
Yeah I will say media.
And then let's say men with I'm sorry Max width of 600 pixels.
Then we want the main header
We want the height to only take up 50 VH remember it it takes up a hundred by the fall but now when
it's less than 600 I'll save that.
Now it's only 50 viewport Heights which is what I want.
All right.
Good.
And then another thing I want to do is just make sure that there is no more see how this margin below
these boxes we have the class of Section boxes.
I'm just going to grab on to that in the C Ss right here.
And we're going to say margin bottom zero.
Hey we're going to say that's important.
OK so that gets rid of that.
Oh what.
That should work.
So.
Oh you know what we didn't put Roe.
It should be the ROE because that's what the margins actually on.
All right so that's going to be it for this video guys in the next video we're going to start to work
our way down and we're going to do the about page the about section.