All right so we have our landing area here the header we have the boxes now we want to work on the About
section so we're going to go under the boxes section and let's say section about.
All right so for this I am going to use the section class and also create a custom class called Section
about.
Let's also make it gray and we will lighten it will say Litan 3.
And let's do Center OK let's see let's put a container inside here we'll have an H2 and we're going
to say about this land under the age 2 will have a paragraph of flow text.
GPP
and let's do Warum 20
and then under that div I'm sorry under that paragraph we're going to put a row and we're going to have
a column that will be stacked on small devices and then on medium screens and up will be six columns.
So we're going to want two of these.
And in the first one will be that image that people image.
So it's to image it's given a class of responsive dash I am g as well as circle and then the source
is going to be I am g slash people dot JP So if we save that and take a look.
OK that looks good on this side we want to have that.
It's going to be a collection.
And I want to give it some extra shadow.
So in this column let's say I want to move it down a little bit so I'm just going to use a B R here.
And actually what I wanted to do instead of doing six I wanted to do 5 and then offset it by 1 that
way it's not so close to the image it's pushed over a little bit.
So we'll offset it and then let's put a UL but the class of collection and also a class of with Hetter
not with but w i th header.
And then let's give it some extra shadow some extra depth so we'll say Z dash dash dash for OK and now
in here we want our head so this one will be collection Dasch header and we'll putting h 5 in here and
we'll just say Services
OK.
And then the rest of these let's do ally collection item and we want to have a check icon.
So I'm going to do I material Icahn's
and let's align them to the left.
I'll give this a left class and it's going to be the check icon.
And then after that I'll say business
consultation so save that and then we go so let's add some other services.
I'm going to copy this library here so will do two three four five six and under business consultation
let's add a service of financial analytics
OK.
So this one will be security
services
and let's do marketing say marketing and advertising
an Internet services
and counting.
All right.
So that looks pretty good.
So now let's do the testimonial area.
So we'll go under this section.
So give us the class of section in Section
testimonials.
We're also going to give it a blue background.
Make sure it's white text and center
in our container put in H2 and we'll say what our clients say
let's put a row and then we're basically going to have three boxes so we want them to be on medium screens
and up we want them to be four columns wide.
So call as 12 am four and we're going to have a card.
So we'll say a card class of card class of gray light and dash for let's do black text and let's give
these a Z depth as well so say Z dash depth dash four.
All right.
And then inside here we'll have our card content.
And then that's just going to be a paragraph.
I'm also going to put some some E-M tags some emphasis.
And then let's do Lorem 30 tab.
All right.
Now under the card content we're going to have a class of card action which is kind of like a footer.
And we're just going to put a name let's say John Doe
from ABC Inc.
All right so if we look at that should look like that's you know what let's do 20 words instead.
There we go.
All right.
So I'm going to copy now this whole column which ends right here so when can grab that and we're going
to have two more.
So the second one here I'm going to change all I'm going to change is the name right here the name the
company so we'll say Sharon Johnson from
I don't know x y z
and this one down here we'll say from one to three
say Wayne Jackson all right.
So those are testimonials.
All right.
Now I'm going to skip the contact area with the Google map.
For now we're going to do that in the next video.
But I just wanted to do the water and get that out of the way.
So let's go down here and I'll put a comment here that says section contact just as a placeholder.
And then right here we'll do our folder.
OK.
And the water I'm actually going to use the same format from materialize.
SS If we go to our foot or here just going to grab this just to kind of shorten things up and we'll
change a couple of things.
So for the color let's go to the top.
The footer tag here and say blue gray and we want to dark in one.
And then let's see in this was changed this to location.
I'm going to get rid of this white text class just in H5
and let's see we'll get rid of this and we'll put a paragraph that will say this land.
And then for the paragraph we'll just say 5 5 5 somewhere.
Dr.
Boston Mass and then age five we have our links.
So we might as well just copy our links from the Nav..
So I'll grab home about testimonials and contact.
We'll just grab those and put those here in the UL
like
you should do it.
And then down here this foot of copyright I'm going to add blue gray and then I'm going to do Darkon
for and then we'll just add here is land theme twenty eight 18.
You know we'll just do that.
All right.
Let's see.
So for this instead of more links I want this to be a back to top with an icon.
So we're going to put in I tag here the class of material icons.
And let's also add a class of left and the icon we want is going to be keyboard arrow up.
And then after that icon we're going to say back to talk.
All right let's save it see what it looks like.
Good.
The only problem is our links are blue.
So we just want to add a class to these lengths of white text.
Ok so grab that
right.
So it should look good.
There you go.
Now for the scrolls spy because right now we don't have those.
We don't have them to have it implemented so let's do that.
So these links they're going to go to hash home hash about and so on the hash home is actually going
to be the body.
So give that an idea of home and then we also want to add a class of scroll spies so that it gives it
that effect.
OK.
Next one will be the about which is right
here.
So this section will have an idea of about and we want to have a class of scrolls by.
OK contact we'll have one but we haven't done that yet.
Testimonials is another one.
And yeah I think that's it.
OK now we have to initialize scroll SWI So let's do that right here.
So I believe we just do class scrolls spy and then
skirl spot.
All right.
So let's try that about testimonials contacts not going to work yet.
Home works good.
All right so in the next video we're going to work on the contact form and we're going to implement
the Google map behind it.