All right guys are in this video we're going create the contact form and implement the Google map.
So we're going to go right above the foot are we already put a comment here for the contact and we're
going to use a section tag with the section class and also section Dasch contact.
And let's also do Center and let's do scroll spy.
Now this also needs an idea since it's going to be using scroll spy and say eye contact.
Now inside here we need to place a did for the Google Maps I'm going to create a div with an ID of Google
Maps.
OK.
Nothing's going to go inside of it just that div there.
And then we'll continue on with our container and let's put a row.
Now what I want is the form to be six columns wide but I want it to be pushed over to the right.
So we need to set an offset.
So we're going to say call let's do as 12 and then and six but we also want to do an offset and six.
OK so six offset.
And then here we're going to put a card panel
and we're going to use a little bit of depth shadow so let's do the dash dash dash 5 and inside the
card panel will put in each form will see a contact us under the age for let's put input field.
And this is going to be the name so we'll say input is going to have type text ID name.
And let's do a placeholder of name.
Ok under that will have a label for name and now same name.
And then what I'll do is copy that input field div and we'll do two three four.
So the second one is going to be email.
So I will be email.
Will do.
Type email.
And then this next one is going to be the phone.
So let's say I did phone placeholder
phone number label will be phone name for attribute will also be.
All right and this last one here is actually going to be a text area so I'm going to replace input type
text with text area and member text areas need a special class of materialized dash textarea and then
it also needs an ending tag.
And then for the label will say message
message will change the placeholder and let's change the ideas while
and there we go.
All right finally we need our input.
Our submit button so that will be input type submit value will say submit give it a class of PTEN and
let's do blue dash gray and save.
And then there's our form.
So behind it is where the the Google map is going to go.
Now there's quite a bit of Javascript.
We're going to need to bring in we're also going to need to bring in the Google Maps API script.
So we're going to go down to our script tags go right below the materialize script and above our custom
script
and then the source is going to be HTP and it's going to be maps Daut Google API I's dot com slash and
maps slash API slash Jay ass.
So that'll bring in the the API for us.
All right.
Now there's quite a bit of Javascript that we need to write and I'm not going to explain every line
because this isn't a javascript course.
There's plenty of snippets you can find for Google Maps.
This is basically one of those.
So we're just going to type this so now we're going to have two variables.
One is going to be the position where we want our marker.
The other is going to be the center position.
Both are going to be around Boston Mass if you want to change that.
That's fine.
But it's going to be an array and it's going to have a latitude and longitude.
So the latitude is going to be 42 Daut thirty six thirty six 1 1 4 5.
And then the longitude is going to be negative 71 Daut 0 5 7 0 8 3.
So that's the position and then the center position
is going to be 42 Dortch 3 7 7 8 1 5.
And then it's going to be negative 70 Daut 90 1 1 3 3.
So those are positions.
Now we're going to create a function called show Google Maps
and we're going to create a variable here called the last launch.
So latitude longitude we're going to set it equal to a new Google dot maps dot lat long should be uppercase.
Believe me I like that.
And then in here we want to position zero so that's still the latitude that's going to be this number
right here the zero index of that array and then we also want the longitude which will be position 1.
OK let me just close this up so that's that.
And then we want the center left latitude and longitude.
So I'm actually going to just copy this line and then change this to center.
Lat launch and again we were going to do this Google maps at launch except we're going to do our center
position right.
OK so now that we have those Let's create a variable called Map options and set that to an object.
And and here we're going to set our options like our zoom level which I'm going to set to 12 street
so we can do strawe Street View control
we're going to set that to false we don't want the Street View control scale control.
We'll go ahead and said that true.
And you can look at the Google Maps API docs if you want to look at all this stuff.
Then we want the map type D and I want it to be a good road map type thing so we're going to say Google
dot maps dot map type Id just right here and it's going to be Daut road map like that.
And then the center position is going to be the center
launch.
OK so that's the options.
Now we have to actually create the map so we're going to have we're going to take that map variable
set it to new Google dot maps dot map and then we need to pass in where we want to put it.
Now remember we are that idea of Google Maps.
That's what we want.
So we're going to say document dog get element Friday and then Google Maps I think was a was it all
lowercase.
Oh so Id I guess just Google map.
That's what we want to use Google map.
All right.
And then we want another parameter with our map options.
So that'll create the map.
Now we want the marker
here seeking comment this stuff so this will be.
Will say create map
map options map positions.
All right.
So show markers so we're going to say marker equals new Google Maps thought.
Marker
you know why it's usually these should be uppercase
K and this is going to take an object and we're going to say the position of the marker which is going
to be our last longe position.
Right.
And then the math is going to be our map variable and then we're going to say Dragon Ball you can make
your icon your markers drag a ball I'm going to say false for that.
And then animation
when it's set to Google Maps daunts animation Daut drop so we'll give that a little drop animation.
And then finally we need to add the event listener.
So the big Google Maps Daut the vente dots and then we're going to add the dorm Lisner
So Adam listener to the window
load.
And then we want to show Google Maps.
So now we need to do is add a little bit of CSSA make sure this is saved it's not going to show up yet
because it needs to be treated kind of like how this primary overlay is its position to absolute within
its container and then it's a 100 percent height and width.
We want it to take up the whole section contact.
So let's go to our CSSA and let's say Section contact because we need to set that to relative.
So that's a relative and then let's do our Google map.
We want to set the position to absolute.
We want to set the height to 100 percent with to 100 percent top 0 and left zero.
All right and let's set the z index to 0 as well Z indexes.
Basically how close it is to you to the screen.
The higher it is the closer to you it is.
So let's save that and still doesn't seem to be working on this.
Oh there we go.
All right so we have them out now.
Notice that the pin and the card panel here has it's not showing because we need to basically up the
in the z index of that.
So let's go right here and let's say Section
contact
card panel and we're going to position that relative.
And then we're going to set the z index to 1 and save.
So what that did is it moved it above the map because the map has a z index of 0 and you can see we
have a little marker here as well.
And we can move this around to.
All right.
So that looks pretty good.
So I think that's going to do it for this project guys.
Hopefully you enjoyed this.
And that's it.
All right.
So I will see you in the next one.