You guys welcome to the material I CSSA from scratch with five projects course in this course you learn
all about them materialized CSSA framework so that you can build really great looking you guys in Web
sites.
Now this is not a design theory course or anything like that.
After the first section you'll be spending all of your time in a text editor or building things with
this great framework so it's a very hands on course.
Now before taking this course you aren't expected to know anything about materialize.
We're starting from absolute scratch.
If you do know a little bit about the framework you're going to learn just about everything else.
And if you do already know materialize you've used it before.
We have five real world great looking projects for you to complete.
So even if you wanted to skip the learning sections and go right to the projects you could do that as
well.
All right so what should you know before taking this course.
Now you should know basic h Tim Allen elenchi ss.
That's really all you need to know tags and styles basic layout etc..
You don't technically need to know javascript and Jay Querrey but it will help you a bit because materialise
has a lot of great javascript widgets.
Now in most cases it's just a matter of initializing them with a line of code and then adding some attributes
or classes but in some of the projects we'll be writing some custom javascript and Jay Querrey but nothing
too difficult so if you're not familiar with javascript you'll be just fine.
OK I'll even learn some.
And then obviously if you do know a framework like bootstrap you'll you you already understand the whole
scope of what a UI framework is and that can obviously be helpful.
But of course that's not needed.
Now as far as what you will learn you'll learn the entire materialized CSSA framework from start to
finish when it comes to all of the CSSA and Javascript components.
But what do you think is worth even more than that is that you'll learn to structure web pages and you
wise and I like to break things into HTML 5 sections and organize them in a way that's easy to understand
and scale if needed.
So if you wanted to add another section we build it in a way that makes that really easy to do.
We'll also be adding some custom javascript and J.A.G. stuff like a basic to do list in our admin team.
We'll have some Google Maps integration things like that.
And then in the last project we're going to use SAS which is a CSSA preprocessor that allows us to use
variables and dynamic features in our CSX.
OK now as far as the learning career curriculum goes after the intro videos will start on the materialize
sandbox.
And for those of you that took my bootstrap 4 course it's pretty much the same thing that we did there.
We're going to complete that and we'll move on to our 5 projects and I'll show you a preview of what
those are in a minute.
OK also all the code is included in the course.
Now as far as the sandbox goes what this is is something I put together that is kind of like a custom
learning UI.
It has predefined menu items for each section and some pages have some.
Some of the core each team already created.
So all we have to do is add the materialized stuff.
This really lessens the the painful typing of stuff that you already know and then once this is finished
you'll have it to look back on if you need to know when the class names or how to initialize the carousel
anything like that.
You'll have this really good resource to look back on.
All right so once that's done we're going to move on to our first project which is called Travel ville
and it's basically a theme for a travel agency that uses the carousel slider.
It uses auto complete card's icons and a bunch of other stuff.
And as you can see all projects are completely responsive and they all look great on mobile devices
as well.
OK next we have a theme called KwaZulu which is a cloud hosting theme.
I got the idea for this from Heroku although it's not nearly as in-depth but the color scheme is similar
as well as the content.
Ok this theme will have three separate pages rather than just one landing page.
We'll also use a carousel slider for the testimonial sections and tabs in the solution pages and some
other stuff.
Next we're going to build an admin theme called Mad Men or material admin and this is our most interactive
project as far as the javascript and Jay Querrey we're actually going to have these numbers here.
Count from 0 up.
They're going to animate.
We're also going to have we're going to add a simple chart here.
So this is from canvas J.S..
We're just going to add some dummy data here.
We're also going to make this to do lists.
You can't really see it down here but it's a quick to do list.
We're going to make this function so we'll be able to add to Dewes and delete them and so on.
We're going to use modals we're also have a preload or so that it takes one second for each page to
load and it'll show the little spin or graphic.
So it's going to be a very interactive project.
All right so the next one is going to be a full screen landing page called biz land which is a business
consulting theme will be using scroll spy so that we can just click on a link here and it will basically
animate us down to the section that we want.
We'll also be using a Google map for the background under the contact form and then the last project
called Gallop's is going to be a graphic design portfolio and we're going to be using SAS with this
project.
OK we're going to compile our SAS with a goofy tool called Koala.
We're also going to use scroll fire which will allow us to scroll down and we'll have each project here
appear as we scroll down.
All right guys so I really hope you enjoy this course.
I put a lot of time and effort into the projects I wanted to create themes that looked professional
and looked like something that you would really create for a client.
All right so let's jump in and get started in the next video I just want to take a little bit of time
to talk about exactly what materialize CSSA is as well as what material design is.
OK so I will see you in the next lecture.