All right so we're going to go ahead and set up our environment now since this is a front end course
so we don't need any databases or anything difficult like that in this video we're just setting up a
text editor and we're going to be using Visual Studio code for this course.
Now you don't have to use VS code if you want to use atom or Sublime Text or web storm or some other
editor that's absolutely fine.
But if you want to follow along to a T then I would suggest using VS code along with the couple of extensions
that I'm going to install as well.
All right so you can go to cocotte Visual Studio dot com and just download it.
It is completely cross-platform so it doesn't matter if you're on Windows Mac or Linux.
Ok I already have it downloaded so I'm just going to go ahead and open the windows cause I'm going to
open up the setup file and we're just going to go through the install a real quick.
I already had installed at one point so I guess I already had the folder created but we're just going
to click next.
Now you want to choose these two options right here.
This is going to make it so that when you right click a folder or a file you'll be able to open it with
Visual Studio code which is pretty handy right.
So just get that set up OK so that's all set.
Let's go ahead and watch visuals to your code.
And you should see your welcome page here I'm just going to close that up and what I want to do first.
Basically I want to set up a couple settings a couple of preferences and then install a couple extensions.
So let's first go to File preferences settings or hit Control comma or command comma and basically the
settings file is one big case file so they're just key value pairs of different categories.
There's only a couple of things that I want to change.
One is my font size so that you guys can see this better.
So to change a setting you'll see it says Ed. font size 14.
I'm going to click the little pencil icon and say copy to settings and what it will do is move it over
here to the custom area where we can actually edit it so I'm going to change it to 26 and hit Control
s or command.
If you're on a Mac and it'll save it automatically and you can see it kicks in.
All right so another thing I want to change is my tab size so I'm going to click the little pencil icon
and change it from 4 to 2 so that way our code isn't so spread out and then I also want to turn on word
wrap so I'm going to search for the word wrap in the search bar and you can see added or word wrap is
off.
I'm going to go ahead and set that to on and just click click save and retry and then it puts it over
here and turns it on.
All right so let's go ahead and save that control ass and close out.
And now we're going to install a couple of extensions so we're going to click this icon at the bottom
here.
This is where you can search for extensions and so on.
So we basically want two extensions One is live server which is right here so when I click the little
green install button and it'll install and this is so that we can take in each HTML file and we can
open it on our local host rather than on our file system.
And it also gives us autoload functionality so as soon as we save it will update and I won't have to
keep reloading it.
It's very very helpful.
So once it's installed you just want to click this reload button and it reloads your editor.
All right the next thing I want to install is prettier.
So we're going to search for prettier and prettier as a code formatter and basically what I want to
do is configure it so that it will fix things on save.
OK so if we for instance if we're missing a semi-colon in our CSSA if we save it will automatically
at it and it will also format our code nice and neat.
That way all everyone's code will match and it just makes things much easier.
So we're going to install that
and you can see it's quite popular there's $1 million downloads
OK so once that's installed you just want to click reload again.
And then those are the only two extensions that we need at least for now.
So next thing I want to do is go back to my settings or preferences or preferences settings and we need
in order for prettier to auto save or auto edits are correct when we save we need to search for.
Let's see what it is it's I believe it's format on save.
So search for format right here edit or format on save as set defaults.
I'm going to go ahead and set that to true so it gets put over here and we'll save that with control
or command us.
And then the other thing that I want to change I'm going to search for prettier and we want.
Well actually this is completely optional.
I prefer single quotes in my javascript.
We will be doing a little bit of Javascript and if I do if we don't change this all single quotes will
turn to double quotes.
So this right here pretty or single quote.
I'm going to set to True but it's completely up to you if you want to use that or not.
OK I'm going to save.
And that looks good so go ahead and close this up.
And that should be all the settings we need for now.
So now I want to do is just test a couple of things out.
I'm going to just create an on each team I'll file right on my desk top.
You don't have to save this.
You don't have to keep this or anything.
It's not going to be in the files it's just a test some things.
So we're going to say open with code you should have that if you chose those two options in the beginning.
All right so we're in the index each time I'll file.
Now another thing I want to mention is Emmett.
So it is just a fantastic program.
It's it's a it's an extension for most editors but it's included by default with the code so it's not
something we have to install it's already here.
But if you're using atom or Sublime Text or something like that I would highly suggest installing it.
It allows us to do things like put in an exclamation and hit tab.
And it gives us basically just head body tags a whole each time I lay out if we want to do tags like
let's say in H-1 we could just do H-1 tab it'll give us a beginning and ending H-1 if we wanted to add
an ID we could do hash lets say test tab it'll give us an idea of test if we wanted a class we could
do Daut test or whatever we want the class name and it'll give us that class.
Now if we want a div we could do div dot tests for a class of test but we don't even need to put the
word div if if that's what we want we can just do dot test tab and it will give us a div with the class
of test.
Same thing with ID if we wanted an idea of test we could go ahead and do that.
So Emmon is very very helpful.
We could do things like let's say we wanted 10 allys we could do ally times 10 and tab and that gives
us 10 allys it's just it really makes things much easier and I'd highly recommend it if you're not already
using it.
And I will be using it throughout the course so I wanted to show you that so that you don't get confused
when you see me doing things like that.
OK another thing I wanted to do is just test out the live server so I'll just put an H-1 in here and
just say hello world and save.
And then if you install life server you should be able to right click and say open with live server
and you can see that it opens our file up.
So I'm just going to snap these over.
Now notice that the in the U R L bar it's at our loopback address which is 1 2 7 0 0 1 that's your local
host and it's on port 5500 by default.
All right.
Now what's nice about this is that if I change something here if I change this to.
Hello there and just save it automatically reloads I don't have to keep reloading it.
So that's really nice.
All right.
So I would highly recommend that you use something like this.
Most most braue are text editors have something like this for instance Adam has Adam live server.
It just makes things much easier and more efficient.
All right so that's all I wanted to do.
Now that we have everything set up on do you want to stop the server you can see right down here where
it says port 5500.
Just click that and that'll stop the server.
OK.
And if I reload now it won't work.
So in the next video what I want to do is start to set up our sandbox so we're going to have a bunch
of files I already pre-made that are ready to go and ready to start.
Learn start looking at the syntax for materialize the classes the javascript components all that stuff.
So we'll get into setting that up in the next video.