All right guys so before we move on to the next section and get to work on MacIan dematerialize framework.
I just want you to set up the sandbox OK so the sandbox is a collection of HTL files that we have one
for each section and each I'm sorry one for each lecturer and each lecturer will cover a certain aspect.
So for instance Section 2 Lecture 1 is on typography and you can see the file name here to one typography
daughter each team now and we have things like headings paragraphs block quotes stuff we're going to
go over we're going to add some materialize markup some classes and talk about it.
That will be one lecture and then the next one will be on text and background colors.
You can see the name of this file is to underscore two colors on each team.
And we look at the different colors the dark and then light and classes things like that.
So for each lecture will have a different page that we're going to edit and look at the classes and
so on.
All right so section 2 and 3 will be on CSSA components.
So things like cards and tables and forms things like that.
And then four and five will be on javascript's So for instance the carousel will look at the collapsible
tabs things like that Parallax so different different javascript features.
So this is basically the end result of the sandbox.
OK and this will be included in your in this particular lecture's files.
But what's really important is the starter version of it.
So you'll have a zip file called materialize sandbox starter.
That's what you want to download.
All right I have it right here the zip files so what I want you to do is create a folder somewhere on
your computer and just call it materialize underscore sandbox OK and open that empty folder.
And then we're going to take all the files from the start of version.
OK.
So it should look like this are going to grab everything here and just bring it over all right now this
is your sandbox to work with for the next few sections.
So what I'm going to do is just open this with the code which is the text editor I'm using.
Feel free to use any other text editor I would suggest having the files on the side here though.
All right so let's quickly take a look at the structure.
So like I said we have an HMO file basically for every lecture for the next four sections.
And if we look at the folders here we have a local version of materialized CSX.
At this time we're using version zero point one hundred point two which is the latest from materialise
CSSA dot com.
Now Version 1 is in alpha and at some point that will be stable.
When that happens this course will be updated updated very soon after that.
But for now no matter what the latest version is I would suggest using the version that comes in the
sandbox just so you don't run into any issues.
And then the course will be updated later on.
OK we also have just a style CSSA And in case we need any extra styles but I don't I don't think we
actually do need that Faunce that's just the folder for the fonts that comes with materialized.
If I were to go to materialize CSSA dot com and download the package this is what we get.
OK excluding the images the images are something that I added for cards and things like that so we just
have some high quality images to work with.
OK in the javascript folder we just have the general materialized in a file javascript.
We're obviously not going to touch this file.
We just need to include it for any javascript.
OK we also need to include Jey query but we're going to use a CDN for that.
So to look at one of these files they're all basically formatted the same as far as like the head.
Things like that we're in we're bringing in the material Icahn's library materialise has its own icon
library.
We're bringing that in from Google API eyes.
We're also importing the material I CSSA file from the local version that we have in the CSSA folder.
We're importing the styles CSSA file.
We have a viewport for responsiveness and mobile devices.
And then down here we just have the title of the of whatever the lecturer is.
OK you're not going to touch any of this.
This is just the title.
And then this is the menu.
OK so this is that menu you saw with all the different links to the different lectures.
So what you want to do is go down to where it says start here.
OK nothing above start here do you need to touch ok unless we're specifically adding something maybe
in a style or something like that above.
But generally you're going to want to just scroll down to where it says Start here and then down here
you'll see it says.
And here I should put some spaces in there.
OK so we'll be working with everything in between.
And some things like headings.
You'll see there's nothing here we'll just start from scratch and put in our headings.
Some things actually have some.
Some tags and content and we'll just add our classes and so on.
So you can learn about all the different classes.
All right and then down at the bottom we just have a query included are materialized javascript and
oh this test right here.
That won't be there for your version.
That was just something I was testing out.
And then here is where we're just initializing the dropdown menu.
So you don't have to worry about this now in some in some lectures we will have to add some javascript
especially for 4 and 5 sections 4 and 5.
So that's where we'll add javascript down here.
So we have javascript's start here.
So I tried to lay it out in a very simple way that's understandable and if we look at the next file
you'll see it's very similar.
If we go down after the menu it's start here and this is where we'll be working.
All right.
And down here you can see if we have some javascript to add will put it down here.
OK.
So that's all I'll be doing.
Guys this is how the next four sections are going to work.
Once we get through the sandbox we're going to start to build some real projects or I'd.
But I'm doing the sandbox will really teach you what's available with materialize as well as get you
familiar with the syntax with the classes with what we can do with javascript initialization things
like that.
OK so in the next section we're going to start.
And we're going to get into basic typography alignment things like that.
So I will see you in the next video.