All right so now we're going to start to get into the javascript widgets or javascript components of
material ICSA us and we're going to start off with the carousel so this is file for underscore one carousel
and you see these panels here.
This is actually for the content slider down here which we're going to get to later.
But first we're going to deal with just a straight image slider or I should say Carrousel.
So let's give this div a class of Carrousel.
OK whenever we want to use a carousel we add that class and then these tags here need a class of carrousel
dash item.
All right.
Now this will work without having a Tref but it's good practice to put something here.
I'm going to put a hash one exclamation just to give it kind of an identifier and also to give it a
pointer when you hover over it.
And then for the image we'll just do image slash image one dot j peg.
All right so that's basically it for a carousel.
I am.
So what I'm going to do is copy this a tag and let's just copy it let's just paste this.
And so that's one two three four more so one two three four and we're going to change the image numbers
here.
OK.
And let's change the identifiers of the length so it will say 2
and 5.
Right.
Now if I say we don't see anything because just like with most of the JavaScript widgets it needs to
be initialized in Jay Querrey or in Javascript.
So let's go down to the bottom here.
And all we have to do is throw in our query and say the carousel class is probably spell it right.
And then we just need to call Daut carrousel like that and save.
And there we go.
So now we have a nice carousel and if we click on one of these images it'll go over we can go backwards.
It's also touch enabled for mobile devices.
So that's one type of carrousel we also have a full with our Slider.
It's also called.
So I'm going to do is copy this whole thing we just did and then I'm going to comment it out OK and
then for the full width I'm going to just replace what we have here.
And then we're just going to add one class in addition to carrousel called carrousel dash slider and
save right.
Now if we just do this you can see it gives us one image at a time and I can bring it over.
But it still has that effect where it's kind of getting smaller and then the other one comes in.
This the switch effect is the same if we want to have just a straight slider what we can do is it's
actually a comment that out and
we'll say gee query let's say dark carousel dash slider.
And again we're going to do a carousel.
But we're going to pass an option of full with and set that to true.
All right so let's save that now it looks the same to begin with but if I slide it notice that it doesn't
have that effect it's just a straight slider just goes from image to image without one getting smaller
and having that that switch effect.
And you can also go backwards.
OK.
But it's up to you if you wanted that the other way that's fine as well.
All right so those are the basic image sliders or carousels knowledge.
Look at the content slider.
So instead of just having images we can actually have content.
So what I want to do is comment this so
and let's let's start to add some stuff here.
There's quite a few classes we need to add so just like above we need the carousel class.
We also want the carousel slider
and we also want I'm going to do centers well which will center everything.
And then it's going to have another attribute called Data dash indicators
and we want to set that to true.
All right the indicators are basically the little dots that show which slide you're on.
And I think we can actually use these with with the other ones actually hold on let me try this for
a second.
If we put this in here and save up so we can do that with the images as well see the little dots here.
I should mentioned that.
All right.
So I'm going to comment that back go and we're going to have the data indicators on the content slider
as well.
And then for this div here.
Notice that the div has the Tref OK that's not a mistake it's supposed to we're supposed to do that
and we're going to give it a hash one exclamation.
All right we're also going to give it a couple classes.
So we're going to give it a class of carrousel item just like above and let's say we want the background
to be read and then I want white text.
OK.
And then for the H-2 we're going to leave that no class is needed for this.
This div right here we're going to give this a class of carrousel dash fixed dash.
Item.
OK.
We also want to center it because it's going to fix it.
It's going to basically just do just that.
It's going to position it in a fixed position and then we're going to have a button or it's actually
a length that I'm going to format as a button by giving it a classic beat and then I'm also going to
make it the color black.
OK so that is a panel.
Each each slide is called a panel.
So what I'm going to do is copy this whole div right here and then we have what three more so go ahead
and replace all these.
That one ends there.
So say one two three more and I'll save it in a minute.
Let's change up some stuff so this will be two.
This will be three and four.
And then let's change up the colors a little bit.
So the second one let's make it instead of red we'll make it Amber.
And the third one let's make green.
And then the fourth one will make blue.
All right let's save that and then we go.
So we have our heading we have our paragraph in our button our indicators and we can we can slide it
and we can put any type of content here we want and then fix the carousel fixed item is what pushes
this button down here.
If we didn't have this class let's save that let's go to the last one you'll see that it's just right
under the paragraph.
But if you want it down there you can add that fixed item class.
That's what that does.
All right guys.
Those are the different types of carousels that we can have with materialize in the next video we're
going to go ahead and look at the collapsible widget.