All right guys who are in this video we're going to look at the collapsible widget which is basically
like an accordion menu.
So what we're going to do is go to for a collapsable daughter H.T. amount.
And you see we have a UL here and each UL has an ally with two divs.
The first div has the header or the heading and then the second one has the text or the body which is
in a span.
We also have an icon next to the heading.
So first thing we're going to do is give this UL a class of collapsable
and we're going to give it a another attribute called Data dash collapsable and we want to let it know
that this is going to be an accordion type or an accordion collapsable I should probably spell that
right though.
All right.
And then each list item it doesn't need a class.
What we do need a class on that is.
So this does will have a class of collapsable however.
Westons spell that right.
So collapsable Hetter it's hard to talk and type and then let's see for an icon of course we need our
class of material Icahn's doesn't matter what icon we're using we need that.
And then inside here we're going to give it to the group underscore work icon and then for this div
the second div here it's going to have a class of collapsable body.
OK so we have collapsible Hetter and collapsible body.
So what I'm going to do is just copy this list item and let's see if we can ignore this pre-select for
now.
But let's go ahead and just replace both of these list items so one and two.
And then we're going to change this to second.
I will say this is the second area.
And then this will be third.
Let's say this is the third area.
And let's also change the icon so the second one will be the help icon and then the third one will be
the info icon.
All right so let's save that.
And there we go.
And if I click on one of these headings you'll see that the body will show.
And it's only going to show one at a time.
If I if I were looking at the third body and I could the first third is going to go away.
OK.
So that's the accordion type.
And then if we want to pre-select something I noticed when I enter the page they're all closed if I
want one to be open then we could go ahead and do that by adding an active class to the header.
So let's say we want the second one and that's why I had that pre-select comment there so let's save
and now you see the second one is automatically open when we enter the page.
So that's the accordion we also have the expandable type which instead of doing it from scratch I'm
just going to copy this whole UL here and just replace this one and then all we're going to do is change
the data collapsable attribute to expand the expandable
and we'll go ahead and save that.
Now the difference is even though I have the second one open if I could.
The first the second one stays open so we can have multiple groups are multiple content areas open at
the same time where with the accordion it can only be one at a time that's the main difference between
adding accordion or expandable.
All right.
So that's pretty much all there is to it.
We can also add in events so that when it's open when a collapsible item is open we can do something
or when it's closed so if we go down to the javascript and we go ahead and put in our collapsible class
and we call Daut
collapsable and then we can pass and here and object and we can do on the open and set that to a function.
So function and let's just pass and here we'll say alerts
open.
So save that and Ill do it right away because we have one that's pre-selected or two that are pre-selected.
They both have the collapsible class so both will be affected.
But if I open another one it will say open.
It'll give the alert right before it opens.
We can do the same thing one close if I were to grab this and we could do on close and will alert close.
All right so save we get open.
Open.
And if I close the second one now we get close.
All right so we can have something happen in javascript when we open and close these accordion items.
OK so that's it for collapsable.
And the next video we're going to look at feature discovery.