All right guys so we're going to take a look at the feature of discovery widget I guess we could call
it in materialize which is really cool.
So basically if we were to click this button here we get this really cool.
I don't know what to call this really it's just like a pop up with syntax with the heading and paragraph
from that pulsating effect so we can open and close it.
But I have an issue with this documentation because this actually doesn't give us everything we need
to actually create this.
If you were to take this and put it in your age Tim Allen add this J query it doesn't work.
So I'm going to show you how to actually do it.
So in the four underscore or three feature discovery age I'll file it should look like this.
Basically we're going to have our open and close buttons and then we're going to have the mock up for
the feature discovery.
So these two buttons are actually links but they're going to be formatted as buttons.
Let's give them the class of waves effect.
You don't want cap locks locks whatever caps lock.
So waves effect.
And then also we want waves dash light and DTN.
All right.
We want the same classes for
this one here.
Class.
All right.
So we're also going to add in on click event here and we're just going to do it this way where we say
on click and we want to take the top target class
and we want to call DOT tap target.
I like that and then we want to call open.
All right.
And then we're going to actually just copy that on click and put that on this one as well on this tag
except we're going to change this to close.
All right.
And that will actually activate the feature discovery.
Let's save that.
It's not going to do anything yet because we haven't added the markup for the feature discovery for
the buttons and so on.
Or the the whatever that is the floating action button.
So let's go to Steve here and let's give it a class of fixed action button nothing we haven't seen before.
And for the tag we're going to give us an idea of menu and then we're going to give this a class of
beat and beat and floating to make it the circular button and we want it to be large and we want it
to be the color cyan.
OK.
And then for the icon let's say material icons we're going to give it the menu.
The menu icon.
OK.
So if I save that we have our little button here.
Let's see it should be down here and the reason it's on is because I put the word button here that should
be beat.
OK.
Now that moves it down.
Now this div here we're going to give this a class and this is something that's not in that documentation
page.
We're going to give us a class of top targets wrapper and then this does we're going to give a class
of tap dash target.
We're also going to give a color class of Suyin and then we need to give it a attribute of data activates.
OK so we're going to say data activates menu which should match the ID here.
And then this div underneath we're going to give this a class of tap target content and let's also give
it a class of white text to make sure the text is white.
I'm also going to give this paragraph a class of white text
not positive that that's needed.
But I'm just going to put it anyways.
OK.
And then we need another button another folding button down here so this does the one that wraps the
tag we're going to give a class of tap Dasch target Dasch wave and then the tag will give that a class
of beads and PTEN floating.
And also to make it large large and let's make it sign.
And we also want to give it a class of tap target origin.
OK and I'll show you why we have two of these floating buttons here in a minute.
But let's also give this I tag a class of material icons and the menu icon in that should do it.
So let's save that.
And now if I click this button I so open now open is actually going to toggle it.
The Clozaril only close.
OK if I click this it doesn't do anything unless it's already opened then it will close it.
OK so the open will actually toggle close we'll just close it.
Now you notice that we have two of these these floating buttons.
One is in this state.
The other is in this state so if I were to change this icon to see the clothes icon and save you'll
see that we have the menu icon but once I open the feature discovery it changes to close and I can actually
click that and close it.
So if you wanted to keep it like that you could if you wanted to change the color like say red.
So when we open it now it turns red.
OK so you can change the the open state of the button if you want or you can just keep it the same and
it's completely up to you.
But this is the correct markup that actually works and they don't have this in the documentation.
All right so in the next video we're going to take a look at the TOSed component which is kind of like
a kind of like an alert box that pops up and then it fades nicely.
We're also going to look at tool tips and these are both different forms of dialogue's.
All right so that's what we'll get into next guys.