All right guys in this video we're going to look at dialogues so we have toasts and tool tips toasts
are basically kind of like alerts that pop up and dismiss.
And then a tool tip is if we hover over it we'll get a little tool tip over and we can position them
as well.
Now for the toast we're going to add a little bit of Javascript so you can see here we just have a bunch
of buttons we have show.
We have rounded toast and toast with callbacks.
We're going to start with just the show toast.
Now we could put this inside of an on click if we wanted to.
But I'm going to do it the better way which would be to give this some kind of ID.
So it's a we call it toast one.
And then we'll go down to the javascript and we could use vanilla javascript here but we've been using
Jey queries so we might as we'll just use that.
So we'll say TOSed one and we'll say dog click OK.
So when that's clicked we're going to run a function
and inside this function we're going to say materialize
materialized on toast.
And inside here will say I am toast.
So let's save that and let's click that first button and we get this I am toast.
Now by default I think it'll just stay there forever until we actually go down and click it or click
we can kind of drag it away but we can add a duration so let's put a comma here and add a second parameter
of 3000 and save and then click it again and it should go away in three seconds.
OK so this is in milliseconds so 3000 milliseconds is three seconds.
So it's as simple as that to show one of these things for the rounded what we can do here is let's give
this an ID of toast to.
While we're at it we'll give this one an idea of toast three.
And then we'll go down here and
let's just copy this.
So I'll say toast two.
And then all we have to do to make this round rounded is add in a third parameter and say rounded.
So save or click on that and we get the rounded toast and it should go away in three in three seconds.
All right.
So let me just put some comments here for you guys so just say
we're on toast
rounded toast and then we can also do a toast callback.
Meaning that if we wanted something to happen once just once a toast is dismissed and goes away we can
do that.
So I'm going to copy this and we'll change it to toast three.
That's the third button and we're just going to add in another parameter which will be a function and
we can do whatever we want here let's just say a word and we'll say toast.
Dismissed.
OK now you can keep this rounded.
If you didn't want it to be rounded you could just pass in an empty string like that for the third parameter.
So let's save that and let's click the last one here and then once it goes away.
We get an alert.
All right.
And obviously you can do whatever you want inside of this function.
But if you wanted something to happen you could do that.
Now in addition to button clicks we can actually ignites the TOSed from javascript's So it's.
Or we'll just say create
toast by just simply saying actually we'll describe this right here and paste it in and save it now
when the page enters it'll actually run.
So we can do that we can also dismiss them all if we want.
So if I were to click this multiple times we'll get multiple toasts but if I wanted to get rid of them
I would say remove all toes.
And what I want to do is I'm going to use the set time out javascript function and that will allow me
to do something after a certain amount of time so it takes in a function and then it takes a second
parameter of the amount of time to wait.
So I'm going to say two seconds or two thousand milliseconds and then in here I'm going to say materialize
Daut toast Daut remove all.
OK so what will happen is in two seconds after the page loads it'll remove any toes that are visible.
So let's save it.
Let's click this a bunch of times and in two seconds they'll disappear OK I'll reload cooking a bunch
of times two seconds.
They all go away.
OK so this will remove all.
OK.
And again you're not restricted to Jay Querrey for instance we could do if we comment this so.
So if I comment that out let's also comment the one out that runs automatically if I could the first
but nothing's happening.
But if I wanted to do it say documents daunts get element by id grab toast one and we could say Daut
add event listener and we could say on a click than we want to call actual do.
Well we'll just do a function like this.
I'm not going to get to and start using aero functions and stuff even though I know a lot of you guys
do know that stuff.
This is a materialized course.
It's not a javascript course if you are interested in aero functions.
6 in advanced javascript I would suggest my modern javascript from the beginning course but what we're
going to do here is just this line.
OK so this should do the same thing as this just without j queries so if we save and I click it and
nothing happens let's see why is that.
That's because I shouldn't have a hash here because it's get element by d it knows it's an idea without
that hash.
So there we go Snel that works.
All right.
So that's going to be it for the toasts.
Now let's move on to tool tips and there's not really anything we need to do in the javascript for tool
tips.
Everything is done through custom attributes.
OK so we have a bottom tool tip what we need to do is add a class in addition to button tool tips like
that.
And then we add a data position attribute which in this case we want to be bottom.
So if I save that and I click.
Actually we need some content.
So that's going to go in an attribute called Data Dasch tool tip
and this will be the content.
So just say I am a tool tip and now if I click that we get I'm a tool tip and when I hover away it goes
away.
All right now if we want it displayed in a different position where I could do is just going to copy
this whole a tag here and paste it here and then we'll just change the position to top we'll do the
same thing here will change the position to right.
And then here will change the position to the left.
All right so it's going to work the same way except there are going to be in different positions so
that's the right that's the left.
And then lastly we can add a delay if we want so if we hover over any of these they pretty much just
show up right away if we wanted to delay we could add a data delay attribute and set that to milliseconds
we'll say 2000 so two seconds.
So the first one if I hover over it it takes two seconds for the tool tip to show.
OK and just for that one these ones will show up fine but this one will wait two seconds.
All right.
So that's it for tose intuitive dialogs and the next video will look at the material box widget as well
as the slider.