Hey guys in this video we're going to take a look at the material box which is kind of like a light
box.
And also the slider now the slider is similar to the carousel slider version but it's a little different
song and show you how to do that.
We're going to go to four underscore five material box slider door each tiem now and go to where it
says start here.
All right.
So we basically just have a row with two six column divs.
So I'm going to put one material box here and then one on this side one will have a caption and one
won't.
So basically we just have an image tag here and we're going to add our image source which will be IMJ
slash image one dot J Pag.
And then we're also going to give this a class of material boxed and then we're going to give it a with
of 100 percent OK and that's it.
Let's save it.
So there's our image.
If I go and I hover over it you'll see automatically it fades out and it gives us this magnifying glass
icon.
If I click it and then it brings the image into focus so it's gives us a nice light box effect with
almost no work at all just a class and a with.
All right.
Now we want to have a caption what we could do is let's just copy this and replace this image here we'll
put it to image too.
And we still want the material box class and the with but all we have to do is add a data caption attribute
and we'll say this is my awesome photo and save.
And same thing now if I click it you'll see down here we get a little caption.
All right so pretty cool pretty easy.
Next we're going to take a look at the slider.
So for the slider we're going to give this div that wraps around this well.
A class of slider and then the UL will get a class of slides.
OK.
And then the Allies don't have to have any special class we're going to put our image in here.
I mean these image three since we used one into the material box and then the div that goes around the
H3 in the h 5 here we're going to go ahead and give that a class of caption
and let's see for the H5 any of that a class of light and let's do Gray dash text and let's say teks
dash liten 3 so just changing up the color a bit making it a little lighter.
All right.
And then more what I'll do is copy this whole div here.
All right so the caption div and I'll replace this paste.
Then let's throw our image in here we'll do image for and then let's go down here we'll replace this
div again and do image image 5. Jay peg is going to change these captions because they don't make sense.
We're going to do the center one there.
This one will be the left will say left a line caption and this will be the right line caption.
All right.
So if I save that we're just going to see a box here and that's because we haven't initialized it so
we're you to go down to the javascript and we're just going to use a little bit of query here and say
the class of slider.
And then we want to call Daut slider.
OK.
And now you can see we have our image.
We also get these little dots down here we have our caption.
Now the text is not aligned yet.
I haven't added the class for that.
They're all in the same place but let's say for the first image which is actually image 3.
Let's say we want to center that.
So what we would do is add in to where we have the caption class we would say Center dash line.
And let's see this one here we'll put in a class of left a line and then we have right a line.
We'll save that.
Now that one center you can't really see it I guess we could we should probably make this text darker.
So let's do class.
Actually we want the first one to class equal this will slave black and we'll do black for this one
as well.
I'm sorry should be black text.
Otherwise it's going to do the background.
There you go.
So that's centered.
Next one comes in from the left.
Next one comes in from the right.
OK.
So that's a slider.
Now we can add options as well so if we go down to where we have our slider and we pass in an object
we can say indicators.
So if we wanted to not show the indicators which are those dots we'll save that nicely those are gone.
But I'm going to keep that to true.
We can also change the height.
So I think the default is 400.
But if we wanted to do it say 600 and save you'll see that now it's bigger.
We're going to keep it at 400.
We can also change the transition.
The transition speed which is I think 500 by default will set it to two thousand.
So now it takes a lot longer to go from one image to the other.
You know see where it changes
takes a lot longer to kind of fade in.
But the default I believe is 500.
And then we can also change the interval for which the image shows I believe the default is 6 seconds.
Let's change it to.
So I'll save it should stay for two seconds switch to seconds switch and so on but we'll set it to six
which is the default.
So you have a couple of different options that you can use with the slider.
So some pretty cool effects nice components but that's it.
In the next video we're going to take a look at modals.