All right it's you know we're going to take a look at modals.
So we've havock if you have experience with bootstrap then you know what imortal is basically where
we have a button we click and we have this nice little pop up with some content.
Now we can see the modal content right away I have that already here.
Just by taking the div right here and adding the class of modal and saving that will actually make the
content disappear.
OK and we can do the same thing for this down here.
So this div will give a class of modal and save.
That's going to go away.
And let's see did I have another one.
Bottom sheet motile.
So this right here also give a class of motile and it just sets it to hide by default.
All right.
Now we're going to do is go back up to the first one and we're going to work on the trigger.
OK so every modal needs to have some kind of trigger which is usually a button or a link.
So we're going to add of class here.
Let's make it look good.
Little push button put waves effect and waves dash lights and then we also need to put the class of
modal dash trigger.
OK.
In addition to that we need an H raft which is going to go to an ID.
So it's going to be a hash and then I'm going to call it modal one.
OK.
So that is going to look for a motile with the idea of modal one.
So we're going to go down here and give this an ID of modal one.
And that's how it knows to to use that modal.
OK and then there's just a couple of things you need to add here so this div should have a class of
modal dash content and this div right here should have a class of modal dash for her.
All right.
And then this.
OK right here I'm going to make this into a button.
So it's a actually it's going to be a modal action buttons so it will take a class of modal action sort
of kind of be built into the modal.
I'm also going to give it a class of modal close so that it closes when we click it.
Let's do a Wavves effect and let's do waves green and let's do DTN flat.
All right.
So let's see what that looks like.
OK so we have our button if I click it.
Hey it's not working because we actually have to initialize the motile.
So we're going to go down to the javascript
and we're going to put in our J query for the modal class and we're going to say Daut modal cadence
that should be enough.
There we go.
So now we have our modal never OK button if I click that that's going to close it automatically.
Now we have some options we can put in here.
So one is dismissable hand and that's true by default I believe because if I click and I click outside
it closes.
But if we don't want that we can set it to false.
That way if we click and I click outside it does not close.
I have to actually click OK.
All right but true is the default and that's what I'm going to leave it at.
Another thing we can do is change the speed at which it opens and closes so Indurain will be open.
So let's say two thousand and that should open pretty slow.
So you see it comes in it takes two seconds.
The default I think is 300.
And that's really quick.
All right.
And if we want the out duration we can do that as well.
So we'll say out duration 2000 just to test it out comes in quick.
Dismiss it and it goes out slow.
The default for that I think is 200.
We can also add a call back for one when it opens.
So if we say ready we can set that to a function and that function can take in the motile and trigger
and then inside here let's just say console door log and we'll just say motile opened and then let's
also see what we get for modal and for a trigger.
All right.
So we'll save that we'll open up our consul with F 12.
Make sure you're on the console and we'll click and you can see if we get motile opened and this is
what it gives us for the motile.
So basically gives us the div with the ID and all the attributes and stuff and then this would be the
trigger.
So this gives us the actual button that triggered it.
All right so if you wanted to do something with that you could.
So let's now go back up here and see.
So that's just a regular motile.
Now let's look at the fixed footer model.
So I'm going to close this up and let's add to the trigger here.
So I'll say class equals waves of fact waves slides between and we eat our motile trigger.
OK.
It also needs to know which motile to call so that's in the treffen it's going to be the idea of motile
too.
All right so we're going to go down to this div and let's add the ID of modal to and then we're going
to add to this class here modal dash fixed dash flooder.
OK.
And then this div will get the content the modal content.
And then let's go down to the bottom.
After all these paragraphs and go to this div and just like above we're going to give this a mobile
for and then for the button here say Tref equals a hash exclamation and then we're going to give this
class of modal Dasch action also modal close so that it closes say waves affect
waves.
Green and Button flat.
All right so let's save that and see what this does so if we click that we get our fix for motile what
this means is that the footer here that has the button is going to stay fixed and even if the content
stretches outside it's just going to give us a scroll bar rather than making it a large motile.
OK.
So this is good if you want to have like a like a poster or something maybe you want a whole blog post
inside the motile.
So that's what you would use that for.
Now we also have something called the ball bottom sheet motile.
So let's go ahead and add our trigger stuff here.
I'll actually just copy and see.
Scrap this whole a tag here and copy it and I'll paste it here.
Except we want to change the ID to model 3 and then give this an idea of model 3
and let's also give this class in addition to motile we want to add bottom Dasch sheet.
OK and then for the footer we will basically want to do kind of the same thing we did here so when the
copy this whole modal for Dev and just paste that here and then we can save that let's see what that
does.
So what that does is gives us a modal but not middle of the page it puts it at the bottom.
OK so it's a bottom sheet motile.
All right.
So you have some different options as far as how this displays so that's going to be it guys in the
next section we're going to I start to look at some other javascript's stuff some components we're going
to look at parallax and we'll move on to the side Nav. and some other cool stuff as well.
So I will see you in the next section.