All right guys so we're going to start to get into cards which are a big part of a lot of frameworks
slightly bootstrapped for added cards instead of the old panels that they used to use they're just a
nice way of displaying content.
They give you a border or a drop shadow.
You can use images in them links buttons and it just makes things look really nice.
So what we're going to do here is just start with a simple card without a title.
So this is the three underscore one cards dot each time l file.
So basically we just have two divs.
Now before I go into this notice that I have a row here and we're using the grid system.
Basically we have two 6 column divs.
All right.
That's how we're going to display these cards so we have our other six column div.
Then we have another row with two six column div.
So it's like that the whole way down.
All right.
So you can kind of ignore this stuff it's just mapping out our grid.
But for the Cards what we want is one div which is going to have a class of card.
And then here we're going to have a class of card content.
OK and we'll save that and that gives us pretty much the simplest possible card that we can have over
here.
Let's add a color so we'll do a class card and it's given a color of red and we'll even darken it a
little so dark and two and then we'll give this a class of card content.
And we also want to give this white text so that it shows up on the dark red.
See I messed that up somehow.
Let's see.
Oh I put cards content should be card.
There we go.
So now we just have a red background and obviously you can use whatever colors you want whatever text
colors you want.
Now we're going to move down to the card with title that's this one right here.
So again classic card anytime we have any type of cards that will have that class and then we want the
card content.
Same thing.
And now for the span right here you see this is where we put the title it's in a span.
But we're going to give it a class of card title.
OK.
So let's save that.
And now you could see we have our title.
Now these links down here I want to add these links and we want to make these look good.
So this is going to be the action area.
So it will say class equals card dash action and save.
And there we go.
So that makes that look much better gives it some padding pushes it over.
Change the color also makes it all upper case so this is a card with a title and with an action area.
OK so the next one I'm going to look at is a card with an image.
So we're going to go down to this div here and give this a class of card using.
And we're also going to do right here.
We're not going to do the card content just yet.
We're going to do a class of card dash image.
OK if you want to put an image in here you want to wrap it in that class.
We don't really need an alt for the source.
I'm going to use my images folder.
I'm going to use image one dot j peg.
OK.
And let's see that's just the title so give the span a class of card title and then this div here we're
going to give a class of card content OK and then we have our action down here.
Card action so you can kind of mix and match.
I mean you don't have to have an action here but you can if you want just save that suit that looks
like.
All right so the title is going to be basically inside the image.
Now if you wanted the title in here what you could do is you could just kind of bring it down into the
card content like that.
OK.
But I actually like it.
I actually like it up here.
Where was it.
It was under the image.
That'll put it inside the image so we can also have a card with image and a floating button.
So maybe if you wanted like a link instead of having the read more you might want the floating button
link like right here so we could go.
Class equals card and this would be class equals card isn't going to make this a different color let's
say blue dash gray.
And let's say liten dash 4 or make it really light.
And they will put an image in here I'm going to say in the images folder.
I'm g to dot j peg in let's see we're going to show you know what I missed this.
I did this.
This here the lighting and the blue gray.
This should actually be on the card div so I'm going to cut that out and put that in here.
And then this should actually be card image like that.
OK.
And then we're going to go down here and this is where we're going to put our button.
So we're in a class equals member the beats and dash.
Floating class.
And we're going to say Half-Way dash fab so half way fixed action button will add the waves effect and
the waves light in and let's make it blue OK and then for the icon we put an add icon on the plus sign.
So add our material icons class.
All right now give us the button and then this div right here is the card content
we'll save that and that does not look right.
Let's see if we have our card class card image and then our span.
That's the span should have a card title.
Sure some of you guys caught that and will save.
And there we go so we have our title in the image and then we have the little button here.
So that could link to like the in her blog post or something like that.
OK so there's a lot of different ways you can format these cards.
Next thing we're going to look at is a horizontal card which we can put an image on the side instead
of on the top.
So let's go down to horizontal card and the first class are always going to add is card.
And then we're also going to add horizontal.
All right.
And then this div here we're going to have an image so we have to wrap it in the card image and for
the image itself let's go in the images folder and do image three thought jpeg and let's see this.
This right here we're actually going to do a class of card dash stack.
Ok if we want to do a horizontal card we need the stacked class and then the content comes so card content
and this will be the title.
So that will be class card dash title and you're not going to remember all this stuff right away you're
going to have to have something like this.
This sandbox as a reference to go back to to to make sure you have your right classes but let's save
that.
And that's what it gives us.
All right so if we were to make this bigger you can see the images the image stretches out.
And if we make it like really big it takes up the whole place.
OK the whole thing.
And you don't need to have a title in there.
If we were to take that title out in save you'll see that the will move up and it'll take less size
for the image to fill the whole place.
So next we're going to look at the card reveal which is really cool because it will hide the text and
then we can click the read more and it'll then slide up and show us.
So we're going to give this a class we're going to give this just a class of card and then we have an
image so we're going to do class card image.
And let's also do a Wavves effect
waves like these waves and then let's also do Wavves dash.
Block the waves block will make it so that when we hit the reveal the image will kind of get away from
the corner and we'll get sent down through the whole image and give it a nice effect.
All right.
So next thing we want to do is add in the image.
So it's two image for dart J peg and we're going to give this a class of activator.
Now the activator class is just that it'll activate the reveal module.
And when you actually see what it does it'll make more sense.
So it's a activator.
And then this will be the content.
So I will say class equals card content and then we have our title.
All right we'll have an icon.
Let's make this more Virts.
This is going to be kind of three vertical lines and give us a class of material icons.
All right.
And then we're going to go down here and we can add an activator to anything.
So I just want to show you that in addition to the image we give this a class to read more a class of
activator and that will also activate the reveal.
Now down here will be the inside of the reveal so when we click it.
This is the content that will display.
So we need to add the class of card reveal which initially hides it and then it'll show when we activate
it or we reveal it.
And then this will be the title.
So it's a C class equals card title
and for this icon this is going to be the close button because we want to be able to close it as well.
OK and then this here will be actually this paragraph doesn't need anything it doesn't need any kind
of class so let's save and see what that gives us.
All right.
So Carville and if I click the icon OK so the icons not working.
But if I click read more you'll see we get the revealed content.
Let me just see what's going on with this icon here.
All right.
So we want on the card title we want the activator class
ok because the the title or the more verts icon which is this right here is actually wrapped in the
span of the of the title.
So we need the activator on that.
So now if I click it it'll work OK.
And like I said you can add the activator to anything we have it on the image as well.
So if I click that that will reveal it too.
All right so now we're going to moved on move on to the tabbed card.
So go ahead and add our class of card
and this will be class of card content and then our card title
right and then down here we have a div and we want to give this a class of card tabs.
OK so at the bottom we have the card tabs div just like we have the card action if we want we can have
tabs.
And then for the UL we're going to have to give that a class or a couple classes.
One is tab's one is going to be tab's with fixed which is going to kind of spread them across the top
and then each ally is going to have a class of tab
cry and the traffic knows that they're going to tab one tab to tab three.
So what we want to do is these divs down here we want to associate these with those IDs so we're going
to say I.D. tab 1 and this will be the tab too because we want these to show when those particular ones
are clicked.
So Tab 3.
All right.
And then it's you know it's just let's save that.
And then if we go down here we can look at the tabs card.
OK.
So the tabs are working but the content doesn't look right.
That's because this div wrapping it should have the card content that's what adds the padding and all
that stuff.
So save that.
And now that looks a lot better.
Now let's say we wanted to add a background color to this card in the tabs.
What I'm going to do is copy the entire tabbed card which is from there to there and we'll go down here
and let's replace this stuff.
This is all the same thing.
I just we're running out of time here and I don't have to retype it all out but all we have to do is
let's add to this div here the actual card will add a color of orange and we'll say Darkon and let's
give it white text.
OK.
Save that now for this right here this area I want to make this black so we'll go down to where you
want to go down to the UL and we're going to add.
First of all we're going to add tabs dash transparent because you can see that they're white it's white
by default.
So we'll save and now it's transparent and you can see the background color.
But what I want to do is actually make the content black not that part.
I want to make the content black.
So right here we'll say black and let's do actually will lighten it a little bit will say liten dash
for sort of be like a gray ish.
And then let's add white.
It's already white text.
And then we go.
So now we have kind of a Halloween looking card tabbed card.
All right so now we're going to move on to card sizes.
So if we go down here we're going to have three image cards.
So what I'll do.
Let's see instead of just typing all this so let's copy the first image card we did which is right here
card with image.
So grab from here to here and let's go back down to sizes and we'll go to the small so this div ends
here so we're just going to pace that in let's do it for the next one so this div here which ends right
here pace that in the large one we'll paste that in.
Let's change the images.
So the first one will be image five.
Will be six and this will be seven.
All right so if we save that we have our card images.
Now what I want to do is show you that we can actually make the small medium and large just by adding
a simple class to the card div here so we'll say small and save and you'll see it'll shrink it up.
Now it's going to cover some syntax so you might want to shorten your text but Or if it doesn't matter
if it's covered then you could leave it and just click read more go to the blog post or whatever.
This one here we're going to set to Medium.
So we'll save that and you'll see that that gets a little shorter.
I put that on the right medium.
And then let's do small.
I did so also we want to do large OK.
So there we go.
So small medium large you can basically just change the heights of these things.
OK so down here what I want to do is show you about panels and also shadow shadow is separate from cards
you can put shadow on anything but I just figured this was a good place to display it.
Basically a panel is kind of like what we have up here just a border with the drop shadow except it
only takes one class instead of the card and the card content.
It just takes the class of card panel so I can say Card dash panel and save.
And there we go.
All right.
So let's see we're going to add that to all of these.
You know it's a class
card panel.
And this one here.
All right so if you just want like a border and some padding and stuff like that you should probably
use card panel instead of card and card content.
So let's add some colors to these so for this first one here we'll see a blue.
And for this one make sure it's on the card panel class not the actual column.
So for this one let's say indigo and we'll do Suyin and it's to Amber and save.
And now we have a bunch different colors for the darker ones like say Indigo you probably want the text
to be white.
So for this span right here I'm just going to add a class of white dash text and save.
And there we go.
Now for the shadow there's just a couple of classes and there Z depth classes so if we were to do Z
dash dash dash one on the blue and save you'll see there's no difference.
So the depth one is basically just.
Well actually these have a shadow by default so it's going to be like that default shadow.
If we do too it should look a little more prominent as you can see it's now a little more prominent
for this one here.
Let's do Z dash Deppe dash three and save.
And that's even more prominent.
And then for this one will do Z dash depth dash for and that has an even thicker shadow.
OK and I believe four is the highest we can go.
OK.
So that's how we can add shadows and you can do that on buttons you can do that on anything.
But most of this stuff has as that kind of a default shadow that's that's just the material design look.
But you can make that shadow thicker with these ZDF depth classes.
All right guys so this was kind of a long one.
This is because there's a lot of different types of cards that you can do.
So that's it.
In the next video we're going to take a look at breadcrumbs and flooder.