Guys who now are going to take a look at breadcrumbs in footer.
So these are actually components that you usually want to stretch all the way across so noticed at the
start here is actually below the container.
So that way it goes all the way across and it's not restricted inside the container and the breadcrumb
is very very similar to a nav bar.
It's structured pretty much the same way we have our NAV tag and actually just going to give it a class
of grey to change the color and we're going to give it the Nav. wrapper class which just like all nav
bars gets this class.
OK.
And let's also give it a container so that the words aren't stuck up to the side.
OK so that pushes those over and then we have our div here.
Now this I'm actually going to give this div a class of call and s 12.
OK.
So just a 12 column row.
And then for each of these eight tags here we're going to do class equals breadcrumb and that'll spread
them out a bit and just make them look much better.
So it's a class
all right so let's save that.
And then we go so that breadcrumb adds these icons here and it does that by adding maybe four pseudo
class so it can actually put content before we go right here.
So before and you'll see it has the code for the content that will give it the arrow.
So using the the material icons font family the font size they're 25 pixels.
And then the actual text is 18 pixels.
It just adds a little bit of padding and stuff.
So that's a breadcrumb very very easy.
And what's cool is automatically that the last link was automatically lighter than these ones because
you would be on the instance the Bradd profile.
All right then you would have this go to your users page which displays all your users and then your
home page would be here.
All right so let's let's now create a foreigner or so you can see I just have just blank footer tags
here.
We're just going to create this from scratch.
So there's a class we can use called Page Footer.
OK.
And we want to give us a color or I'm going to make it gray and I to say dark and dash 3.
So I'll make it a dark gray and inside here let's put a container and let's use the grid system so we'll
put a row and let's do let's see what we want to do.
We'll do 12.
So we want it stacked on small screens.
We also want the call class.
So call us 12 and let's do all 6 so large six.
And inside here we'll put in age five and let's just say about us and we'll give this age five color
we don't have to do this stuff but I figure we'll just kind of do this throughout the course so that
you're constantly reminded of how to add colors and stuff like that how to lighten it all that all that
good stuff.
All right so give it great text and let's lighten it up.
Say Leitung three.
And then under the age five I'm going to put a paragraph with some dummy text on just going to do Lorem
20 tab which will give us some dummy text so we'll save that.
See you know what let's do six.
So that on medium screen it's also six columns and then underneath this column we're going to do the
next one which will be it will have the class call.
It'll have let's do as 12 and let's do let's see em for.
Yeah we'll do em four but let's offset it by two because we have 6 4 which is 10 and we want to offset
it by 2 so we'll say offset dash em to dash and 2.
All right.
And then and here let's put in each five again and let's say Lenk So this will be just a list of links
We'll also give this a class of gray or I'm sorry gray text and let's see.
Actually this should be text liten since it's just text it's not the background to the same thing here.
K and see underneath that let's do a UL and we'll do a bunch of lies to say Ally times for using Amut.
And inside the I'm going to have an eight tag.
So having a tag in this will have a class of white dash text
and let's make this the we'll just say link one.
All right.
So I'm actually going to just copy that line.
And we'll go ahead and paste isn't pretty or will format these so we don't have to worry about that.
If you're using prettier and let's change this to four
three and two.
OK so those are links.
Now I also want to have like a copyright area underneath.
So we want to go.
Let's see where do we want to go.
We want to go under the container
also under the container which is right here and we're going to put a class of water dash copyright
and we'll put another container in here to restrict whatever's inside of it and then inside there we're
just going to say copyrights and I'm going to use the Ampere's copy semi-colon which will give us a
little copy symbol 2018.
And then underneath that we'll just put in a tag with the class of grey text.
And let's also do text liten 3.
And we also want to align it to the right and when to say Dot right.
And inside here it's not going to really go anywhere.
I'll just put a hash and then inside the actual tags we'll just say.
Terms and Conditions.
And there he goes.
Now we have a little flutter now I think it would look better if the copyright area was a little darker
or just a different color.
So what I'm going to do is in the copyright class still do Grey.
But let's say Darkon dash to and save.
All right so I think that yeah it looks better.
Yes so that's it.
So we have a photo or if I make this really small it'll stack on top of each other because we use the
s 12 class here and we have quite a bit of space between the two because we set this one to be medium
for and then we used an offset of two.
So it's kind of pushing it over a little.
We could have just did another six like M6 and say but see how it's it's too close.
I wanted to push it over a little so it's good to set that offset.
All right guys so that's going to be it for this video in the next one we're going to talk about basic
form and input.
So once we do that we'll move on to the more fancy stuff with sliders and some javascript functionality
and so on.
All right so I will see you in the next video.