All right guys who we're going to start to look at forms and inputs and we're going to be doing this
for this lecture and the next one.
The next one will do.
Some of the more fancy stuff but this is the file called Three underscore three forms dot HMO.
All right so we're going to close that up and we're going to go down to where it says Start here and
we just have a form with some divs and then inside those divs we have an input and a label.
OK now materializes one of those frameworks where the the the inputs actually look pretty decent without
having to do anything at all to them.
There's no materialized classes or anything it just looks like this by default with the exception of
the text area which doesn't.
But for these like for instance the textfield there's not really anything we really have to add here
as far as classes or anything like that.
We have an input with a placeholder an ID the label has a four attribute which should match the ID that's
not materialized It's just standard HVM owl so that if you click on the label it'll actually refer to
that of that field.
All right one thing we do want to do is wrap these divs or add to the divs the class of input field
and save.
And let's see what that did.
So if we go and we look at the input field div which is right here let's see what that includes It makes
it relative.
It gives it a margin top.
So it kind of moves it down a little bit but that's that's about it.
I think it may be used in job for javascript for something but I think that's about it.
So we just want to make sure that we add that class for all of these divs.
So this will be class input fields.
Now for this for this example I want to show you how to how we can add a value.
This is just standard reached him.
So let's say we wanted the value of whatever Jaun at gmail dot com save and that will be filled.
And then to disable it we just want to add a disabled
disabled attribute like that in a class with an attribute and save.
And now we can't edit that but that's not materialize I'm just showing you how it looks and materialize.
Nothing we did here is specific to the framework.
All right.
Now for the text area you can see this doesn't look right compared to the rest of these.
So what we have to do with text areas is we need to add a class
of materialized text area
dash text area.
All right so once they do that and they save now you can see the text area looks good.
And let's also give the div a class of input field.
All right.
Now this next one is an inline field.
OK.
Which it isn't right now but we're going to make it into an inline field and we do that by adding to
this class or adding to this div a class of input field just like the rest but we're also going to add
the class of inline.
All right.
So by doing that we'll be able to make this in line.
And that should be Dasch field input Desch field in line and then we use.
Now you can see it's on the same level as the text.
OK.
Or the label.
Actually it's on a label it's just the text here.
The label is this actual number sign.
And you can see it moves up when I click in it which is pretty cool.
In fact any of these if we don't have a placeholder.
So for instance let's go to the name and remove the placeholder and save now the label is right on the
input and if I click it moves up OK it moves up and down.
So I'll leave that placeholder off just as an example.
So that's in line.
Let's see.
Let's go to the icon prefix if we want to add a prefix.
First of all let's give it the input field div and then we're going to go right before.
This is for a telephone number.
So I'm going to put in I tag with the class of material icons and then we're going to use the phone
icon.
OK.
Now that alone looks crappy.
So we want to add to this material icons class prefix and save and now it kind of pushes the input over
and it puts it in place.
All right so now what I want to do is look at some validation.
Now this is just UI validation it's looking like stop us from submitting the form or anything but let's
say this email address right here which is this input.
It has to be an email address and it's going to go off of the age of 5 validation because we have type
e-mail.
So what we can do is we can add actually first of all we need to add our input field class or this won't
work right.
And then we're going to add a class to the input of validate.
Now just having that if I were to put something in here that's not an e-mail address and click out.
You'll see that the line turns red.
Now if we want a message what we can do is where the label is.
We can say data Dasch error equals.
And let's just say
invalid.
And then we can save data Dasch success equals valid.
So we'll save that.
And now if I click and I put something that's not valid and click outside we get the text invalid.
If I put something that is a valid email address and then click outside we get valid.
So we do have some UI validation we can do without even having to touch javascript or anything like
that.
All right so that is pretty nice.
Next we're going to look at select lists.
OK now what are you going to do here is we just have a div.
Give it the class of input field and let's give this select some options.
So I'll say option actually we'll just add let's say option times for tab and for this one it's going
to be disabled because it's just like the type.
Kind of like the title.
We're going to make it selected by default and it's just going to say select option.
OK.
And then for the options we'll just say one doesn't really matter.
Option 1 2 3 option 2 and option 3.
Okay.
And then if I save this notice that we we can't see it you don't see any select list.
That's because with materialized when we use a select list you actually have to initialize it in the
javascript.
OK with Jay query so we need to go to the bottom down here where it says javascript's start here.
OK.
Notice we are already in the document d'arte ready for Jay query.
This obviously is just for the dropdown for our menu right here.
This is on every page but what we want to do is we want to initialize the select with us and we do that
by using Jey query and just taking the Select that's on the page and we're going to call Daut material
underscore select like that it's going to call that special function.
And now we can see it.
And if I click it we get the dropdown.
OK.
So we need to add that in order to initialize this.
And it also initialize these other selects that we have which we don't we actually don't have any options
for yet.
So the next one I want to show is option groups.
So what I'll do is actually just copy the select list we just put in and let's just let's change this
to multiple select lists just so we know what it is.
Actually no this isn't a multiple select.
This is this is option groups
option group select and what we want is just different groups of options.
So let's take a here story here and let's say actually you know let's get rid of this
and then let's do opt groups like that should give us a tag I guess.
M-ID isn't going to work with that so it should be opt group and then we're going to give it a label
of let's say Option Group 1 and then we want to wrap a certain set of options so we'll just take one
and two and wrap that.
OK and then let's actually just copy this whole thing.
Paste it there.
This will be group 2 and then this will be three and four that so let's save and now if I were to click
this we have Option Group 1 we have two options option group 2.
Ok so you can kind of separate your options into groups.
Next thing we'll look at is multiple select So what I'm going to do is copy the regular select we have
and just place it in there and then all we have to do to make this a multiple select is just as on right
here multiple night class multiple.
But just a multiple attribute.
And now we can go ahead and select different options.
Kind of like a radio box inside of your select list.
All right.
So speaking of radio let's do those next.
So we're just going to go ahead and put in
we're going to put in some paragraph tags in each one I want an input and this is going to have a type
of radio.
OK so we don't need a name
actually.
Yeah we'll just keep the name.
So we'll say this is for gender since it's an input radio we should have a name I.D. we'll see say male
and let's put a label a label for say so label for whatever the idea is which will say it may not may
al will go like that.
All right so there we have one radio button now just copy this and this one will be female.
And we'll save that.
And there we go so we have our radio buttons if we wanted one to be checked by default.
Obviously we could just put a check to attribute that's just standard now.
Another thing we can do is we can change how the Although Phil looks so it takes the whole thing up
if we want we can add to the radio input.
A class of with Dash gap and save.
Now if I check this one see that looks different and has the gap around it.
So we can change how that looks as well.
All right.
So next we're going to look at checkboxes so very similar We're going to put in our paragraphs and let's
say inputs.
Type is going to be a checkbox and see let's say ID.
Each team will go out and just put some languages in here or technologies for name we'll just say tech
and let's put a label you know save for HVM how and save.
Now we have a little check box and it has that cool animation by default.
So it's copy this paragraph and I want to put a couple more put three more and then this one let's make
this C Ss
and for this one I'm going to just make this one checked by default.
Just kind of give me a couple of different examples.
That's checked.
And then for this one let's call it J.S.
and what I'm going to do is give this one a class of filled dash in and save.
And now this one it has a different effect.
You see how it doesn't flip like the default.
It just kind of it fills the whole thing and dark and it doesn't do the little flip.
And then for the last one here we'll make this ph P
and what I want to do is disable this one so I'm just going to put in disabled and save and you see
that checkbox is disabled.
So just a couple of different options that you can do with your checkboxes.
All right so those are the basic form elements.
Next we're going to get into more fancy things like Sliders and ranges and things like that.
We'll also be working with javascript a little bit.