So in the last video we looked at some of the just the basic input fields like just text inputs text
areas select lists.
Now we're going to look at things like switches range sliders file uploads and we're going to also do
a little bit of Javascript and Jay query to initialize stuff and also give you show you some options.
Because some of this stuff can take options as well.
All right so we're going to start off with the switch so if we go where it says start here this is file
3:4 forms underscore to daughter aged male and for the switch.
I just have a set of divs here and we're going to add a class of switch and inside the switch we put
a label and we don't actually need a four attribute inside the label we're going to say disable and
put an end to it.
So this input it's actually going to be the type of checkbox because each Jim'll doesn't actually have
a switch input so it will be checkbox and then we're going to put it to check out
like that.
OK.
And then what we do is put a span underneath and give it a Class Scott class of lever OK nothing inside
just the span and then we can put in the table.
So you have to structure it like this in order for it to work so it's save.
And that gives us a little switch and we can switch it on and off.
So this is something that is common on like mobile apps.
Now the check is what turns it on.
If I were to take away checked it'll be disabled by default but we can still turn it on.
All right.
Let's see so I have disabled switch here that would just be the same thing except it wouldn't have checked
OK so that's a disabled switch.
So now let's take a look at file input.
So this is the standard looking each time I'll file input and you can see here I just have an input
with the type of file.
So I have the text input with the type of text underneath because what materialized does it makes it
so that when you choose a file that saves vs code setup file we want this right here the name of the
file to be put on the text.
Ok so what we need to do is first wrap this div or wrap this in a div called Fylde dash field and also
input Dasch field and I forgot the class.
All right.
And then this div here we're going to give a class of button because we want it to look like a materialized
button and down here this div that's around the text the input text we're going to give this a class
of file paff wrapper.
And then the input itself is going to have a class of file paff and a type of text.
So let's save that.
And it should look like this.
Now once we choose a file it gets put onto that line which looks really nice.
I really like the look of materialized file inputs are going to reload that to get rid of that file
name and let's move on to the slider so we have the input type range which is actually an H team out
element but it looks really cool and materialize if we wanted to add to it like a man and a max value
we could say men equals zero Max equals 100 and all we need to actually add to the inclosing element
the class of range field
OK.
So now when I slide it you can actually see the number as it pops up which is really cool when I let
go it goes away.
All right.
So next thing we're going to look at is the date picker.
OK so this is actually going to take some javascript.
I don't think there's anything we need to really add here aside from the input field class.
Yes so all we need to do now is go to I mean right now it's just a text field right with an idea of
date.
So let's go down to our javascript
and we're going to say in net date picker.
So we're going to use a little bit of a query.
It should have a class of date picker and then we're going to say Daut pick a date.
OK that's the name of the function takes in an object of options and we just make sure we have that
class C date picker.
No we don't.
So we just want to add that as a class
OK so go back down here and there's this quite a bit of options here.
So for instance we have an option called select months and this will create a drop down to control of
the month let's say.
True.
And let's actually save that and if I click we're going to get something like this.
So we have our our calendar basically we have our months and then if we click the years we'll see actually
oh you know what we can add is an option is select years
and we put this as a number let's say 15 and now it'll give us up to 15 years of date.
OK we can also add the option of to day.
And if we said that to today a string of today let's see what that does.
So that's going to give this right here it's going to say today and we can just market OK which is pretty
cool.
We can also add the clear actually the clear it's there by default do we even need today.
We might not even need this.
No we don't we don't need that.
We'll see what else enclose it by clicking outside of it.
We can also make it so that it can close when we select a date so it doesn't close.
Let's go ahead and do that.
So add an option here of close on select and we'll set that to true soon now.
So now if I click here and I select the day it just closes automatically so you can set that to True
or false it's false by default.
All right so that's the date picker.
Now we also have a time picker so we're going to go up here and let's add a class just like we added
the date picker class we're going to add time picker and then we're going to go down to the javascript
and we're going to grab it with Jay query
OK and the function we want is just like pick a day we have pick a time
OK that takes in an object and we can have different options in here.
So if we save that it should work.
If I say choose a time actually it's this one here and you can see it's at 12.
Now I want the default to be the the now time where ever time it is right now so we can see default
and set that to now and let's save.
And now if I go and click on the field it's going to have the time right now.
All right.
So some other stuff we can do is we can change it to a 24 hour clock if we want.
So if we say 12 hour and we can set that to false so now you'll see that it's a 24 hour clock.
OK but I don't want that.
So you could either just get rid of the option or set it to true.
You can also change the text.
So for instance the done text we have the done text we have the clear text
and we have apps we have the cancell text.
So that would be this is the done the cancel in the clear so let's say done I want it to be go clear.
I don't know.
I will just test it out we'll just say a race and then canso will say leave.
So let's save let's go back and then we go race leave go so you can change that up.
But I'm going to just leave it at the default which was OK.
Clear actually only I don't think we actually need to uppercase it that's done in the styling.
Try that.
And there you go.
All right.
We can also do auto close with this so if we choose a time it should auto close.
If we have that option.
So it's a little close.
True.
And I'll choose a time and it closes automatically.
All right so that's the time picker.
The next thing we're going to look at is let's go back up here.
It's going to be the character counter.
OK so right here we have this text field which has a label of post.
I wanted to count the characters like you would on like Twitter or something where you can only have
whatever it is 120 characters and it shows you the amount of characters so to do that.
All we have to do is add to the text field a data length property and let's say this can only be 20
characters and we'll save and let's click in here and right away it's 0 to 20.
And I can start typing as soon as I get to 20.
It turns red.
OK.
So that's pretty nice functionality just by adding this right here this attribute value.
So now do the auto complete.
So what I have here is just a text in a text input called fruit.
What I'm going to do is add a class to the text input and I'm going to call it auto complete
and then we're going to go down to our javascript's and from here we want to initialize that.
OK.
So to do this we're going to take the autocomplete class and we're going to call Daut auto complete
and pass in an object and then it's going to take in a data object.
OK so this is where we want to put the text for the data.
Now this is fruit's I'm going to say apple.
And we just want to set these to null by default.
So orange
and I'm just going to copy these down.
So say orange
say Strawberry's
peers and plumbs.
All right.
So we have our data and we can actually set a limit
so let's set a limit of 20.
And I think I think that's good.
Let's save and let's go down here and let's take in a and then we go.
So anything that has an A in it in this list will pop up and obviously you can do like a fecche request
to an API and get some data put it in here whether it's your own API or an external one and you can
have auto complete.
So if I put a p it's going to narrow it down to anything with a P.
I put a p p narrows it down to Apple.
And if I click Apple it's going to put that right in.
All right.
So really nice feature.
You can also change the minimum length for the auto complete to start.
So if I say min length of the fault is 1 but let's make it two.
So now if I put an A in like this yes that doesn't mean length or this should be an upper case at all.
All right so if I put a.
Nothing happens if I do P though it does K because it takes a minimum of two to start the auto complete.
All right guys that's going to do it for this video in the next video we're going to get into tables
as well as media.
So embedding images responsive images videos things like that.