All right guys in this video we're going to take a look at tables and some media elements like images
and embedded videos so tables they actually look pretty good by default you can see that we have three
tables here.
No classes or anything.
This is just what they look like by default in materialize.
All right so that's the first table.
The second one I'm going to give it a class of striped and if you're familiar with bootstrap it basically
does the same thing.
It'll make every other row a light gray color.
OK so that looks pretty nice.
Nice and clean.
And then this third table I'm actually going to do a couple things too.
So first I'm going to give it a class of bordered and see what that does.
So what that does is it basically puts a line underneath each row.
OK so gives you a border for each row.
We can also give it a class of highlight.
If I do that initially you'll see it looks like there's no change.
But if I go in I highlight over a row it'll turn dark gray or light gray rather.
All right.
So it allows us to do that.
Another class we have is responsive table.
So it's a responsive Dasch table and save.
And notice that it completely changes the way it looks it basically puts the headings on the side here
and then it puts the data in a column.
All right.
That way no matter how small this is we can just have a scroll bar and we can see all the different
columns and all the data.
All right.
Now in this case these tables only have three columns so this doesn't look bad.
This actually looks better than this in my opinion.
But imagine if there were five six seven columns it would look horrible all squished together.
But if they're responsive you would have these nice rows and you can just scroll through.
All right so it doesn't look the best but it's very very difficult to get a table to look good on a
small screen.
OK so that's tables.
Next thing I want to do is look at responsive images.
So first thing I'm going to do right here is just put in an image let's say image slash image one dot
j peg and save it.
And by default it's just going to give us the full size image which is huge.
We have to scroll over to see the whole thing.
Now if we want to restrict this let's say we want to wrap this in a column.
So what we're going to do is put a let's do 6 column div and then just take this image here and let's
put that up here and save and it's still basically bursting out of its container.
A six column div ends like right here.
So what we want to do is constrain it into its container.
So to do that we give it a class of responsive dash I am g and save.
And now you see that it's restricted into its container.
OK if this was let's say a and 8 column actually will do a 12 we'll just do a full column and you see
it's constrained inside.
OK.
Now we can also make circular images so if I were to take this and just add a class of circle and save
it makes it a circle or an oval shape which looks really cool.
If we want to do a video or an embedded video rather I'm going to just paste in I-frame for a YouTube
video it's just my channel trailer and save it.
Now I have it set to 853 by for 80 and you'll see it just goes off the page I have to scroll over if
I wanted this to be responsive and restricted to its container I could wrap it in a class called video
dash container.
All right.
So I'll just grab this and we'll just move this up into here and save.
And now you can see it's restricted no matter how big or small I make this it's going to show the whole
video.
All right.
And then for this last one here the video element I don't actually have a local video to use but I'm
just going to show you the mark up.
So what we would do is have a video tag with the class of responsive dash video
and we wouldn't put the source here what we would do is inside the video we'll put a source tag and
then on that will put the source attribute and it would be set to some video it could be an MP 4 MP
4 or an API or something like that.
All right.
And we just want to give this a type of video slash and then whatever the type in this case an MP for.
All right so if I save that that nothing is going to show because I don't have the video.
But if we were to put a controls attribute here you know see the controls are in there.
All right.
And if you want to try putting a video locally inside your folder that's fine.
So not much to do here.
There's not too many different table classes.
Not as many as bootstrap media.
Pretty pretty self-explanatory.
Just use responsive image response video and they'll get restricted to their containers.
All right so in the next video we're going to take a look at chips and pagination.