All right guys who in this video we're going to talk about what are called chips in materialize.
And we're also going to look at pagination so chips are basically like tag's if you see a blog post
and it has tags at the end basically containing key words about that post.
Chips are good.
A good way to display those.
All right so let's see we had a blog post about web design web development and we had some keywords
here.
They're just wrapped in single divs.
What we could do is give these each a class of chip.
All right so give that a class.
This one will say class chip and this one will also give a class of ship and just doing.
Now if I save you'll see that that looks pretty nice.
So if we have this at the bottom of a post it looks nice it's a nice way to display tags.
Now we can also make it so that we can get rid of them we can actually close them out.
So again if we were to give these class of chip and I'll just copy this div here and will add it to
these.
And then also have an icon.
So this will do class and will give it a class of material dash icons and clothes.
All right so let's grab that and put those here as well.
If I say we have our little X now just doing that isn't going to make them work it's not going at all.
It's also not going to make them look right.
You also want to add a class of clothes here in the actual tag.
OK which we don't usually do but in this case we do so let's save that.
Now Yosi they look much better and we can actually close the chips.
Ok they come back if we reload because obviously we're not like persisting data or anything like that.
But yes we can close that and close the chips up.
All right we can also use images with chips so I'll just grab one of these divs here and add the class
and then we could add an image so say image slash image one dog j peg.
And for this one let's do image to
and for this one will do image three.
So if we go ahead and save that now you see that we have our chips so we have little images.
A good reason to have this would be for avatars if you were to have people and you had their little
avatar there and maybe even just one on a blog post the author or whatever.
So we can also have inputs where we can have auto completes and we can actually add chips to the input.
A good way.
A good reason for this would be a blog post form where you are adding these tags and maybe you had a
list of.
Or a database full of tags that you wanted to come up automatically.
So we would have to do is take a div and go ahead and give it a class of chips dash input.
And if I save that nothing's going to happen we're actually going to have to add some javascript's So
we're going to go down to where we put our Javascript.
And from here we're going to use a little Jey query and we're going to take that chips was it chips
Desch input and we want to call Daut material underscore shit like that.
And if I save it you'll see that it just gives us a line teks line.
And if I typed something in and hit enter it turns into a chip and we can actually get rid of them as
well.
So really cool.
There's actually quite a few options we can as well if we put some curly braces here so we could put
our placeholder
takes a string so we could say enter a tag and save in a C now says enter a tag.
We could do a secondary placeholder
that should actually be secondary uppercase P placeholder and we'll say plus tag and save.
And what this does is if I add a tag and enter you'll see that.
Now read here it says Plus tags so every time I enter it'll say plus tag after it.
All right.
We also have autocomplete options.
So it's a auto complete options.
And here we can put an object that takes a data object and let's say HTL Actually it should be in the
form of a string so aged him out and set that too.
Now it's a success
and let's say javascript.
All right.
So if I were to save that and I would start to type.
Each team now would just click in here.
So you'll see we get the dropdown if I do see we'll get we'll see SS and Javascript will come up because
they both have a C like s than just C Ss and if I click on the dropdown it'll get added as a tag.
All right.
And I think I think that's pretty much it as far as really useful options.
Now one other thing you can do is you can add an event for when you add a chip.
So let's say add inserts to uppercase will we'll add chip event.
So if we have our chips inport
or chip dash and what we can do dot on and then we have an event called Chip Daut add and then we put
a function here for when that happens.
And this would take in an event in the chip and let's do a console log.
All right.
And I'm just going to put some back ticks in here I'm going to use a template string so that I can put
a variable in my string.
So say you added a chip and then here will put a variable so we can use this syntax is E-6 javascript
syntax and we can say Chip dog tag.
All right so now if I add something here let's say hello.
Actually it's opened up our console with F 12.
So say hello and hit enter.
That didn't work.
Oh I forgot the dog should be classed ship in port.
Or is it chips.
Yeah I guess it's chips and put so.
Hello.
There we go.
So you added a chip.
Hello.
We say test.
You added a chip test so if for some reason you want something to happen in your javascript when a chip
is added you could do that.
OK could get added to a database or you know through an API or whatever it is that you want to do.
All right so now we're going to take a look at pagination which is pretty easy it's just a couple of
classes we need to add.
Basically we just have a UL with a bunch of allies within a tag.
And the first and last one have icons.
OK so they have tags.
So what we'll do is add a class to the UL of pagination.
And this first list item here I'm going to give a class of disabled
and we're going to give this an icon this is going to be the one the left icon.
So it's going to be Chevron underscore left.
And of course we need to give it to the class of material ikons
all right and then each each list item here we're going to give a class of waves dash effect.
OK.
And I'm just going to copy this and each list each beginning list tag I'm going to add that class to
And then for this icon here we're going to give it a class of material icons
and we're going to make this one a chevron underscore.
Right.
So let's save that.
So there's our pagination now.
You'll have an active page number that you were on so let's say we want to to be the active.
What we would do is just add the class of active and save.
And now I can see that that's active.
And the waves classify you see if I click it will give it that effect.
All right so it's as easy as that to create pagination in your UI.
Obviously you know with your back and programming or whatever it is you're doing you'll have to add
that logic but this gives you the UI.
All right guys.
That's it.
And the next video we're going to take a look at prae Lowder's.