All right guys now we're going to take a look at prae Lowder's which are like animated spinners and
you can see I have one here already.
The reason that I have this here and it's already it's already has all its classes because there's quite
a few classes that you need for it to have one of these spinners and they didn't want to just have you
watch me type them all and they're pretty repetitive.
We have the circle circle three times but this is a standard preload or and I'm going to get to this
I want to show you how to change colors how to change sizes and so on.
But before we do that I just want to look at the progress bars.
OK so we have determinant progress bars and indeterminant So we're going to start with the determinant.
So this div here we're going to give a class of progress.
We basically just have a nested div and then the second one we're going to give a class of determinant
and then we also want to give this a style attribute because we need to set a with K.
So basically how full Do we want this to be let's say 70 percent.
So that gives us a 70 percent full progress bar.
If we were to do 50 percent that will be half full.
OK now the indeterminant if we were to give this a class of progress just like the one above.
Notice that these are in six column divs are six column divs inside of a row.
And then we'll give this a class of indeterminant
and save.
So this is kind of like a horizontal preload or we don't need a lot with or anything like that because
it's not actually a progress bar it's more like a preload or type pre-loading that looks like a progress
bar.
All right so now let's move on to the actual spinner preload.
So like I said this is the bare bones that you need to create this.
You even need the active class if I get rid of that.
You'll see that goes away.
So make sure you have that.
Now this says small red so what I'm going to do is to change the size to small I'm going to have the
class small save that and you'll see it shrinks.
And if I want this to be read then I'm going to give this a class or add to the class of spinner Lehre
and we're going to say spinner dash red dash only and save.
And now you see it's a red spinner.
OK so what I'm going to do now is just copy the whole preload or wrapper to the ending div here and
go to the next one and paste that in.
And we're going to change.
This is standard blue so I'll get rid of the small class and change this to spinner blue only and save.
And now it's just the medium size or the standard size blue.
OK if we want a big yellow one we can go ahead and paste this in and change this to big and then change
this to spin or yellow.
So these are the only classes you really need to change if you want to change the look of the spinners.
All right.
Now we can also do a spinner with flashing colors and this has quite a bit of markup.
What I'm going to do is copy this last one we did the big yellow and paste this in here.
All right.
Now the the idea is to have one pre-Lie one wrapper and then to have a bunch of spinner Lehre class
divs inside.
So I'm just going to spaces out a little.
So this is the first one.
And let's say we want the first color to be let's say green.
So we would change just not to spin or green only but to just spinner green.
All right.
And then we would take this OK.
Not the preload.
But everything in it.
And then add that down here and we'll change this one to let's say blue.
So we want the second color to be blue.
And then we'll go ahead and paste in another one and we'll change this one to red.
All right.
And then going to save this.
And now we have a spinner that's going to change colors.
OK so it's going to fade from green to blue to red.
OK and I know that's a lot of markup just for that one spinner but you need that if you want it to flash
different colors.
All right so that's it.
Not too much to this.
Pretty simple.
This is actually going to be the last video on CSSA components.
So the next video will start to get into javascript's OK or the next section.
And we're going to look at the Carousel.