All right guys welcome to YOUR NEXT PROJECT.
This is a theme called Mad Men or material admen and it's an administrative panel that has quite a bit
of interactivity I wanted to do a project where we could actually have things that happen in the UI
and we're going to use some custom Jay query for that.
Now this is not AJ Corey or javascript of course so I'm not going to be going over it in depth but I
did want to just add some snippets and just some pieces of code that would do some cool stuff.
All right we're also going to use some of the JavaScript materialize components like the preload or
the the toast dialog things like that.
So first thing I want you to notice is if I reload the page we get the little preload or for a second.
So one second will go by and then the page will load once the page loads.
Notice the numbers they count up from 0 to whatever these numbers are for the visitors the blog posts
and so on.
We also have a little progress bar.
This actually doesn't actually do anything but it's just there for show then we're using a chart from
canvas J.S. which is a chart library.
This is just dummy data.
It means absolutely nothing.
It's just I wanted to have something.
If you look at a lot of the different admin panels they have stuff like this.
It's just there for a show and obviously if you build your back and you could hook that up to it.
All right.
And then these comments over here if I click approve or deny we'll get a little toast dialog that says
approved or denied.
If we go down here we have a quick To Do list that actually works.
So if I put in hello and enter it'll actually get added and we'll get a little dialogue.
OK we can also remove them as well.
So we're going to do that with Jake worry.
We have a recent post table right here and that's the main page.
OK.
Other than that we have our post page which is basically just a straight up table with some pagination.
Same thing with the categories and each page will have the little preload or only one thing I forgot
to mention on the dashboard is if we go down to this button here we can choose to add up at a post a
category or user and these will all open modals.
OK we even implemented S.K. Ed. Which is a wizzy wig editor that gives you like a Microsoft Word type
feel.
OK and if we wanted to add a category we could do that.
And then on the single free source pages like posts if I click the plus it'll just do the post.
If I go to the categories page and click it it'll add the category.
We have our comments comments will have the users image the comment and then a check and a x icon and
then the users will have the user image as well and we can add a user here.
Not literally as a user but show the modal.
OK we also have a nice looking side navigation with the background image that the users image and some
links.
And then I even created a logo a logon page so if I click logged out it'll go to log in HD a malware
we have this nice looking log in form and even if we type something in here it doesn't matter what it
is it will redirect us to index him which is our dashboard.
All right.
So all in all it's going to be a pretty big project probably the longest one of course because there's
quite a bit of interactivity and user functionality.
It's not really hooked up to anything it's known.
There's no back end or database but just to give you some cool effects in the UI.
All right so let's get started.