All right so we're going to get started here and we're going to start the same way we did the last few
projects we're going to create a new folder.
I'm going to call it Magin which is the name of the theme and I'm going to grab the files from the theme
starter so we're going to grab all those copy them and we're going to paste them in here.
OK.
And then we'll open up our folder with our textedit or I'm using VS codes I'm going to do open with
code.
OK.
And we're going to start off with our index each team now as usual.
And for this project we're not using Fonte awesome so we don't need to bring that in.
We're going to stick with the material icons.
So let's go down to the where the H one is and we're going to go ahead and get rid of that and we're
going to start our navigation.
OK but before we do that let's go ahead and open this with live server or of course you can just open
it with your just open the page to him I'll file.
All right so I'm not going to use exact side by side because I want this to be kind of big and I want
enough room to code so I'll have it kind of like like that.
All right so let's start with the navigation.
So the navigation is going to be a blue color.
So we're going to put a nav with the class of blue and we're going to darken it so it's too dark and
dash too and inside the now we're going to have a container to kind of contain everything in the nav
bar.
Then we have our NAV wrapper class and inside that we're going to have our brand logo.
So a tag with brand logo.
And actually we'll just have this go to index each team how it's going to be quite a few pages in this
project.
Most of them are really easy though the dashboard is where the most the most code is going to go.
So it's easy for the logo we'll just say Madeleine and I'm going to close the sidebar for now.
So we have our brand logo under that.
We're going to have our button collapse so a with the class Button dash collapse and we want to have
our special data activates attribute for the side menu
and we'll just call this side nav.
OK we're also going to do in addition to button collapse we want this to actually show all the time
which is something new that we haven't done yet so we're going to use a class called show dash on dash
large.
OK.
And we want it to the right and then inside the tags we're going to put our menu icons so and I tag
with the class of material icons
and we're going to use menu.
OK let's save that and it should look like this.
OK now this is always going to show no matter what even if it's big like this if it's small it's still
going to show and it's still going to open up our side now.
OK so we might as well initialize our side Wow while we're here so let's just do that side now.
So we'll just take our boughten collapse collapse
and just simply call side now.
No end there.
OK.
Now we don't have any links yet so it's not going to show anything.
Now underneath the button collapse underneath the tag here we're going to put in our well and we're
going to give it a class of right and we're also going to give it a class of hide dash on dash.
Mead Imedi dash and dash down so high on medium and down screens.
All right.
And then we're going to have an ally.
This is going to have a class of active.
This is the dashboard link so say dashboard and we're going to put our link around this.
So this will be in a tag.
And then let's couts move this into here.
And then this will go to index dot aged him.
OK so that's our dashboard link.
Now let's copy this down.
Get rid of the active though we don't want that.
And then this is going to be to the post page.
So it's going to be posts that HDMI all the posts.
And then let's copy this one down so we'll do it.
That's three four five and that should be good.
So we have dashboard posts categories
which will go to categories that HVM how they will have comments.
OK so the Sugo comments start each time.
And then we'll have users.
So those are our main links.
Now we're going to do is put in our side now.
So let's go under this.
Well you know just put a comment that says side now and we'll do a UL.
Now this you all has to have an idea of side dash now because that's what we use with the data activates.
And I'm also going to give it a class of side now.
OK and inside here we're going to put an ally.
And then we need that little area at the top that has the background image.
It has the the person image.
All that stuff.
So it's going to be a div with the class of user dash view.
And then we'll have a class of background and that's where the actual background image goes.
OK so I have an image of an ocean in fact I'm going to bring all of the images in and you can get these
from the project files for this lecture.
So bring over my folder my project folder go into the I Am G and I'm just going to bring these images
in.
OK and again you can get these from the project folder and just to show you what they look like excuse
me what they look like.
We have our ocean image and then we just have four people so person one person for Guy that's all the
images will need.
So the background is going to be the ocean image.
So what we need to do is just put in an image tag and we're going to point this to I am just slash ocean
dot Jay peg.
OK and then underneath that background Div. we're going to put a in a tag.
It's not going to actually go anywhere but this is going to be the image of the person and it's going
to have a class of circle OK for the source it's going to be I am g and we're just going to use person
one dog j peg.
All right.
So let's save that and let's see what it looks like so we have all of our links if I click this.
We have our little background and the little image of the guy.
So underneath the guy or actually to the side we want to have the name and the e-mail.
So we're going to have a couple other links here.
So let's do this
let's do the name so we're going to see a span of a class of name and then it's also going to have a
class of white text because of blue background.
So we'll see.
John Doe All right.
And if we look at that you'll see it actually puts it underneath.
OK and then we're going to put another tag and for this one we're going to do another span's going to
have a class of e-mail as well as white text.
OK and then we're just going to say Jadot at G-mail dot com.
OK so now we have a little name and email and image.
So underneath that this ally right here we're going to start our links and we can actually copy what
we have up here.
So I'm going to grab the dashboard.
I'm going to grab actually all of these and copy them and we'll paste those in.
Now we're going to get rid of the active class on this ally.
And I'm also going to put an icon just for the dashboard so right here in the link We're going to put
in I tag with the class of material icons.
And we're going to use the dashboard icon.
OK so if we look at that it should look like that.
OK.
Now underneath the last link the last list item the user's right here we're going to put a divider member
that's going to be an ally within a tag that has the class of divider like that.
It doesn't actually need in a trough.
And then underneath the divider we're going to have another ally and we're going to give.
We're going to put in a tag here with the class.
This class of sub header
and this is just going to say Account controls.
OK.
And the only control we're going to have is the logo.
So we'll put one last ally and let's do an eight tag I'm going to give it a class of waves effect.
We haven't used that in a while.
And then let's have it go to log in dot each team.
And then the text will just say Lago.
OK and that should be our now bar and the side now of hey something's not right here.
See
see Carl controls some Hatter
that's weird he's at Gray.
So we have users and then our divider
Ah the divide shouldn't be a link it should be a div.
Sorry about that guys.
And you see a lot of the stupid little mistakes like that.
I don't like to edit out because it's just real life stuff.
You know we do this all the time.
I'd rather have leaves little things like that and then have a cookie cutter course that that is just
not realistic it's you know every time you create something you're going to make mistakes.
You're going to have typos so I figure leave it in as long as it's not something that's really going
to throw you guys off.
All right so let's see I think that that's pretty good for now.
I mean there was quite a bit to do with the side now and all that.
So I think I'll stop the video here and in the next video we're going to work on the four boxes that
have the stats for the post and the users and all of that.
All right so I'll see you in the next video.