All right so in the last video we created the nav bar and the side navigation.
Now we're going to do the stats on the dashboard and we're going to start off by just putting static
numbers and then we'll do the little jay query magic to make the numbers go from zero to whatever the
number is.
OK so let's go under the nav and I'm just going to put a comment here and we'll say Section stats.
OK so just like with all of our projects we're going to do a section with the classes section and then
a custom class of Section Dasch stats and we also want to center everything.
OK so in here we're going to do a row.
Use the grid system we're going to do actually different sizes for our different columns for each size.
So for a small we want a full width so as 12 for medium sized screens we want 6.
So we wanted to be basically split in half and then on large screens we're going to do three.
OK.
So three across.
So make sure you get that and then what we'll do is put in our card panel for the first one.
This is going to be for the post.
It's going to have a class of blue.
We're going to lighten by Warren.
We're going to have some white text and make sure that it's over.
All right.
And then inside here we're going to have an icon.
So we're going to do material icons and the icon name is insert underscore a motor car and that'll give
us a little alarm.
What is it I think it's a little pencil I think.
I'm not sure.
Oh this is the monthly visitors.
So it's like the little face.
All right sort of the icon will do an H5 and we're going to do monthly visitors and then we want an
H 3 and this is going to have a class of count.
OK we're going to use that in the Jay script that we're going to write.
And for the count we're going to say twenty thousand three hundred.
OK.
Under that we're going to have our progress bar so it's going to be a divot the class of progress if
you remember those.
And it's going to be gray.
And then we're going to do Litan one.
OK.
And then inside here it's going to be a determinant progress bar so it's not going to be the animated
one.
So we want to give it the class of determinant.
Spell out right.
Determinant and then it's going to be white.
OK and then we need to give it a style with the with that's how we can we can show how much it's filled.
So I'm going to say the width will be 40 percent.
What do they do here style equals should be with colon.
40 percent like that.
All right so let's save that and should look like this guy.
Now we're going to do is the blog posts.
So what I'll do is copy the column.
So the Stiv here we're going to grab that.
And let's go ahead and paste in.
That's two three and four.
So if I save that it'll be four cross OK.
And then once we get to medium screen you'll see it will be two across and then on small screens one.
So now let's change up these cards we're going to go to the second one which is going to be the blog
posts.
So I want to change the color from blue going to change it to.
Actually it's not going to have a color because it's going to be white.
So we want to get rid of these three classes.
So it's just Card panel and center.
And then the icon is going to be mode underscore and it will give us that pencil icon OK and then for
the text here we're going to say blog posts and then for that count we're going to do 1 0 5 ok for the
progress bar let's do 20 percent
ok except I'm going to change the C liten right here.
The class where a determinant is we're going to change it from white to blue because now it's on a white
background.
I'm going to light it by one I like that.
All right.
So if I save that it should look like that.
So the next one is going to be the comments.
And this one's going to be blue so we can leave all those styles and stuff.
We just want to change the content.
The actual comment is going to be mode underscore comment and then the text will change that two comments.
Let's change the number to twelve hundred and then we'll leave the with a 40 percent that's fine.
So if I save that there we go.
Now the last one is going to be the users and that's going to be white like this one.
So what I'm going to do is actually copy the blog post right here the blog post column.
And just to replace this one.
So enough to retype all the class color classes and stuff.
And then for the icon that's going to be supervisor account a supervisor underscore count some weird
names for these icons and then users.
And the number of users will be 350.
And for the progress bar let's say 10 percent.
So save.
And there we go.
All right so what's the one thing I want to do is make the icons bigger.
So for each material icons class I'm just going to add medium.
The medium class that will make them a little bigger.
And save and there we go so looks pretty good.
All right so now we're going to do is the counter effect.
Now we're going to be using Jay Querrey for this and a lot of you guys that know me that follow my YouTube
channel and other courses know that I'm not usually a fan of Jay Corey but the reason for that is because
I think it's over used for things like Dom manipulation for Ajax when you could use the GPI or you could
use Acciona or something but something like this is exactly what I think J.A.G. should be used for as
little widgets little animations things like that.
OK.
So the counter we're going to it's going to be a couple of lines of code we're going to use the anime
property or the animate method.
So let's go down to our javascript and let's say counter.
OK and I'm not going to go crazy with the explanation because this is not a J.A.G. course and it's just
a little snippet of code.
I would suggest taking this snippet and putting it somewhere in case you want to use it in another project.
OK so we're going to take the class of count because remember all of the H threes with these numbers
have a class of count and we're going to loop through them within each loop K and each takes in a callback
function.
And then what we're going to do is take this meaning whatever the current count Ron and then we're going
to call Propp and we want the counter
property and that's going to have a zero default.
And then we're going to call Daut animate and case this is what makes the magic happen.
So this animate we're going to pass in an object and we're going to pass in counter colon.
And then this dot text.
Ok this text is going to get whatever the text whatever the number is.
OK whatever's in that text and then it's going to take in a second parameter.
So after this curly brace we're going to put another we're going to put a comma and then another sort
of brackets or curly braces.
And this is the options.
So we have duration as an option which I'm going to set to one second which is a thousand milliseconds.
We can also do easing which is like the effect and that's going to be swing and you can look more on
the J.A.G. documentation if you want for other options.
And then we're going to do step which is going to be a function and that takes in a parameter of now
and then we're going to take the text.
So this was this Daut text and then we're going to round up so we're going to use the math object.
And then Seele which rounds up and then pass and now.
OK.
And that's it.
That should actually do it.
So let's save and there we go.
So now within one second it just counts upwards.
It starts at zero and counts upwards and if you wanted to take let's say three seconds we could change
that.
And now it will take three seconds to count up.
OK but that's way too long.
I think one second is good.
All right.
Now I think that we should also implement the preload or functionality as well.
Now the the way that this works is we're going to initially hide every section K on the dashboard every
every area is going to have a class of.
Right so what I'm going to do is go to the very top of the script tag right here.
Before we even do the document dart ready and I'm going to set all the section classes to hide and there's
a lot of different ways you could implement this.
But this is just the one I chose let's do let's say Hyde sections.
OK so if I save that everything's going to go away.
I mean right now we only have one section but it goes away.
And then what we're going to do is wrap everything including the document dart ready in a set time function.
Ok so if we say set time out and that takes in two things One is a function of what's going to happen.
And then the next is the amount of time we want to wait for this to happen so I'm going to say one second
or 1000 milliseconds.
All right and then we're going to take everything here.
So this all of this and cut it in we're going to put it in the set.
Time out.
All right.
And then inside the set time.
So we want to then fade in the sections.
OK so we're going to go right in the document ready.
We do want to do it when the documents ready and we're going to say show sections OK so we can do that
by simply saying DAW's section and we could do a show but I'm actually going to do fade.
And I think it's a better effect.
So we're going to do that.
So if we save it's going to wait a second and then it's going to fade in.
OK.
And then the count starts the count isn't going to start until it's actually finished until you can
see it.
OK now that's that's great but we don't have our preload yet so let's do that so at it.
We're going to go up to our mark up down the very bottom here and we'll say premotor.
OK.
So let's see.
Let's actually grab it from materialize
see.
Where is it.
Premotor.
So I'm going to grab.
I want it to be that big one.
It's going to get this right here
right.
So freeloader big active spinner.
Only this is fine so I'm going to use this.
Now if I save it and we take a look.
The freeloaders is going to be its relative right but we want to position it absolute.
So well we'll have to do is edit our CSSA So remember we have the main CSSA file for custom stuff and
I'm also going to give it a class of loader like that so that we can grab onto that civil say Dot loader
and then we're going to send it through position.
Absolute and I'm going to set it from the Top 40 percent and from the left 47 percent and we'll save
it and I can see it's in the middle.
OK so if I reload it waits a second and then loads.
But the freeloader is still there.
So what we need to do is when everything comes in when the section comes in we then want to hide the
freeloader.
All right so what we'll do is let's say hide freeloader
So remember it has a class of load so grab onto that and we'll say fade out.
All right so save it pre-loading there sections come in and the preload or fades out.
OK so it's as easy as that.
And like I said there's there's a million ways to do stuff like this.
This is just one of them.
If you have a different way that's fine.
I just want to get it working and and you know as long as it has good performance.
All right so that's going to be it for this section or the arms or this lecture or guys in the next
video we're going to start to work on the chart area.
We're going to work with canvas JSL a little bit.
So I will see you in the next video.