All right guys so in this video we're going to set up the part of the dashboard that has the chart in
the comments.
So what we're going to use canvas J.S. which is a chart library a javascript chart library age HTML
5 library.
But we're not going to learn about it.
It's just too it's just to fill a spot and make it look good.
This is a materialized course.
Again we're not going to be learning about javascript charts.
So what we need to do is just include the script and then I just have some javascript that I'm going
to pop in and you can actually grab from the resource files.
So first thing we need to do is bring in charge.
Now I'm not going to download it and include it locally.
I'm going to use their CD and so I'm going to go to our index each time I'll file.
And let's go down to where we have our scripts and we'll go right after the materialized script and
right above our custom script tag and let's say script source and it's going to be HTP ass Kandis.
Ass dot com slash assets slash script slash canvas office canvas J.S. dog men dog.
J.S. Okay.
So that's going to bring in the script for us.
Let's save it and make sure we have no errors in the console.
We had F 12.
All right so that should be working.
Now we're going to create a file in our JSA folder called chart.
J.S. OK and this is where we're going to put our chart data.
Again if you if you're really interested in canvass SJS I'd suggest looking at the documentation.
It's pretty good actually you see
charts gallery.
So these are all the different types of charts we're going to do a line chart
and see something like this simple line chart yes.
Also this is the exact chart I want to use.
Good.
I couldn't find it before but you can see they are already in.
They include the script which we just did and then we want a chart container wherever we want to put
the chart.
So we want to live like this.
So I'm actually going to just copy that.
You guys can just type in and it's a simple line but let's go to right under the stats section and above
the pre-loading the freeloader is always going to stay at the bottom.
So right here we'll say section and we'll call it visiters that's what this chart is mimicking So it's
a section Daut section Daut section Dasch visitors.
All right.
And then let's see what else did I want to do here.
I want to make this I want to give it a light blue background so we're going to do blue and then liten
dash four.
All right.
And then we'll put a row and let's do call as 12 am 6 so it's split in half on medium scratch screens
and then l 8.
OK so it's bigger on larger screens.
And let's see we're going to put a card panel here
so in this card panel is where we want the chart container so I'm going to paste that in and it's going
to be 300 pixels height height 100 percent with.
OK.
And then we're going to have another column.
So after this one we'll have another column so call it will be as 12 medium 6 and then l4.
OK and this is where the comments will go.
I'm not going to do it just yet though but I'll just put a comment that we're going to put the comments
here and cry Christ let's save that.
Now if we look at it we're not going to see any chart yet because we haven't added that that code.
So what we'll do is go to our Candis Web site here the sample chart.
And we're going to grab everything that's in the script tag tags so from here to here the window dot
on load.
And we're going to copy it and we're going to go and pasted in chart.
OK so this is basically this is our char Except they're going to change the text to daily visitors and
we'll save it and if we go back to our page here OK we're not loading chart.
So we need to do that.
So let's go back to our index aged him now and we'll go right down here and see script source is going
to be in our J s folder and then chart.
James
OK.
Now this actually took me quite a while to figure out what was going on here.
If I remove the preloaded functionality where we wait that one second.
This chart looks fine once they added the freeloader it messed up.
And the reason for that is it's loading the dimensions and stuff before the page loads because remember
we're waiting that that extra second for the page to load.
So to fix this all we need to do is go into our chart J.S. and see where we actually call chart render.
We just need to wrap that in a set time out and basically have it wait one second just like we did with
the rest of the sections.
OK so a set time takes in a function
and also a time which should be one second just like should match the other set timeout and then we're
just going to move this in here.
OK so now if I save now the chart looks good.
OK so make sure you do that.
In order for this to actually look normal.
All right so that's all set.
Now we can close up charg As we shouldn't need that anymore and we're going to go down or go up rather
to where we put the comments in the latest comments.
OK so this is actually going to be a collection so remember are you well with the class of collection.
And it's also going to have a head or so we want the with Dash head or class.
And I'm also going to give it a class of latest Dasch comments.
Okay.
And then here let's put a list item with the class of collection dash Hetter.
And we'll say latest comments like that saves you what it looks like.
All right.
That should actually be an age five
so age five.
There you go.
Now below that we're going to use an avatar collection.
So are a collection item.
So it's going to be an ally with the class of collection dash item but it's also going to have a class
of Avatar came.
Remember we did all this stuff in the sandbox so we're going to have an image of the person and it's
going to be a circle.
So we want to give it a class of circle.
The image will be an I am g slash person person one dot J Pag.
So if I save that we get our little guy there and let's give them a title so under the image will have
a span with the class of title and we'll give them the name John Doe.
OK then we'll have his comment.
Now I will add the comment.
I don't want it to display the whole thing because the comment could be very long.
So what we'll do is give it the class of truncate which automatically truncates whatever the text is.
So if I say Warum 30 tab and save it doesn't show off all of the 30 words it truncates it which is what
we want.
OK I actually want that.
That's right.
But then under the paragraph I want a couple links to approve or deny.
So we're going to do a with the class of approve spelled it wrong and they approve and say We're also
going to give it a class of green dash text.
See it's not going to actually go anywhere let's say prove high and then we'll put a little pipe character
here space and then let's do another link.
So we'll go like that and we'll change this one to D-NY
and we'll change this to read text
I save that but they should say denie.
All right so now we have a prove and deny.
So now all I'm going to do is copy this list item
and we'll do two more and then we'll just change the second one to person two will change the name here
to say Steve Smith.
This next one will be person three.
And let's change the name to let's say Allen Williams and save.
And there we go.
So now we have our latest comments.
Now we want to add the functionality where if we click approve or deny it gives us a little toast dialog
that says comment approver comment denied.
So we're going to use Jay curry for that so we're going to go down here under the counter and we'll
say comments
prove and deny so very easy.
All we have to do is grab onto the class of proof and we'll say when we click that was so when we clicked
that we want a function.
Now it's a link so I want to stop the default behavior so we passed in an event parameter here and then
we simply do e Daut prevent default like that.
OK.
And then and here is where we want to do our toes.
Remember the materialize Daut toast and it takes in a message which will be comments
approved and then it takes in a second parameter of the time it's there for which will be three seconds.
OK and then we'll do the same thing for nice we're going to I'm going to take this.
Copy it down and then just change the class to deny and we'll change the message to comment denied.
All right so let's save that and let's go and click approve and then we go comment approved or clicked
deny comment denied.
All right.
It's in use easy is that.
OK so in the next video we're going to start on the next area which has the quick to do's and the save
the post table the recent posts.