All right guys so in this video we're going to do the recent post table and we're going to do the To
Do list.
OK I'm not sure if we're going to get to the functionality of the To Do List.
We'll see how much time we have.
So let's go right below the section we just did with the chart.
Still above the preload or the preload or and all the Modals should always stay at the bottom.
OK after all the sections.
So we're going to say section and we'll just call this recent posts and to do these.
OK so we'll say Section Daut section and we're going to also give it a class of just Section Dasch recent.
OK and then we're going to do a row inside that row will have a column and we're going to do as 12.
So that's stacked on mobile devices l 8 k so large screen will be an 8 column and on medium screens
it will be a six column div.
And inside here we're going to have a card and we're going to do our card content
and we want to have a title so we'll do a span with the class of card title and the title is just going
to say recent post or recent posts.
OK.
And then underneath that we'll have a table and we're going to do a Streitz table so we'll give it a
class of striped and then we'll have a T head.
So our table headings which will have a table row and then some th's which will have a title and a category
and then just a blank th.
Because that's where you go outside of the shoe go right here so that that will be where the details
button goes.
All right so under the t head let's put our t body and inside here we're going to have some table rows
so this will have a table column which is a T tag and we'll say post one
and then the category I'm going to say web development and then we want another D.
This is going to be the details button or details length.
So we'll put in a tag and I'm going to give it a class of between blue and white dash 2.
OK and it's going to go to details dot each team male
and let's see.
Actually no it's not going to go to details are going to go let's see actually details aged him out.
And then here we'll just say details like that.
All right so the rest of the posts will be for the rest of the rows will be the same except the content
so I'm just going to copy the TR and put it in two more times and then this one will be post 2 category
will say graphic design.
And then this one down here let's do post 3.
And we'll keep web development for the title or for the category.
All right so this is what it will look like.
Now on this side we're going to have to do.
So let's go create another column so this column right here ends here at this div So we want to go right
under it and do another column as 12.
And on medium screens it will be six.
It will be split in half.
And on large screens it will be four
now the dues are also going to go inside of a card.
So we'll see a card
card content's they'll have a title which will go in a span so card dash title and we'll just say quick
to do this.
All right then we're going to have a form I'm going to give an ID of to do dash form no action.
We're going to use J.A.G. to grab onto the form by the ID.
All right.
And then we'll have an input field div
and inside here we're just going to have an input no label just the input.
And I'm actually going to give an ID so that we can grab on to it.
And Jay query of to do.
And then we'll add a little placeholder that will say add to do like that.
OK.
And then if we save that that's what it will look like.
Now I'm going to add some initial to do's.
They're going to be in a collection.
So under the form we're going to have a well with the class of collection.
And let's also give it a class of two do's and then inside here we're going to have a list item with
the class of collection item.
Now they're also going to have some secondary content.
We want the X so that we can delete that to do so we're going to put a div and we'll put a title say
to do one and then we want in a tag with the class of secondary content.
And we also want to give it a class of delete so that we can grab onto it.
All right.
And then inside that this is just going to go to a hash and an exclamation it's not going to go anywhere
but inside the tag what's inside the tag we're going to have an icon so material icons and it's going
to be a close eye soon to be an X.
So if I save that it's going to look like this.
OK and I'll put one more so.
Copy that.
Ally and will just change that to to do two and say.
All right.
So that's the mark up.
So I guess we have time to do the functionality.
Now one thing I forgot to do is I want the body to have a darker color than these white cards.
OK so what we'll do is on the body tag we're going to have a class of gray and then lightning dash for
and save.
OK that way the body has kind of a gray that light gray it looks a little better with the white card.
All right.
So now let's get down to our javascript's area.
Let's go down to here and let's say quick to do this.
So what do we want to do here we want to basically catch whatever we type into that input field so we
can actually get get us we can call a submit function on that form.
Now remember we gave the form an ID of to do dash forms.
So we're going to say to do form on submit then we want to run a function.
OK we want to pass an event parameter here because we want to stop the form from actually submitting
and we do that with the dog.
Prevent
default like that.
OK and we can just console Daut log and test.
So they will just say one two three.
So now if I go down if I open my console with 12 click on the console tab put something in here and
hit enter or we see one two three.
OK.
Next thing we want to do is basically build our output.
OK now we can get whatever we type in this with Jay Querrey.
So if I do.
Jay queery I remember that input we gave it a class or do we know we gave it an ID of to do so we could
say to do.
J.A.G. to do it.
VAL.
And that'll give us the actual value.
So if I type in hello and I hit Enter it's not going to work.
Oh I forgot the hash the id to do now if I do.
Hello enter we get hello down here.
So we basically just want to build up our dorm so that we can put whatever we have here into this list.
OK so the way that we're going to do that is by creating a variable called to do or not to do output
and I'm using Consta musing S6 and tax and then I'm also going to use a template literals so we can
use back ticks.
These are not quotes.
These are back ticks to the left of your number one key same key as the till day.
And then in here we're going to build out our list item.
OK and it should look just like this.
OK like one of these to do so I'm just going to copy this one of those allies and put that within these
back ticks OK now we don't want to do one as the actual to do we want what I just showed you now when
you used template literals which are what these are called these these tactics we can use this syntax
whips to put in a variable.
Now in this variable I mean this could be any expression actually we're going to use J Querrey So we're
going to say Jay Querrey ID to do and we want the value the value.
So we want to go like that and that'll put whatever the value is there.
OK.
Now up until this point it's just putting all this in a variable it's not going to output it yet.
So what we want to do is we want to take the two Doo's class which is to see what is it right here.
So to do as class is actually the UL.
And we want to append our new to do into this and we can do that with the J Kuri method append.
So that's what we'll do we'll go ahead and write under the variable.
We'll say bring this back we'll say class to Dewes which is the UL.
And then we want to append into it.
Our output variable which is the new ally.
OK hopefully that makes sense.
And then finally we'll just have a materialized toast that says that the two had been added
and we can do that like this.
I will say to do added and three seconds.
All right so let's save that and give it a shot.
So I'll say test and enter and then we go to do at it and it gets added down here.
Now we want to do is we want to be able to delete these.
So we want to be able to click on these axes and have them delete.
Now since there's multiple X's we're going to be using the class to delete.
And there's multiple ones of those.
So we have to use what's called event delegation.
So we're not going to call the actual event on the delete class we needed to call it on a parent of
it.
So I'm going to use the to do as you well.
So we'll go down here and let's say delete to do's.
So I'm going to take that well which has a class of to.
And instead of doing a dot click we want to do a dot on click.
This is how we can do event delegation.
So dot on click and then we want to get the daily class OK which is if we look up here each of these
tags around the icon they have a delete class.
OK so that's what we're targeting.
Now we want to do is pass in a function for when we click on to delete.
OK.
And this is going to take in about an event parameter and then we're going to prevent the default
and then to to actually remove We want to take this meaning whatever one we click.
We can use this and then we can do Daut remove.
OK.
Now when we click on a delete it's the actual tag that we're clicking here so if I do this don't remove
it's going to remove just the tag.
Let's let's see what that does.
All right so if I click it it just it just removes the X which obviously isn't what we want.
So we want to go this Daut parent which moves to the next level up.
All right now the next level up from the tag is the div..
OK because we have a div.
That's not what we want to remove.
Either we want to move the ally which is another level up.
So we want to do dot parent dot parent dot remove.
And that should do it.
OK and then we'll do our materialized toast like that and we'll just say to do removed and save.
And now if we go down and click the X it goes away we get to do removed we can add it to do and then
delete it.
All right so that functionality is done.
So now let's just add a simple footer.
Real quick before we end this video.
So under the section we're going to do for her will be for our dog S. dot blue dot Darkon dash too and
we want to do white text and we want to center it.
OK and we're just going to put a paragraph we're going to say Mad Men panel copyrights and then we'll
do ampersand copy 20 18.
And there you go.
All right so in the next video we're going to do is add our little floating button here so that we can
add posts.
It'll take us to the post categories and user page things like that.
I'm sorry not the page is going to open up a modal for each one.
OK so we'll get to that next.