All right guys we're almost done with the dashboard part of this theme so we need to add our floating
button down here to add the post users in categories and that's all going to happen through modals.
So let's first create the button so I'm going to go right under the flooder that we created in the last
video and let's say fixed action button and we're going to give these.
It's going to be a div with the class of fixed action dash PTEN and then we want in a tag with the class
of beat and floating which will put it down in the corner.
I'm also going to give it a class of between large which will make it bigger and then a class of red
which will obviously make it red.
OK we don't even try here.
And then inside the tag I want the plus icon.
So we're going to do I don't.
Material dash icons.
And in here we're going to say add.
Ok so if we save that you see now we have our little plus icon it's going to stay in that position no
matter what.
Now I don't want to actually push this for anything I want to hover over it and then have the other
buttons pop up above it to add a post a user or a category.
So to do that just like we did in the sandbox we go right under the Atallah and put a UL.
OK and in this you will have an ally and then we'll have an eight tag with a class of DTN dash floating.
It's also given a class of blue.
All right.
Now this is actually going to trigger a modals so I'm going to put a hash and then say post dash motile
and remember any button or link that triggers a modal also needs a class of modal dash trigger.
OK so that's a must.
And then inside here we're just going to have another icon.
So we'll say material icons and we're going to use a mode underscore at it because that gives us a pencil
icon.
So if we save that and I can see as a hover over it we get the pencil icon.
All right.
Now let's create the other one so I'm going to copy this list item and we're going to do two more.
OK.
The second one is going to trigger the category modal.
So we're going to change this to category motile and we're going to also change the icon from Mode edit
to folder figure folder is a good image for a category.
All right.
And then this last one here is going to be it's going to trigger the user mode.
And for the icon we're going to use the strange supervisor account icon.
So supervisor dash sorry sorry underscore account.
So if we save that now we hover over it now we have our three different icons and each one will trigger
the modem.
All right so let's start off by creating the post motile.
Now all the models are going to go at the bottom they're actually going to go under the free loader
actually do it above the freeloader.
So right here we'll do post motile or it's actually the ad post moto.
So we're going to do a div with the idea of post motile because that's what we pointed to.
I'm also going to give it a class of motile.
All right.
And then here we're going to do our mobile content.
So we'll have an H for will just say add post and then we're going to have a form with no action.
And inside the form will have our input field.
OK.
So that in the input field will have an input and we're going to give us an idea of title say the post
is going to have a title and then a label for title and then the text will say title.
All right.
Now we're also going to have a select list for categories so this will also go into a div with the class
of input field.
And then here we're going to say select We don't need an ID and a name so we can get rid of that.
And inside here we're going to do our first option which is going to have no value it's going to be
disabled because it's basically just like a title and it's going to be selected and it's just going
to say select option.
OK.
And then for the rest of these we'll do our options I'm just going to do value 1 1 2 3 and 4.
And then for that that the option text will put the category name.
It doesn't really matter I mean these aren't hooked up to a back end or anything.
So we'll see a graphic design
and let's do and three will be let's say tech gadgets and then we'll do one more for and that will be
other.
OK.
And then we'll have a label underneath.
So label and this will just say
category.
All right and then under that div we'll have one more input field.
And put field div and in here we'll have a text area which doesn't need.
Actually it is going to have a name and I'll show you why in a minute.
And then the ID we'll be Fati we don't need the calls and rows though.
OK.
So we have a text area now and materialize your text areas need to have a class of materialized textarea
in order to look good.
And I think that's it.
Let's go underneath and put a label and this will be body.
All right so now we want to do is go under the form and we're going to have a model for her.
So it's going to be a class with modal Forder.
And inside here we'll have an eight tag.
And let's actually let's give this a class of modal Dasch action also modal Dasch closed that way it
closes when the button is pressed DTN to make it a button and then we also want blue and lets do white
dash text and then we'll just say submit.
All right so let's see what that looks like.
So if we go and we click on the pencil icon looks and it's not going to work yet because we didn't initialize
the Modals So let's go down to the javascript there actually it will do we'll go like right here
and we'll say Jay Querrey class motile is going to call Doughton modal.
All right let's see if that works.
And there we go and post.
Now we also need to initialize a select I forgot about that.
I think it's a little weird that we have to initialize it but I guess because of the cool effect it
gives.
So it's a select and then we want to do Daut material underscore select.
All right so now we can have our select option.
All right.
Now the post I want to use a wizzy Wigg editor we're going to use S.K. editor which is very easy to
implement if we search for S.K. editor CDN that way we don't even have to download the script.
All we have to do is simply put this in our file.
So I'm going to copy that and we're going to put that right above the canvas on the chart J ass script
and then all we have to do is whatever the name of our textedit are.
I put body for hours.
We have to just put this in.
So I'm going to copy this line here.
You can just type it if you're not on this page and let's go down and just put this at the bottom.
So we'll go under the delete here and paste that in and then change this to body because that's what
we used for the name and save and now hopefully if we go and we go to the post model there it is.
Now we have this text editor.
Awesome.
All right so the other models aren't as difficult.
So what I'm going to do is just copy the the ad post motile that we just created.
So again the copy that we're going to go underneath paste it and this is going to be the category ad
category modals So we're going to change this to category and we're going to change this.
And then all it's going to have is a title so we can get rid of this to select input field the body
get rid of all that we just need that one field and then that should do it.
So it's save.
And now if we go and we cooked the folder icon we get ad category.
All right so now let's do the user.
So for the user what I'm going to do is copy the category motile.
All right.
And we'll paste that in and we'll change this to user.
Change this to user mode.
I will say add user.
And then we're just going to have a few textfield So this will be the same name
so we got name and then we'll do e-mail password and confirm passwords so for fields so will change
just one to email type ID email the text email and for all right.
And then this stuff down here will be password
password.
I know this stuff is this is kind of tedious but I mean it has to be done.
All right.
And then this one here is going to be typed password
but the ID I'm going to do password to.
And then for the text let's say confirm password and change the four to password 2.
All right so we'll save that.
Let's take a look.
So if we go to the little user's icon add user name email password confirm password.
All right guys so that's it.
We're done with the dashboard which is the most difficult part of this project.
We have a little sidebar so things are looking pretty good.
We have some some user interactivity here.
So when the next video we're going to start on our resource pages we'll go ahead and create our post
pages and the categories and all that stuff.
All right.
So I will see you in the next lecture.