All right guys in the last video we went ahead and finished up the dashboard so everything here is working.
We have our To Do lists that we can add stuff to.
We have our chart.
We have our free loader when we load that page.
We have our little floating buttons with them with the Modals So now we're going to move on to the inner
pages.
So let's start with the Post Page The Post's categories these are going to be pretty easy they're basically
just going to be tables.
Same with the comments end users but there'll be a little more they'll be a little more markup in those
because we have to add the images and so on.
All right.
So let's go ahead and add some new pages here.
So in addition to index each team our We're going to create posts not aged him at all and we might as
well just create the rest of the pages we need so it's two categories not that glorious but categories
daughter aged him.
Let's also do what else do we need here let's do users
let's do comments
and we're going to have a log in page to log in age aged him.
And so that's I think that's it.
And that's it for now at least.
So let's close all these up except for posts.
That's what we want to work on.
Now what I'm going to do is copy everything in the index each team I'll file just so we can have like
the things that are going to be repeated like the nav bar and all that stuff.
So we're going to paste that in.
OK.
And let's let's go down to the javascript thing get rid of some of the stuff that we don't need so I
want to keep the freeloader on every page so we're going to keep like this part where we hide the sections
where we have the time out where we fade in the sections and fade the loader out.
We need this for the side navigation and we need this for the modal selects.
Yeah we'll keep that count.
We don't need that.
We can get rid of it and once we do all this the post page is what we'll copy for the rest of the inner
pages.
OK we don't need to comment approving and deny.
We don't need the quick to do's get rid of that we don't need to delete to do's.
So that ends at c that ends right here.
We also don't need the actually know what we do need that because we're going to have the post motile
on this page so we'll keep that.
OK so that should be all we need for the javascript.
Now the chart.
J.S. we don't need that I can get rid of that we don't need the canvas J.S. script.
And we'll keep the rest.
OK so we're going to keep the preload.
I don't know why I'm starting from the bottom but that's what I'm doing.
So it's fine.
The user mode so we don't need what we do want to keep is the post motile.
So we can get rid of the user in the category but let's keep the post modal which is this one here.
All right.
And then the fixed action button we're going to be changing that up.
But we'll keep that for now the footer we're keeping.
And then all the sections we're going to get rid of.
So this is the the to do's and all that get rid of that.
Get rid of this one here which is the section.
Visitors will get rid of the top on the stats.
So up to this point and we'll delete k we obviously want to keep the nav bar and that should do it.
So it's safe.
And then we should be able to click on the post link and it loads the post page which basically just
has a folder on it and the floating button.
So let's change the active link in the nav bar.
Right now it's on the dashboard.
See right here we're going to take that.
We're going to put that on to the posts and save and that way the Post is now highlighted.
Now for the content let's go under the nav bar between the now and the footer.
And we're going to put a section here will say Section posts.
So it's do a section each team I'll tag with the class of section and we'll give it a class section
posts.
Let's make it gray gray background and we'll lighten it let's say light dash for we make it really light.
And then in here we'll have a container.
So this stuff is all the same we'll do a row let's do a full column full 12 columns so I'll say Dot
call DOT s 12 and then and here we're going to do a card let's do our card content
it inside here will have a title so the title will be a span with the class of card title and we'll
just say posts
and then we're going to put a table.
So what I'll do is copy from the index aged him how the table we have which is right here.
So this table I'm going to grab it and we're going to put it in here and let's save
all the details page that's what we need.
Let's create that
details start H.T. OK.
So there's our table now I also want to put the date created in here so let's do that.
So in our table in our t h area let's go right below the category and let's say a date created.
OK and then for each one of these We're going to need a new t d.
Let's say January 1st 2018.
And I'm just going to copy that and put that in here.
But let's let's change this to January 2nd.
All right.
We'll go round here and paste that in.
I'll change that to January 3rd.
We should probably put a few more posts as well.
So let's copy this actual copy all three of these will make six posts.
So all of the t was inside the T body.
Copy those and just paste them in again and we'll change this to pose for and this one will be.
Post 5 and post 6.
Ok I will just change the date Opsahl say five six and seven and I'll change one of these categories
we'll say.
Tech gadgets still look more realistic So let's save that.
And there we go.
So there's our post page.
Now I want to put some pagination down here.
Obviously it's not real pagination but just just for the UI.
So we're going to go down let's go down under this div which is the card content we want to go under
the card content and we want to put in a card action.
OK.
So it's kind of like a flutter of the card.
And this is where we're going to put our pagination so will say UL dot pagination.
Hopefully you guys using it.
And then this one is going to be this is going to have a class of disabled because this is going to
be basically the current page you're on.
And then inside there we're going to have a tag with the class of let's do blue text and it's not actually
going to go anywhere inside the tag we're going to have a chevron left icon.
So we'll say I doubt I thought material dash icons in here will do Chevron underscore laughed.
OK.
So if I were to save that I see now we have the little arrow icon which is disabled on the next list
item in our pagination is going to be the active one.
So let's say Ally Dortch will say active class.
It's also going to have a class of blue because it's going to have a background.
And let's also do Litan will do Leitung dash 2.
All right in here will have an 8 tag with the class of white dash text and none of these are going to
actually go anywhere.
But this is going to also.
This is going to have a one because it's basically the first page.
So if we take a look at that case we have the one and that's the active page.
And then what I'll do is just copy this or copy that down and we'll just remove the active from it so
word or move the active floor move.
Actually all of these blue and Litan But let's give it a Wavves effect class.
OK we'll change this to two and then we can copy this.
So we'll do like two three four and five.
So change these numbers up so this will be three four and five and see what that looks like.
All right so that the text is white we can't see it.
So we have to change these.
I'm going to do control d to select the next one next one and the next one and then change them all
to blue text
and then we go.
So now we just need our right Chevron.
So what I'll do is copy once.
Let's copy this ally right here and put that out here and change this to Chevron right
and I'm just going to take away the disabled class and I'm going to put on a Wavves effect.
I'll save that.
And there we go so there's our pagination when we click on it you see the little waves effect.
OK.
So that's it for the post.
Now the category's is basically going to be the same thing just different content so I'm going to copy
everything.
Go to our categories and paste it in.
Now here we actually don't need the S.K. editor.
We can get rid of that.
Oh we've got to do the motile on the post page.
So real quick let's go down.
We already have the actual modal right here.
We just want to edit the button instead of having all of these things pop up.
I just want to click the plus and that will open the modal.
So are you just going to get rid of the whole ul.
You know we'll get rid of all that and then we're going to go to the actual link right here and put
an H ref to the post.
Motile and remember we have to add a modal trigger as a class.
OK so if I save that now if I click the plus icon it opens up the molto.
OK so now we're done with that we can close that up.
Actually let's copy everything again because we want that same type of modal button.
So will copy from posts.
Paste in categories again get rid of the S.K. editor.
We also don't need to select
Let's see we can get rid of the script to the S.K. editor and
we actually want the category modals so I'm going to copy from the index page the category motile which
is right here and we'll go and will replace the post motile on the categories page.
So paste that in.
All right and then the action button we're just going to change this to go to category modal right now
for the table.
Let's go up to the top of the table.
Actually first let's change the active class C and go right here.
So class active we want to take it off of post and put it on two categories and then we'll go back down
to the table and further categories it's basically just going to have a title and create date so we
can get rid of this category.
And what I'll do is just get rid of this TDD and now we can have that as the category name.
Same thing here.
Get rid of that.
Get rid of that for this one will say we got web development graphic design.
Let's do tech gadgets.
And then this last one is going to be other
other.
And then we can get rid of the rest of the teacher's
all right and we'll leave the pagination.
So let's save it.
Let's go to categories.
One thing I forgot was the title.
So where is it right here.
So we want to change this from posts to categories.
All right.
And if we click the button here that should open the category motile.
So we're going to go ahead and saw here guys in the next video we're going to do the comments in the
user's page.