All right so in the last video we did the post in categories in their pages.
Now we're going to do the comments in users which are going to be very similar to posting categories
so I'm going to copy everything that's on the post page.
I actually think a better idea would be to copy everything in the categories page.
And one thing I forgot is in the categories age Tamal I just want to change this to categories as well
as this class name should be section categories.
So we'll save that and then we'll just copy everything here and then let's go to our comments each time
and paste that in.
All right.
We're going to go to the top and change the active class from categories change that to comments
OK.
That will go down.
Change just to comments
and section comments in the title
and as far as the content here we're going to have the image of the person that that created the comment.
So we're actually not going to have we're not going to have a T head area so we can we're going to get
rid of that.
We're just going to have the T body in then what I'll do is leave just one table row and get rid of
the rest.
So down to here.
So now we just have one table we're all in this first T.D..
His first column is going to be the user image but I'm going to set a width here of 70.
OK.
I wanted to be a certain size and then we'll put in an image tag and we're going to give it a class
of responsive dash.
I m g as well as a class of circle.
OK.
Now this source is going to be I m g slash.
Person one dot j peg.
OK reusing the same images.
And let's see I think that's actually we're going to add some inline style as well because I want it
to be pushed over a little bit in the size I want to set the width to 40 pixels.
So with 40 pixels and then margin left will add some margin to the left lets say 10 pixels
OK and then the next t d is going to be the comment.
So I'm just going to do like 10 words will say larm 10 tab
and let's see the next he is going to be a check a check icon and a close are an X icon wrapped in the
link so the link for this one let's give it a class of green text.
It's not going to actually do anything if you want to add the TOSed functionality like we did on the
dashboard you can do that if you want in here will have an icon
that should be a dash
and then this is going to be done.
And then what we will do is copy this.
And then this next one is going to have a class of red text and the icon will be close.
OK.
So it's copy let's save that.
And then let's go to comments and there we go.
So there we have one roll let's copy this.
TR The whole thing is.
Copy that and we'll paste in three more and then we'll change up the images.
So we have person 1 person 2 3 and 4 and save.
And there we go.
So there's our comments page.
All right so now we're going to move to the users.
Actually that's just finished.
Let's let's see if we have anything else.
We just want to get rid of the fixed action in the motile because there's no actual add comment functionality
so I'll save that.
All right so now let's copy categories again.
The whole thing.
And then let's go to users
and paste that in and go up to the top will change the active class from categories to users.
OK.
And then let's see down here we'll change this to users.
I know this can get tedious guys
change that's when it's the same way out and just different content.
It gets very tedious.
So let's see what do we want for users.
We're going to want the name.
Well we're going to want the image first of all so for the first th I'm going to leave it blank.
And then the next one will be the name and then the next one will be the e-mail.
And then let's do a register day
just say registered and the last one we're going to leave blank.
OK.
So then down here let's leave one table wrong get rid of the rest
and for the image what I'm going to do is copy from the comments table row that has the image because
it's going to be the same thing so I'm going to grab one of these TVs well grab person one actually
and then put that here for the first CD.
Actually I'll just get rid of all those so pace set in for the first TV.
Right.
And then the next one is going to be the name
Next on e-mail.
Then we have the registered day
and then we have the details link
between blue Lou Litan dash 2.
That's going to actually go to details dot H.
Hello.
All right so now what we'll do is copy the table row and let's do four users so two three four and then
we'll just change up the content.
So the second one is going to be person to
and for the name will say Larry waters.
Let's see e-mail b l quaters registration will see January 3rd.
All right.
Next one actually is going to be person three person three and then this will be let's say Susan Williams
Susan registered date.
And then this last one will be person for and this will be Jeff Burke say Jay Burke and January 10th.
All right now we're going to need a motel for this.
The user modals So let's let's change this rate here to use or modal and then change.
Actually we'll just get rid of this category motile and will copy the user one from the index
so I'll paste that there and then that should be good.
So let's save it.
Let's go to our users page and we forgot the text in the details button.
And this one.
All right.
So there we go there's our users of the image the name email registered date.
So that's good.
We click this button and we get the ad user.
All right.
So in the next video we're going to get to the logon page and possibly the details page you'll see if
we can get them both done in the same video if not we'll just split them up and then we should be done.
All right.
So I will see you in the next.