All right guys so now we just have to do the log in page and the details page so we're going to start
with the log in.
Now blogging is going to be quite different because we're just going to basically have a little box
in the middle with the log in form.
We're not going to have all of the we are going to have now but we're not going to have all these lengths
it's basically just going to be the blue bar with the logo.
So what I'll do is copy the post page and then go to our log in and paste it in and we can actually
get rid of the Get rid of this select the all the side now because we're not going to need that.
And then we'll leave the pre-load our stuff we can get rid of the S.K. editor script we can get rid
of the modal we can get rid of the fixed action button we'll leave the footer and let's get rid of all
the sections so up to the Nav..
All right.
Now the Nav. is going to be very simple actually we can do it we can just recreate the now because it's
going to be so simple so just get rid of the whole Nav. and let's remake it so we'll just say Nav. with
the class of blue and dark and two container and now wrapper
and a tag with the class of brand dash logo and you'll have a go to index each table.
And then here we'll put madmen and that's it.
That's our now varlets save it.
Now we go east we click log out.
It should take us to the log in page.
Good.
So from here under the nav we're going to put the log in.
All right.
Now I'm going to wrap it in a container
and let's do a row.
Actually you know what.
Let's let's let's wrap this in a section.
I wasn't initially going to but I think it's a good idea to do it so we'll say S.S. and then Section
loggin and then we'll just take this and we'll go ahead and move that up.
OK.
So inside the row we're going to have a couple of classes.
So we're going to do call s 12.
So it's stacked on mobile devices 8.
So eight columns on medium but also an offset on medium screens.
We want to offset it to one large screens.
We wanted to take up six columns and we want to offset it
3 so offset dash L3.
Okay and that's going to change the width of the box depending on the size of the browser.
So if we were to save that we're not going to see anything yet.
But inside here let's put a card panel.
I'm also going to give it a class of log in and I'm going to give it a class of blue Darkon to white
text and center.
So there it is.
So depending on the with ex-CEO it gets bigger and smaller and bigger and you can mess around with it
if you want.
That's just what I what I feel looks the best.
So inside here we're going to put in h one and we're going to say madman.
Log in.
Actually it's doing H-2 that's kind of big.
All right.
So underneath that we'll have our form and we're actually going to have the end the action go to index
start aged so that when you click when you submit it goes to the index page.
All right then we're going to have our input field.
So this is going to be the e-mail but I'm going to prefix it with an icon Silex to material icons female
and we need to give this a class of prefix since it's prefixing an input and k we'll say intuits let's
do type email and let's give in and I d e mail.
OK then we'll do our label for e-mail.
And then the text and save and then we go now the label I want to give that a class of white text.
So it's not so dark
where you go.
All right.
Now we also want the password fields so we're going to copy this whole input field div and paste that
in and we'll change this to the icon to lock.
Change all this stuff to password.
OK.
And then underneath this input field we're going to have our submit so we'll say we'll give it a type
of submit
and value we'll say log in let's do a couple of classes so we want to beat and beat and large Let's
do BATNA extended which is something that it's a custom class I'm going to create in let's do Gray.
OK.
Oh we want to also want to lighten it.
So we'll do Litan for and let's make sure it's black text.
Ok so we'll save that.
And I mean that looks OK but I want the button to actually stretch all the way across.
So what we'll do is go to our CSSA or main dot CSSA file and let's say Vitti and dash extended display
it as a block.
Let's give it a width of 80 percent margin.
Auto.
And let's move it from the top a little bit.
So margin top 20 pixels.
All right and I also want to move the whole log in box down a little.
So remember we gave it a class of log in let's say margin top 70 pixels and save outs to the sum to
the bottom two.
So margin bottom 70 pixels.
And there we go.
So there's our log in page.
So if I put something in here
and log in takes us to the dashboard.
Awesome.
So last thing we have to do is the details page so let's close up those.
Let's copy the post page again and then go to details and paste that in.
And basically the details page is like the post edit page it's where we're going to see the values for
the posts and all that.
So we're going to keep for instance the S.K. added or the Select it's going to have it's going to have
all the fields the motile has.
But in the page.
So let's
let's actually go to the top and let's get rid of the active class on the post.
We don't want an active class anywhere because this isn't actually in the Nav..
OK.
And then we're going to go down here to the section C section
details
and then get rid of the table.
OK.
In the card action.
I want to keep it I want to get rid of the pagination so delete the UL
all right and we can get rid of the fixed action button
and what I actually want to do is in the card content where we have the title I want to put a row where
I want this to be a grid.
If we're going to say dog call will stack these on small screens but I want it to be six columns on
medium and up.
So we want to add these.
And then we'll put the title in one
and then this one is actually going to have the who created it.
It's going to have their image so I'm going to copy that from the comments page right here.
But not just the image.
And we'll put that right here.
And then let's go under it and put a paragraph and we'll say.
Posted by John Doe.
And then another paragraph and we'll say on January 12th 2018 and then I'm going to give this column
a class of center as well so let's save that and then let's click on one of these details links and
then we go.
OK so underneath the row that we just created which ends right here is going to be basically the form
that we have in the motile.
So I'm going to go down to the post motile and copy the whole form.
Copy the form and then I'm going to get rid of the modal altogether.
K now the form will go right here under the road that we just created.
And we're going to change or not change we're going to add value to the input here for the title
of toast one just to make it look more realistic.
And then let's see we'll go to the textarea and in here let's just say this is the content for post
want will save it.
All right so that looks good.
Now will do is create a save and delete button.
OK if they want to save it or delete it.
Actually for the select option let's put selected on one of these categories like that
and you see how the body is like right up against the OR that's the label I'm going to get rid of the
body label because that doesn't look right.
It's pretty obvious it's the body there.
And then let's see in the card action this is where we're going to put the button.
So let's say Vautin class beats and let's give it a class of green and we'll say save and then I'll
copy that down.
And then this one will be delete and we'll change it to read and there we go.
So those are details page.
All right pretty simple and I think that that's it.
All right so I think it's a pretty nice UI.
We even have some functionality but obviously if you wanted to move on and learn a back end language
or perhaps no J asked which is a runtime which is also a server side technology you could actually build
this into a working application.
Obviously this is not that course this is a materialized UI course but knowing how to build the front
end is obviously a valuable skill.
All right so that's it guys for this project and I will see you in the next one.